<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="195" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="193" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[H. J. R. No. 23.] Joint Resolution creating an auditing board to pass on cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain claims against the State and to authorize the Governor to direct payment thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, many claims exist against the State, now unpaid, which accrued during the past administration, for services under the quarantine laws of the State, which claims the Governor declines to order paid, because he is not familiar with the facts and circumstances under which they were created; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, on account of the time which will be required in the investigation and auditing of said claims, the joint committee of the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives heretofore appointed to audit said claims, find it practically impossible to perform such service in connection with their regular duties and complete the same during the present session of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Section 1. Therefore, be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the State Health Officer, the Comptroller of Public Accounts and the At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney General be and they are hereby constituted an auditing board, and they are hereby empowered and directed to inquire into all such claims as may be presented against the state for services rendered under the quarantine laws, under the prior administration, and to approve all such as may be justly payable by the State; and further, that upon the approval of any such claim by the board hereby constituted, the Governor be and he is hereby authorized to direct payment thereof out of the deficiency appropriation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The large number of the claims provided for in the foregoing section which have not been paid and which should be audited and paid without delay, creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and an emergency exists that the resolution shall take effect and be in force and be in effect from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing Joint Resolution originated in the House and passed the same by a vote of 74 yeas and 3 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 24 yeas and no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 30, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. J. R. No. 12.] Joint Resolution confirming the location of the boundary line established by the United States Commissioner between No Man&#8217;s Land and Texas, and Texas and New Mexico, under an act of Congress of June 5, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Whereas an act of Congress approved June 5, 1858, provided: for Commissioners to locate and mark the boundary lines between the territories of the United States and the State of Texas; and'</p>
<p>Whereas in accordance with said act, a survey was made of the bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary line between the Public Strip&#8212;otherwise known as No Man&#8217;s Land&#8212;<pb n="196" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="194" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>and between Texas and New Mexico by John H. Clark, U. S. Commissioner ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed under said act, A. D. 1858; And</p>
<p>Whereas, it appears from the report of the said Commissioner to the General Land Office at Washington, that said surveying was carefully done, consuming over two years on the ground in making the same; and</p>
<p>Whereas, said boundary line so located has been acquiesced in by the State of Texas and the United States Government by surveying up to it and selling the lands so surveyed, or parts of it; and</p>
<p>Whereas, until recently no part of said boundary lines have ever been officially agreed upon or accepted by the General government or the State of Texas, as contemplated by the act of Congress, authorizing the survey; and Whereas, on the 4th day of March A. D. 1891, the Congress of the United States confirmed the boundary lines as surveyed by said Commissioner, John H. Clark, between No Man&#8217;s Land and Texas, and between Texas and New Mexico established under the act of Congress of June 5, 1858;</p>
<p>Therefore, be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Texas: That the boundary line between the Public Land Strip&#8212;otherwise known as No Man&#8217;s Land&#8212;and Texas, and between Texas and New Mexico, estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished by John H. Clark, Commissioner under the act of the United States Congress, approved June 5, 1858, be and the same is hereby accepted, ratified and confirmed on the part of the State of Texas, as the true boundary line be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween said Public Land Strip and Texas, and between Texas and New Mexico.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. And, whereas, the near approach of the close of, the present session of the Legislature renders it unlikely that this resolution can he passed in the regular way, and the fact that there is much uncertainty as to the location of said bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary line, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity which requires that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and the same is so suspended, and this resolution take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution originated in the Senate and passed the same&#8212;vote not given; and passed the House by a vote of 71 yeas and no nays.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the twenty-fifth day of March, 1891, but was not signed by him, nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out his signature.&#8212;Geo. W, Smith, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. J. R. No. 19.] Joint Resolution amending Section 4, Article 6, of the Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved, by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion four of article six of the Constitution of the State of Texas be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 4. In all elections by the people the vote shall be by ballot, and the Legislature shall provide for the numbering of tickets and make<pb n="197" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="195" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>such other regulations as may be necessary to detect and punish fraud and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serve the purity of the ballot box; and the Legislature may provide by law for the registration of all voters in all cities containing a population of ten thous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />and inhabitants or more.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor of this State shall issue his proclamation ordering an election to be held on the second Tuesday in August, A. D. 1891, on this amendment, in accordance with article 17, section 1, of the Constitution; and those voting for the adoption of this amendment shall have written or printed on their ballots the words &#8220;For the amendment to section four, article six, of the Constitution, relating to voting;&#8221; and those voting against the adoption of said! amendment shall have written or printed on their ballots the words &#8220;Against the amendment to section four, article six, of the Constitution, relating to voting.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 15, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION NO. 19.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend section 5, article 7, of the Constitution, of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion 5, article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>The principal of all bonds and other funds and the principal arising from the sale of the lands hereinbefore set apart to said school fund shall be the perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent school fund, and all the interest derivable therefrom and the taxes herein authorized and levied shall be the available school fund, to which the Legislature may add not exceeding one per cent annually of the total value of the permanent school fund; such value to be ascertained by the Board of Education until other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise provided by law; and the available school fund shall be applied annually to the support of the public free schools. And no law shall ever be enacted ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriating any part of the permanent or available school fund to any other pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose whatever; nor shall the same or any part thereof ever be appropriated to or used for the support of any sectarian school; and the available school fund herein provided shall be distributed to the several counties according to their scho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lastic population and applied in such manner as may be provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The foregoing constitutional amendment shall be Submitted to a vote of the qualified electors for members of the Legislature of the State of Texas, on the second Tuesday in August, 1891, at which election all voters favoring said proposed amendment shall write or have printed on their ballots the words &#8220;Tor the amendment to section 5, article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas;&#8221; and all the voters opposed to said amendment shall write or have printed on their ballots the words &#8220;Against the amendment to section 5, article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 28, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="198" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="196" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[H. J. R. No. 1.]&#8212;Joint Resolution to amend Section 11, Article 16, of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section 11, article 16, of the Constitution of the State of Texas shall be amended so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 11. All contracts for a greater rate of interest than ten per centum per annum shall be deemed usurious, and the first Legislature after this amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment is adopted shall provide appropriate pains and penalties to prevent the same; but when no rate of interest is agreed upon, the rate shall not exceed six per centum per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Governor of this State shall issue his proclamation ordering an election on the second Tuesday in August, 1891, at which election the foregoing amendment shall be submitted for adoption by the qualified electors of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Those voting for the adoption of Section 1 [11] shall have written or printed on their ballots the words &#8220;For the amendment to section 11, article 16, of the State Constitution, to reduce rate of interest;&#8221; and those voting against said amendment shall have written or printed on their ballots &#8220;Against the amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to section 11, article 16, of the State Constitution, to reduce rate of interest.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 1, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[H. J. R. No. 12.] Joint Resolution to amend Section 20, Article 16, of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion 20, article 16, of the Constitution of the State of Texas be amended so that it shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 20. The Legislature shall at its first session enact a law whereby the qualified voters of any county, justice&#8217;s precinct, town, city (or such subdivision of a county as may be designated by the commissioners court of said county), may by a majority vote determine from time to time whether the sale of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toxicating liquors shall be prohibited within the prescribed limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The foregoing amendment shall be submitted to the qualified voters of the State on the second Tuesday in August, A. D, 1891. Those favoring its adoption shall have written or printed on their ballots the words &#8220;For local con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol;&#8221; those opposed to its adoption shall have written or printed On their ballots the words &#8220;Against local control.&#8221;</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing Joint Resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the twenty-first day of March, A. D. 1891, but was not signed by him nor returned to the House in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;Geo. W. Smith, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<pb n="199" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="197" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[Senate J. E. No. 16.] Joint Resolution to amend Section 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 11, 12, 16, 25, and 28, Article 5, of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That sections 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 11, 12, 10, 25, and 28 of article 5, of the Constitution of the State of Texas be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 5.&#8212;Judicial Department.</head>
<p>Section 1. The judicial power of this State shall be vested in one Supreme Court, in Courts of Civil Appeals, in a Court of Criminal Appeals, in District Courts, in County Courts, in Commissioners Courts, in Courts of Justices of the Peace, and in such other courts as may be provided by law. The Criminal District Court of Galveston and Harris Counties shall continue with the district jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and organization now existing by law until otherwise provided by law. The Legislature may establish such other courts as it may deem necessary, and prescribe the jurisdiction and organization thereof, and may conform the juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction of the district and other inferior courts thereto.</p>
<p>Section 2. The Supreme Court shall consist of a chief justice and two associate justices, any two of whom shall constitute a quorum, and the concurrence of two judges shall be necessary to the decision of a case. No person shall be eligible to the office of chief justice or associate justice of the Supreme Court unless he be, at the time of his election, a citizen of the United States and of this State, and unless he shall have attained the age of thirty years, and shall have been a practicing lawyer or a judge of a court or such lawyer and judge together at least seven years. Said chief justice and associate justices shall be elected by the qualified voters of the State at a general election, shall hold their offices six years, or until their successors are elected and qualified, and shall each receive an annual salary of four thousand dollars until otherwise provided by law. In case of a vacancy in the office of Chief Justice of the Supreme Court the Governor shall fill the vacancy until the next general election for State officers, and at such general election the vacancy for the unexpired term shall be filled by election by the qualified voters of the State. The judges of the Supreme Court who may be in office at the time this amendment takes effect shall continue in office until the expiration of their term of office under the present Constitution and until their successors are elected and qualified.</p>
<p>Section 3. The Supreme Court shall have appellate jurisdiction only except as herein specified, which shall be coextensive with the limits of the State. Its appellate jurisdiction shall extend to questions of law arising in cases of which the Courts of Civil Appeals have appellate jurisdiction, under such re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strictions and regulations as the Legislature may prescribe. Until otherwise provided by law the appellate jurisdiction of the Supreme Court shall extend to questions of law arising in the cases in the Courts of Civil Appeals in which the judges of any Court of Civil Appeals may disagree, or where the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Courts of Civil Appeals may hold differently on the same question of law, or where a statute of the State is held void. The Supreme Court and the justices thereof shall have power to issue writs of habeas corpus as may be prescribed by law, and under such regulations as may be prescribed by law the said courts and the justices thereof may issue the writs of mandamus, procedendo, certiorari and such other writs as may be necessary to enforce its jurisdiction. The Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="200" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="198" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>lature may confer original jurisdiction on the Supreme Court to issue writs of quo warranto and mandamus in such cases as may be specified, except as against the Governor of the State. The Supreme Court shall also have power, upon affi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />davit or otherwise as by the court may be determined, to ascertain such matters of fact as may be necessary to the proper exercise of its jurisdiction. The Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court shall sit for the transaction of business from the first Monday in October of each year until the last Saturday of June in the next year, inclusive, at the capital of the State. The Supreme Court shall appoint a clerk, who shall give bond in such manner as is now or may bereafter be required by law, and he may hold his office for four years, and shall be subject to removal by said court for good cause entered of record on the minutes of said court, who shall receive such compensation as the Legislature may provide.</p>
<p>Section 4. The Court of Criminal Appeals shall consist of three judges, any two of whom shall constitute a quorum, and the concurrence of two judges shall be necessary to a decision of said court; said judges shall have the same qualifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cations and receive the same salaries as the judges of the Supreme Court. They shall be elected by the qualified voters of the State at a general election, and shall hold their offices for a term of six years. In case of a vacancy in the office of a judge of the Court of Criminal Appeals the Governor shall fill such vacancy by appointment for the unexpired term. The judges of the Court of Appeals who may be in office at the time when this amendment takes effect shall continue in office until the expiration of their term of office under the present Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and laws as judges of the Court of Criminal Appeals.</p>
<p>Section 5. The Court of Criminal Appeals shall have appellate jurisdiction coextensive with the limits of the State an all criminal cases of whatever grade, with such exceptions and under such regulations as may be prescribed by law. The Court of Criminal Appeals and the judges thereof shall have the power to issue the writ of habeas corpus, and under such regulations as may be prescribed by law issue such writs as may be necessary to enforce its own jurisdiction. The Court of Criminal Appeals shall have power, upon affidavit or otherwise, to as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />certain such matters of fact as may be necessary to the exercise of its jurisdiction. The Court of Criminal Appeals shall sit for the transaction of business from the first Monday in October to the last Saturday of June in each year, at the State Capital and two other places (or the capital city) if the Legislature shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after so provide. The Court of Criminal Appeals shall appoint a clerk for each place at which it may sit, and each clerk shall give bond in such manner as is now or may hereafter be required by law, and who shall hold his office for four years unless sooner removed by the court for good cause, entered of record on the min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes of said court.</p>
<p>Section 6. The Legislature shall, as soon as practicable after the adoption of this amendment, divide the State into not less than two nor more than three supreme judicial districts, and thereafter into such additional districts as the increase of population and business may require, and shall establish a Court of Civil Appeals in each of said districts, which shall consist of a chief justice and two associate justices, who shall have the qualifications as herein prescribed for justices of the Supreme Court. Said Court of Civil Appeals shall have appellate jurisdiction coextensive with the limits of their respective districts, which shall extend to all civil cases of which the District Courts or County Courts have original or appellate jurisdiction, under such restrictions and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="201" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="199" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>lations as may be prescribed by law: Provided, That the decision of said courts shall be conclusive on all questions of fact brought before them on appeal or error. Bach of said Courts of Civil Appeals shall hold its sessions at a place in its dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict to be designated by the Legislature, and at such time as may be prescribed by law. Said justices shall be elected by the qualified voters of their respective districts, at a general election, for a term of six years, and shall receive for their services the sum of three thousand five hundred dollars per annum until other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise provided by law. Said courts shall have such other jurisdiction, original and appellate, as may be prescribed by law. Each Court of Civil Appeals shall ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point a clerk in the same manner as the clerk of the Supreme Court, which clerk shall receive such compensation as may be fixed by law. Until the organization of the Courts of Civil Appeals and Criminal Appeals, as herein provided for, the jurisdiction, power, and organization and location of the Supreme Court, the Court of Appeals, and the Commission of Appeals shall continue as they were be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the adoption of this amendment. All civil cases which may be pending in the Court of Appeals shall, as soon as practicable after the organization of the Courts of Civil Appeals, be certified to and the records thereof transmitted to the proper Courts of Civil Appeals, to be decided by said courts. At the first session of the Supreme Court, the Court of Criminal Appeals, and such of the Courts of Civil Appeals which may be hereafter created under this article after the first election of the judges of such courts under this amendment, the terms of office of the judges of each court shall be divided into three classes, and the justices thereof shall draw for the different classes. Those who shall draw class No. 1 shall hold their offices two years, those drawing class No. 2 shall bold their offices for four years, and those who may draw class No. 3 shall hold their offices for six years from the date of their election and until their successors are elected and qualified; and thereafter each of the said judges shall hold his office for six years, as provided in this Constitution.</p>
<p>Section 7. The State shall be divided, into as many judicial districts as may now or hereafter be provided by law, which may be increased or diminished by law. For each district there shall be elected by the qualified voters thereof, at a general election, a judge, who shall be a citizen of the United States and of this State, who shall have been a practicing lawyer of this State or a judge of a court in this State for four years next preceding his election, who shall have resided in the district in which he was elected for two years next preceding his election, who shall reside in his district during his term of office, who shall hold his office for the period of four years, and shall receive for his services an annual salary of two thousand five hundred dollars, until otherwise changed by law. He shall hold the regular terms of his court at the county seat of each county in his dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict at least twice in each year in such manner as may be prescribed by law The Legislature shall have power by general or special laws to authorize the hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of special terms of the court, or the holding of more than two terms in any county for the dispatch of business. The Legislature shall also provide for the holding of district court when the judge thereof is absent, or is from any cause disabled or disqualified from presiding. The district judges who may be in office when this amendment takes effect shall hold their offices until their respective terms shall expire under their present election or appointment.</p>
<p>Section 8. The District Court shall have original jurisdiction in all criminal cases of the grade of felony; in all suits in behalf of the State<pb n="202" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="200" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>to recover penalties, forfeitures, and escheats; of all cases of divorce; of all mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanors involving official misconduct; of all suits to recover damages for slander or defamation of character; of all suits for trial of title to land and for the enforcement of liens thereon; of all suits for the trial of the right of property levied upon by virtue of any writ of execution, sequestration, or attachment when the property levied on shall be equal to or exceed in value five hundred dollars; of all suits, complaints, or pleas whatever, without regard to any dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinction between law and equity, when the matter in controversy shall be valued at or amount to five hundred dollars exclusive of interest; of contested elections; and said court and the judges thereof shall have power to issue writs of habeas corpus, mandamus, injunction, and certiorari, and all writs necessary to enforce their jurisdiction. The District Court shall have appellate jurisdiction and general control in probate matters over the County Court established in each county, for appointing guardians, granting letters testamentary and of administration, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bating wills, for settling the accounts of executors, administrators, and guardians, and for the transaction of all business, appertaining to estates; and original jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and general control over the executors, administrators, guardians, and minors, under such regulations as may be prescribed by law. The District Court shall have appellate jurisdiction and general supervisory control over the County Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners Court, with, such exceptions and under such regulations as may be prescribed by law; and shall have general original jurisdiction over all causes of action whatever for which a remedy or jurisdiction is not provided by law or this Constitution, and such other jurisdiction, original and appellate, as may be provided by law.</p>
<p>Section 11. No judge shall sit in any case wherein he may be interested, or when either of the parties may be connected with him either by affinity or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sanguinity within such a degree as may be prescribed by law, or when he shall have been counsel in the case. When the Supreme Court, the Court of Criminal Appeals, the Court of Civil Appeals or any member of either, shall be thus dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />qualified to hear and determine any case or cases in said court, the same shall be certified to the Governor of the State, who shall immediately commission the requisite number of persons learned in the law for the trial and determination of such cause or causes. When a judge of the district court is disqualified by any of the causes above stated, the parties may by consent appoint a proper person to try said case; or, upon their failing to do so, a competent person may be appointed to try the same in the county where it is pending, in such manner as may be prescribed by law. And the district judges may exchange districts or hold court for each other when they may deem it expedient, and shall do so when required by law. This disqualification of judges of inferior tribunals shall be remedied and vacancies in their offices filled as may be prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Section 12. All judges of courts of this State by virtue of their office, [shall] be conservators of the peace throughout the State. The style of all writs and process shall be &#8220;The State of Texas.&#8221; All prosecutions shall be carried on in the name and by authority of the State of Texas, and shall conclude &#8220;Against the peace and dignity of the State.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 16. The County Court shall have original jurisdiction of all misdemeanors of which exclusive original jurisdiction is not given to the Justice&#8217;s Court as the same is now or may hereafter be prescribed by law, and when the fine to be imposed shall exceed $200; and they shall have exclusive jurisdiction in all civil cases when the matter in contro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="203" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="201" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>versy shall exceed in value $200 and not exceed $500, exclusive of interest; and concurrent jurisdiction with the District Court when the matter in controversy shall exceed $500 and not exceed $1000, exclusive of interest, but shall not have jurisdiction of suits for the recovery of land. They shall have appellate juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction in cases civil and criminal of which Justice&#8217;s Courts have original juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction, but of such civil cases only when the judgment of the court appealed from shall exceed $20, exclusive of cost, under such regulations as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by law. In all appeals from Justice&#8217;s Court there shall be a trial de novo in the County Court, and appeals may be prosecuted from the final judgment rendered in such cases by the County Court, as well as all cases civil and criminal of which the County Court has exclusive or concurrent or original jurisdiction of civil appeals, in civil cases to the Court of Civil Appeals, and in such criminal cases to the Court of Criminal Appeals, with such exceptions and under such regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations as may be prescribed by law. The County Court shall have the general jurisdiction of a Probate Court; they shall probate wills, appoint guardians of minors, idiots, lunatics, persons non compos mentis, and common drunkards; grant letters testamentary and of administration; settle accounts of executors; transact all business appertaining to deceased persons, minors, idiots, lunatics, persons non compos mentis, and common drunkards, including the settlement, partition, and distribution of estates of deceased persons; and to apprentice minors as provided by law; and the County Court or judge thereof shall have power to issue writs of injunction, mandamus and all writs necessary to the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forcement of the jurisdiction of said court, and to issue writs of habeas corpus in cases where the offense charged is within the jurisdiction of the County Court or any other court or tribunal inferior to said court. The County Court shall not have criminal jurisdiction in any county where there is a Criminal District Court, unless expressly conferred by law; and in such counties appeals from Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice&#8217;s Courts and other inferior courts and tribunals in criminal cases shall be to the Criminal District Court, under such regulations as may be prescribed by law, and in all such cases an appeal shall lie from such District Court to the Court of Criminal Appeals. When the judge of the County Court is disqualified in any case pending in the County Court the parties interested may by consent appoint a proper person to try said case, or upon their failing to do so, a competent person may be appointed to try the same in the county where it is pending, in such manner as may be prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Section 25. The Supreme Court shall have power to make and establish rules of procedure, not inconsistent with the laws of the State, for the government of said court and the other courts of this State, to expedite the dispatch of business therein.</p>
<p>Section 28. Vacancies in the office of judges of the Supreme Court, the Court of Criminal Appeals, the Court of Civil Appeals and District Courts, shall be filled by the Governor until the next succeeding general election, and vacancies in the office of county judge and justices of the peace shall be filled by the Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers Court until the next general election for such offices.</p>
<p>Section 29. The foregoing constitutional amendment shall be submit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted to a vote of the qualified electors of the State at an election to be held throughout the State on the second Tuesday in. August, A. D. 1891, at which election all voters favoring said proposed amendment shall write or have printed on their ballots the words &#8220;For the amendment to article<pb n="204" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="202" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>5 of the Constitution, relating to the judiciary,&#8221; and all those opposed shall write or have printed on their ballots the words &#8220;Against the amendment to article 5 of the Constitution, relating to the judiciary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 30. The Governor of the State is hereby directed to issue the necessary proclamation for said election, and have the same published as required by the Constitution and existing laws of the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 28, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring.</p>
<p>Section 1. That the Governor be and he is hereby requested to communicate with the superintendent of the United States census for the year 1890, and secure at the earliest moment the statistics of the population of Texas by counties, for the use of this Legislature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 11, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concurrent Resolution authorizing the appointment of a committee to investigate the case of Jay Gould versus the International and Great Northern Railroad Company, in the District Court of Smith county, and all the proceedings had and done in said cause, and in other, causes in that and other courts of the State, affecting said railroad company and its receivers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Grave charges have been made in the public prints and by current re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports which tend to bring in disrepute the courts of this State, touching the pend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing receivership of the International and Great Northern Railroad Company in the district court of Smith county, and it is due to the officers of said court and to the good name of the State that said reports and charges should be investi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gated, and, if false, exposed, therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curring): That a joint committee of the turn houses to investigate said matters be appointed by the respective presiding officers, to consist of two senators and three representatives, whose duty it shall be to proceed immediately to investi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gate all matters connected with the receivership of the International and Great Northern Railroad Company, in the district court of Smith county, the origin of such receivership, the cause or causes of its duration, the operations and expendi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures by the receivers, and all other suits, matters and things connected therewith or incidental thereto. Said committee may sit during the sessions of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature or in vacation, and is hereby empowered to send for persons and papers, to administer oaths, and to hold their sessions at any convenient point in the State. All parties interested shall have the right to appear before the commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee in person or by attorney, and shall have the right to have witnesses sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moned and examined, and the investigation shall be with open doors. Upon the conclusion of their investigation, the joint committee hereby created shall report the result thereof, together with such conclusions of facts, and recommendations as to necessary legislation they may deem advisable, to their respective houses. If the Legislature be not in session, when such investigation is concluded,<pb n="205" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="203" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>the committee is directed to file said report in the office of the Secretary of State as a public record in said office, on or before the first day of August, 1891, and the same shall be printed and laid before the next session of the Legislature by the Governor. Each member of the committee shall receive for his services five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per day for the time he is engaged in the investigation, and railroad fare paid in going to and returning from the point at which the investigation is held, and the stenographer employed by the committee shall receive for his services not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding ten dollars per day for the time he is engaged in such service; all claims to be approved by the Governor, and warrants drawn by the Comptroller as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said committee shall take down all testimony heard by them, in writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and for this purpose they may employ some competent stenographer, and said testimony as well as all documentary evidence, shall be filed as a part of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port the committee, and be printed for the use of the members of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This resolution shall take effect and be in force from and after its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage by the two houses.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, by concurrent resolution of the Legislature of the State of Kansas of February 11, 1891, an invitation has been extended to the West and Southwest<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ern States and Territories, to participate by means of selected representatives in a commercial congress of the aforesaid States and Territories, to convene at Kansas City on the 15th day of April, 1891, for the purpose of discussing, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mercial and economic questions, involving the welfare of the West and South<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />west; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, The community of interest existing between the several States and Territories of said sections, renders it highly important that such congress should be held, and that Texas should be represented therein; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate of the State of Texas, the House of Representatives concurring: That on behalf of the State of Texas, we accept such invitation, and heartily endorse the objects of such convention.</p>
<p>Be it further resolved, That in accordance with the terms of the concurrent resolution of the Legislature of the State of Kansas, a delegation of eleven, to consist of the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, and four sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ators to be appointed by the President of the Senate, and five Representatives by the Speaker of the House, to represent the State of Texas in said Congress, together with five other delegates to be appointed by the Governor.</p>
<p>Be it resolved further: That the Governor is hereby authorized and requested to select and commission five additional delegates. The actual and necessary ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of the committee herein provided for, shall be paid out of the contin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gent fund of the twenty-second Legislature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, 1891</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="206" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="204" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concurrent Resolution to make more effective a concurrent resolution passed at the present session of the Legislature appointing a committee to investigate the case of Jay Gould versus the International and Great Northern Railway Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany in the District Court of Smith County and all proceedings had and done in said cause and other causes in that and other courts of the State affecting said Railroad Company and its receivers; to authorize said investigating com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee to appoint a sergeant at arms, prescribe his duties and provide for his compensation, to provide for the compensation of witnesses summoned by said committee and testifying before it, and to provide for the payment of other expenses incurred in said investigation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the House of Representatives (the Senate con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curring) that the joint committee appointed to investigate the case of Jay Gould versus the International and Great Northern Railway Company as provided in concurrent resolution passed at a former day of this session, be and they are hereby authorized and empowered to appoint a sergeant-at-arms whose duty it shall be to attend the meetings of said committee, to execute and return all pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess directed to him in summoning witnesses and bringing them before the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee, and to do and perform all such other duties as may be required of him by the committee. Said Sergeant-at-Arms shall receive as compensation for his services, the sum of five dollars per day during the time he may be so employed and shall further receive the amount of railroad fare necessarily expended while traveling in the execution of any process directed to him by the committee. The claim of said sergeant-at-arms for services, after the same shall have been ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved as correct by the chairman of said committee, shall be approved and paid as provided for in section 1 of the original concurrent resolution heretofore passed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All witnesses who may be summoned by the committee, and who shall appear before it and testify, shall receive as compensation the sum of two dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per day for the time they may be present before said committee and shall receive the actual railroad fare necessary in going to and returning from the point at which said investigation is held. The claim or claims of witnesses under this section, after the same shall have been approved as correct by the chairman of said investigation committee, shall be paid in manner and form as provided for in section 1 of the original concurrent resolution heretofore passed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Should, it become necessary in the progress of the investion [investiga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion] provided for, that the committee should go to any other point or points in the state, other than the point at which said investigation is held, then the said committee shall be allowed their actual necessary expenses for such service, in ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition to the compensation already provided for in original concurrent resolution, to be paid in the same manner as provided for in original concurrent resolution.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This resolution shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage by both houses.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>