<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1439" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>SPECIAL SESSION OF THE TWENTY-FIFTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>MAY 22, 1897, AND ADJOURNED JUNE 20, 1897.</byline>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/1439_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<byline>AUSTIN 1897</byline>
<pb n="1440" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="1441" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS. FIRST SPECIAL SESSION TWENTY-FIFTH LEGISLATURE, 1897.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 3.] CHAPTER 1.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for the per diem pay of members, officers and employes of the first called session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature of the State of Texas, convened May 22nd, 1897, by proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of thirty-five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the State treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of the per diem pay of the members, officers and employes of the first called session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature of Texas, convened May 22nd, 1897, by proclamation of the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate, approved by the President thereof, or the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, approved by the Speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants upon the treasury for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, the called session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature, for the payment of the members, officers and employes of which this law is enacted, is now in session, and public policy requires their pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, therefore an imperative public necessity exists that the rule re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 29, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the House by a two-thirds vote, yeas 86, nays none; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 23, nays none.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 18.] CHAPTER 2.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the immediate relief of the citizens of the city of El Paso and El Paso County, who are suffering from the overflow of the Rio Grande, during the past week, and to appropriate five thousand dollars therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Whereas, the unprecedented rise in the waters of the Rio Grande have, within the past week, caused a large portion of the City of El Paso and the surrounding country to be flooded, thereby causing<pb n="1442" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>great destruction of property, especially so in the City of El Paso, ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dering homeless thousands of the citizens of said city;</p>
<p>Whereas, the destitute people are in great need of food and clothing, creating demands upon the city for relief beyond its power to comply with immediately; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of five thousand dollars ($5000), or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the State treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the immediate relief of the said citizens of El Paso city and county, who are suffering from said flood, said money to be expended under the direction and supervision of the County Judge of El Paso County, together with the mayor of the City of El Paso; said money to be paid out on warrants of the Comptroller, which warrants shall be issued on certificates of said Judge and Mayor within sixty days from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The great flood which swept a portion of said city and vicinity within the last few days is hereby declared to be a great public calamity, and an emergency and an imperative public necessity exist re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring that the constitutional rule which requires that bills be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 2, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the House by a two-thirds-vote, yeas 88, nays none; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 24, nays none.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 21.] CHAPTER 3.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the contingent expenses of the first called session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature, convened May 22nd, 1897, by proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the State treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay the contingent expenses of the first called session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature, convened May 22d, 1897, by proclamation of the Governor, and that the approval by the chairman of the Committee on Contingent Expenses of either House, countersigned by the President of the Senate or Speaker of the House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives, as the case may be, shall be sufficient authority to authorize the Comptroller to issue his warrant on the State Treasurer for the payment of any account so drawn against said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the public importance of the objects herein contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated creates an imperative public necessity and emergency, fully au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is hereby suspend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 15, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1443" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the House by a two-thirds vote, yeas 87, nays none; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 21, nays 1.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 5.] CHAPTER 4.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making appropriations for deficiencies in the appropriations heretofore made for payment of expenses in support of the State government from March 1st, 1895, to February 28th, 1897, and for previous years, being for payment of claims registered in the Comptroller&#8217;s office in accordance with law, and for outstanding claims not registered, and other deficiencies.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following sums, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same are hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, for deficiencies incurred in support of the State government for the period beginning March 1, 1895, and ending Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 28, 1897, and for previous years:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">North Texas Insane Asylum.</head>
<p>Registered. Estimated.</p>
<p>Wagons, hacks and harness for year ending Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 28, 1895...... @34 63</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Judiciary Department.</head>
<p>Fees and costs of sheriffs, clerks and attorneys, in felony cases................ 38,788 00 $4,000 00</p>
<p>Fees of county judges, justices of the peace, sheriffs and constables, in examining trials............ 2,616 00 1,000 00</p>
<p>Fees of attached witnesses.......... 47,264 19 1,500 00</p>
<p>Fees of clerks in civil cases........... 3,379 17 1000 00</p>
<p>Fees of attorneys in civil cases......... 11,931 00 400 00</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Criminal Appeals.</head>
<p>Clerks&#8217; fees in criminal cases, year ending Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 28, 1896............ 610 00</p>
<p>Clerks&#8217; fees in criminal cases, year ending Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 28, 1897........ 970 00 500 00</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, year ending February 28, 1896.......... 2 45</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Civil Appeals, Second District.</head>
<p>Contingent expenses, year ending February 28, 1896&#8220;..... 3 43</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, year ending February 28, 1897............. 41 60</p>
<p>Postage, year ending February 28, 1897...... 8 70</p>
<p>Stationery, year ending February 28, 1897.... 28 40</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1444" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Texas Live Stock Sanitary Commission.</head>
<p>Year ending February 28, 1897..... 994 40</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Miscellaneous.</head>
<p>Refund to purchasers of public domain, 1896-7, where in accordance to the certificate of the Commissioner of the General Land Office it is shown that because of conflict, erroneous sales, and other causes, patents cannot issue; said claims to be approved by the Attorney General and Governor........... 843 16</p>
<p>Relief of liquor dealers prior to 1895..... 890 40</p>
<p>To Lawrence Smith, for services as guard at Camp Mabry, for five months, at $35 per month........... 175 00</p>
<p>For relief of W. Y. Robinson, sheriff of San Ja<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinto county, for fees April and October terms of court, 1895, and April term, 1896, he hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing failed to, present the account to the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller for payment within the time prescribed by law..... 763 45</p>
<p>Groceries, drugs, shoes, and other expenses for State Orphan&#8217;s Asylum....... 1,716 16</p>
<p>G. B. Martin, sheriff of King county, for guard<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing infected stock under the direction and by order of the live stock sanitary officers.... 12 50</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, there being no appropriations to pay claims against the State herein provided for, which are outstanding and are legal claims against the State, creates an emergency and an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity which justifies the suspension of the constitutional rule which re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quires bills to be read on three several days in each house, and this act should take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 15, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 21, nays 1; passed the House, with amendments, by a two-thirds vote; and was referred to a free conference committee, the report of which was adopted by the Senate, vote not given, and was adopted by the House by a two-thirds vote, yeas 89, nays 1.]</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1445" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. H. B. 6 &#38; 19.] CHAPTER 5.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to fix certain civil fees to be charged by certain county and precinct offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, and to fix and limit the fees and compensation of clerks of the district court, district attorneys, county attorneys, sheriffs and constables in felony cases, to be paid by the State, and to fix the compensation of assessors and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lectors of taxes, and to limit and regulate the compensation of the sheriff, clerk of the county court, county judge, district and county attorney, clerk of the district court, assessor and collector of taxes, justices of the peace and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stables, and to prescribe penalties for the violation of this act and to repeal all laws in conflict herewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That hereafter, in all the comities in this State, where there shall have been cast at the next preceding presidential election 3000 votes or over, the clerks of the district courts, district attorneys, county attorneys, sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iffs and constables shall receive from the State the following fees and compensation in felony cases, and no more :</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The clerks of the district court shall receive for each felony case tried in such court by jury, whether the defendant be convicted or acquitted, the sum of $8. For each transcript on appeal or change of venue, 8 cents for each 100 words. For each felony case finally disposed of without trial, or dismissed or nolle prosequi entered, $8. For record<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing each account of sheriff, the sum of 50 cents. For entering judgment in habeas corpus cases, 80 cents; and for taking down testimony and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paring transcript in habeas corpus cases, 8 cents for each 100 words; but the fees in habeas corpus cases shall, in no event, exceed $8 in any one case.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The district or county attorneys shall receive the following fees:</p>
<p>1. For all convictions in cases of felonious homicide, when the defend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant does not appeal, or dies, or escapes after appeal and before final judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the Court of Criminal Appeals, or, when upon appeal the judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment is affirmed, the sum of $40.</p>
<p>2. For all convictions of felony when the defendant does not appeal, or dies, or escapes after appealing and before final judgment of the Court of Criminal Appeals, or, when upon appeal, the judgment is af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmed, the sum of $24; provided, that in all convictions of felony where the verdict and judgment is confinement in the House of Correction and Reformatory, the fees of the district or county attorney shall be $12.</p>
<p>3. For representing the State in each case of habeas corpus where the defendant is charged with felony, the sum of $16.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The sheriffs or constables shall receive the following fees:</p>
<p>1. For executing each warrant of arrest or capias, or for making arrest without warrant, when authorized by law, the sum of 80 cents, and 4 cents for each mile actually and necessarily traveled in going to the place of arrest, and for conveying the prisoner or prisoners to jail, mileage as provided for in subdivision 5 shall be allowed.</p>
<p>2. For summoning or attaching each witness, 40 cents.</p>
<p>3. For summoning jury in each case where jury is actually sworn in. $1.60.</p>
<p>4. For executing death warrants, $40.</p>
<p>5. For removing a prisoner, for each mile going and coming, including<pb n="1446" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>guards and all other necessary expenses when traveling by railroad, 8 cents; when traveling otherwise than by railroad, 12 cents; provided, that when more than one prisoner is removed at the same time, in addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to the foregoing shall only be allowed 8 cents per mile for each addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional prisoner; provided, further, that when an officer goes beyond the limits of the State after a fugitive on requisition of the Governor, he shall receive such compensation as the Governor shall allow for such services.</p>
<p>6. For each mile the officer may be compelled to travel in executing criminal process, summoning or attaching witnesses, 4 cents; provided, that in no case shall be be allowed to duplicate his mileage when two or more witnesses are named in the same or different writs in any case, and he shall serve process on them in the same neighborhood or vicinity dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same trip. He shall not charge mileage for serving such witness to and from the county seat, but shall only charge one mileage, and for such additional only as are actually and necessarily traveled in summon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and attaching each additional witness. When process is sent by mail to any officer away from the county seat, or returned by mail by such officer, he shall only be allowed to charge mileage for the miles actually traveled by him in executing such process, and the return of the officer shall show the character of the service and miles actually traveled in ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cordance with this subdivision, and his accounts shall show the facts.</p>
<p>7. To officers for service of criminal process not otherwise provided for, the sum of 4 cents a mile going and returning shall be allowed; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, if two or more persons are mentioned in the same or different writs the rule prescribed in subdivision 6 shall apply.</p>
<p>8. For conveying a witness attached by him to any court, or in any habeas corpus proceeding out of his county, or when di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rected by the judge from any other county to the court where the case is pending, $1 per day for each day actually and necessarily consumed in going and returning from such courts, and his actual necessary expenses by the nearest practicable route, or nearest prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable public conveyance, the amount to be stated by him in an account, which shall show the place where the witness was attached, the distance to the nearest railroad station, and miles actually traveled to each court. If horses or vehicles are used, from whom hired and price paid, and length of time consumed and amount paid out for feeding horses and to whom. If meals and lodging were provided, from whom, and when, and price paid; provided, that officers shall not be entitled to receive exceeding 50 cents per meal and 35 cents per night for lodging for any witness; and provided, further, that no item or items for expenses shall be allowed unless the officer shall present with his account to the officer whose duty it is to approve same a receipt in writing for each item of said account, except as to such items as are furnished by the officer himself; and when meals and lodgings are furnished by the officer in person conveying a witness he shall be allowed to receive not exceeding 25 cents per meal and 25 cents per night for lodging. All of the said receipts shall be filed with the clerk of the court approving such account. Said account shall also show, before the said officer shall be entitled to compensation for expenses of attached witnesses, that before starting with said witnesses to the foreign court, he carried each of them before the magistrate nearest the place of serving the attachment, giving his<pb n="1447" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>name and residence, and that said witness made oath in writing before said magistrate, certified copies of which shall be attached to the account, that they were unable to give bond for their appearance at court, or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fused to give bond after having been advised by said officer of their right to do so. And the officer shall also present to the court the affidavit of the witness to the same effect, or shall show that the witness refused to make the affidavit; and should it appear to the court that the witness was able and willing to give bond, the sheriff shall not be entitled to any compensation for conveying such witness; and said account shall be sworn to by the officer before any officer authorized to administer oaths, and shall state that said account is true, just, and correct in every par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticular, and present the same to the judge, who shall, during such term of court, carefully examine such account, and if found to be correct in whole or in part, shall so certify and allow the same for such amount as he may find to be correct; and if by him allowed, in whole or in part, he shall so certify; and such account, with the affidavit of the sheriff and certificate of the judge, shall be recorded by the clerk of the district court in a book to be kept by him for that purpose, which shall consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute part of the proceedings or minutes of the court; and the clerk shall certify to the original account, and shall show that the same has been recorded; and said account shall then become due and the same shall constitute a voucher, on which the Comptroller is authorized to issue a warrant, and such minutes of the court, or a certified copy thereof, may be used in evidence against the officer making the affidavit, for perjury, in case said affidavit shall be wilfully false. When the officer receiving the writ for the attachment of such witness, shall take a bond for the appearance of such witness, he shall be entitled to receive from the State $1 for each bond so taken; but he shall be responsible to the court issuing said writ that said bond is in proper form and has been executed by the witness with one or more good or solvent sureties, and said bond shall in no case be less than one hundred dollars; provided, the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller may require from such officer a certified copy of all such process before auditing any account; provided, that when no inquest or examin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing trial has been held, at which sufficient evidence was taken upon which to find an indictment, which fact shall be certified by the grand jury, or when the grand jury shall state to the district judge that an indictment can not be procured, except upon the testimony of non-resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent witnesses, the district judge may have attachments issued to other counties for witnesses, not to exceed the number for which the sheriff may receive pay, as provided for below, to testify before grand juries; provided, however, that the judge shall not approve the account of any sheriff for more than one witness to any one fact, nor more than three witnesses to any one case pending before the grand jury, in which case the sheriff shall receive the same compensation as he does for conveying attached witnesses before the court. Subdivision 8 section 4 of this act shall apply to the officers affected thereby in all the counties in Texas.</p>
<p>9. For attending a prisoner on habeas corpus, for each day, $1.60 to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with mileage, as provided in subdivision 5, when removing such prisoner out of the county, under an order issued by a district or appel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late judge.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. All fees accruing under this act shall be due and payable at<pb n="1448" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>the close of each term of the district court after approval, except as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in subdivisions 8 and 9 of the preceding section, which shall be paid when approved by the judge under whose order the writ was issued; provided, that in all cases when the defendant shall be finally convicted of a misdemeanor, the sheriff or constable shall Be required to pay back to the State Treasurer a sum of money equal to the amount he may have received from the State in such cases, and the said sheriff or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stable and their bondsmen shall be responsible to the State for such sums.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. In cases where the defendant is indicted for a felony, and is convicted of an effense less than a felony, no cost shall be paid by the State to any officer.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That in those counties where there shall have been cast at the next preceding presidential election less than 3000 votes the clerk of the district courts, district attorneys, county attorneys, sheriffs and consta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bles shall receive from the State the fees and compensation in felony cases allowed under now existing laws, and are not intended to be af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fected by the provisions of sections 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Each assessor of taxes shall receive the following compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for his services, which shall be estimated upon the total values of the property assessed, as follows: For assessing the State and county tax, on all sums for the first $2,000,000 or less, 5 cents for each $100 of property assessed; and on all sums in excess of $2,000,000 and less than $5,000,000, 2 1/4 cents on each $100; and on all sums in excess of $5,000. 000, 1 7-10 cents on each $100; one-half of the above fees shall be paid by the State and one-half by the county; and for assessing the poll tax, 5 cents for each poll, which shall be paid by the State. The commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers&#8217; court may allow to the asssessor of taxes such sums of money, to be paid monthly from the county treasury, as may be necessary to pay for clerical work, taking assessments and making out the tax rolls of the county such sums so allowed to be deducted from the amount allowed to the assessor as compensation upon the completion of said tax rolls; provided, the amount allowed the assessor by the commissioners court shall not exceed the compensation that may be due by the county to him for assessing.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. There shall be paid for the collection of taxes, as compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for the services of the collector, beginning with the 1st day of Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember of each year, 5 per cent on the first $10,000 collected for the State, and 4 per cent on the next $10,000 collected for the State, and 1 per cent on all collected over that sum; for collecting the county taxes, 5 per cent on the first $5000 of such taxes collected, and 4 per cent on the next $5000 collected, and 14 per cent on all such taxes collected over that sum, and in counties owing subsides to railroads, the collectors shall receive only 1 per cent for collecting such railroad tax; and in cases where property is levied upon and sold for taxes, he shall receive the same compensation as allowed by law to sheriffs or constables upon making a levy and sale in similar cases, but in no case to include com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missions on such sales; and on all occupation and license taxes collected, 5 per cent.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That hereafter the maximum amount of fees of all kinds that may be retained by any officer mentioned in this section as compensation for services shall be as follows: County judge, an<pb n="1449" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; clerk of the county court, an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; county attorney an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; district attorney, an amount not exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing $2500 per annum, inclusive of the $500 allowed by the Constitution and paid by the State; clerk of the district court, an amount not exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing $2000 per annum; collector of taxes, an amount- not exceeding $2000 per annum; assessor of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2000; justice of the peace, an amount not exceding $1500 per annum; constables, an amount not exceeding $1200 per annum; and in addition thereto one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth of the excess of the fees collected by the said officers respectively; provided, that this act shall not apply to justices of the peace and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stables, except those holding office in cities of more than 15,000 in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants, to be determined by the next preceding city election on the basis of five inhabitants for each vote cast at such election; provided, that up to 1902 in counties in which there were cast at the last presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dential election as many as 5000 votes, and thereafter in any counties shown by the national census of 1900 to contain as many as 25,000 in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants, the following amounts shall be allowed, viz.: County judge, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; clerk of the county court, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; county attorney, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; district attorney, an amount not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding $2500 per annum, inclusive of the $500 allowed by the Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution and paid by the State; clerk of the district court, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; collector of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; assessor of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; in addition thereto one-fourth of the excess of fees collected by the said officers respectively; provided, further, that in counties contain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a city of over 25,000 inhabitants, or in which there were cast at the last presidential election as many as 7500 votes or by the census of 1900 shall contain as many as 37,500 inhabitants, the following amount of fees shall be allowed, viz.: County judge, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; clerk of the county court, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; county attorney, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; district attorney, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum, inclusive of the $500 allowed by the Constitution and paid by the State; clerk of the district court, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; collector of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; assessor of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; and in addition thereto one-fourth of the fees collected by the officers respectively; provided, that the county attorney in those counties having no district attorney, where he perforins the duties of district attorney, may receive the same conn pensation as provided for the district attorney; provided, the maximum fixed for compensation of the district attorney shall be construed to be the amount which that officer is authorized to retain of fees allowed such officer in his district, whether composed of one or more counties; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that in counties where a county judge acts as superintendent of public instruction he shall receive such other salary as may be provided by the commissioners court, not to exceed the sum of $600 per annum. The last United States census shall govern as to the population of cities.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The amounts allowed to each officer mentioned in section 10 of this act may be retained out of the fees collected by him under exist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing laws; but in no case shall the State or the county be responsible for<pb n="1450" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>the payment of any sum when the fees collected by any officer are less than the maximum compensation allowed by this act, or be responsible for the pay of any deputy or assistant. Each officer mentioned in the preceding section, and also the sheriff, shall at the close of each fiscal year, make to the district court of the county in which he resides a sworn statement showing the amount of fees collected by him during the fiscal year, and the amount of fees charged and not collected, and by whom due, and the number of deputies and assistants employed by him during the year, and the amounts paid or to be paid each; and all fees collected by officers named in section 10 of this act during the fiscal year, in excess of the maximum amount allowed and of the one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth of the excess of the maximum amount allowed for their services, and for the services of their deputies or assistants hereinafter provided for, shall be paid to the county treasurer of the county where the excess accrued; provided, that any officer in section 10 of this act who does not collect the maximum amount of his fees for any fiscal year, and who reports delinquent fees for that year, shall be entitled to retain when col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected, such part of such delinquent fees as is sufficient to complete the maximum compensation for the year in which, delinquent fees were charged, and also to retain the one-fourth of the excess belonging to him, and the remainder of the delinquent fees for that fiscal year shall be paid as hereinbefore provided for when collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Whenever any officer named in section 10 of this act shall require the service of deputies or assistants in the performance of his duties, he shall apply to the county judge of his county for authority to appoint same, and the county judge shall issue an order authorizing the appointment of such a number of deputies or assistants as in his opinion may be necessary for the efficient performance of the duties of said offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer. The officer applying for appointment of a deputy or assistant, or deputies or assistants, shall make affidavit that they are necessary for the efficiency of the public service; and the county judge may require, in addition, a statement showing the need of such deputies or assistants, and in no case shall the county judge attempt to influence the appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of any person as deputy or assistant in any office. The maximum amount allowed for deputies or assistants for their services shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>First assistant or chief deputy, a sum not to exceed a rate of $1200 per annum, others not to exceed a rate of $900 per annum.</p>
<p>The county judge in issuing his order granting authority to appoint deputies or assistants, shall state in such order the number of deputies or assistants authorized and the amount to be paid each, and the amount of compensation allowed shall be paid out of the fees of office to which said deputies or assistants may be appointed, and shall not be included in estimating the maximum salaries of officers named in section 10 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. All fees due and not collected as shown in the report re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by section 11 of this act shall be collected by the officer to whose office the fees accrued and out of such part of delinquent fees as may be due the county, the officer making such collection shall be entitled to 10 per cent of the amount collected by him, and the remaider shall be paid into the county treasury, as provided in section 11 of this act. It shall<pb n="1451" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>not be legal for any officer to remit any fee that may be due under the law fixing fees.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Any officer named in section 10 of this act, and also the sheriff, who shall fail to charge up the fees or costs that may be due under existing laws, or who shall remit any fee that may due under the laws, or who shall fail to make the report required in section 11 of this act, or who shall pay his deputy or assistant a less sum than the amount specified in his sworn statement, or receive back any part of such compensation allowed such deputy or assistant, as a rebate, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be fined in any sum not less than $25 nor more than $500. Each act for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bidden in this section shall constitute a separate offence.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. It is not intended by this act that the commissioners court shall be debarred from allowing compensation for ex officio services to county officials not to be included in estimating the maximum provided for in this act, when in their judgment such compensation is necessary; provided, such compensation for ex officio services shall not exceed the amounts now allowed under the law for ex officio services; provided further, the fees allowed by law to district and county clerks, county attorneys and tax collectors in suits to collect taxes shall be in addition to the maximum salaries fixed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. It shall be the duty of those officials named in section 10 of this act, and also the sheriffs, to keep a correct statement of the sums coming into their hands as fees and commissions, in a book to be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by them for that purpose, in which the officer at the time when any fees or moneys shall come into his hands shall enter the same, and it shall be the duty of the grand jury (and the district judge shall so charge the grand jury) to examine these accounts at the session of the district court next succeeding the first day of December of each year, and make a report on same to the district court at the conclusion of the session of the grand jury.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The officers named in section 10 of this act, in those coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties having a population of 15,000, or less, shall not be required to make a report of fees as provided in section 11 of this act. or to keep a state<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment provided for in section 16 of this act; the population of the county to be determined by the vote cast at the next preceding presidential election, on the basis of five inhabitants for each vote cast at such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; provided, that all district attorneys shall be required to make the reports and keep the statements required in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. The tax collector and the tax assessor, at the time of their set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement of accounts with the Comptroller, shall file with him a copy of the sworn statement required under section 11 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. A fiscal year within the meaning of this act shall begin on December 1, of each year, and each officer named in section 10 of this act and also the sheriff shall file the reports and make the settlement re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired in this act on December 1 of each year. Whenever such officer serves for a fractional part of a fiscal year, he shall nevertheless file his report and make a settlement for such part of a year as he serves, and shall be entitled to such proportional part of the maximum allowed as the time of his services bears to the entire year. However, an incoming officer elected at the general election, who qualifies prior to December 1 next following, shall not be required to file any report or make any set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1452" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>tlement before December 1 of the following year, but his report and set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement shall embrace the entire period dated from his qualification. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after December 1, 1897.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. The sheriff shall not be required to include in his reports and statements required by sections 11 and 16 of this act the following items, to-wit: All actual expenses, including the per diem allowed him received from the State in conveying attached witnesses out of the county of his residence. 2d. Mileage and sums allowed by law and paid by the State as expenses for removing and conveying prisoners to and from any point beyond the county of the sheriff&#8217;s residence under all legal warrants issued in felony cases. 3d. All sums received as rewards for making arrests of fugitives from justice. 4th. All sums received from the county for the safe keeping, support and maintenance of pris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />oners confined in jail. Nor shall said items be regarded as fees of office within the meaning of this act, to be included in making up the sheriff&#8217;s maximum.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. Any district clerk who shall issue any attachment or sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poena for any witness except upon an order of court or upon the written application, signed and sworn to by the defendant or State&#8217;s council, stating that such witness is believed to be a material witness, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction fined in any sum not less than $25 and not more than $500.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. The clerks of the district court shall receive for the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing; services the following; fees :</p>
<p>For copy of petition, including certificate and seal, each 100 words, 15 cents; provided, whenever in any suit a certified copy of any petition or any other instrument is necessary in the district or county court, it shall be lawful for the plaintiff or defendant to prepare such true and correct copy thereof, and to submit the same to the clerk of the district or county court, as the case may be, whose duty it shall be to compare the same with the original instrument, and if found to be correct he shall attach his certificate of true copy; for such service he shall receive 50 cents for each certificate and seal, and in addition thereto the sum of 10 cents per page, 700 words to the page, for each page of said copy. Each writ of citation, 75 cents; each copy of writ of citation. 25 cents; filing of each paper 10 cents; entering appearance of each party to suit, to be charged but once, 5 cents; each final judgment or decree, 75 cents; every other order, judgment or decree, not exceeding 200 words, 25 cents; where the order, judgment or decree, whether final or not, exceeds 200 words, the additional fee for each 100 words in excess of 200 words shall be 10 cents; making out and transmitting the records and proceedings in a cause to an inferior court, for each 100 words, 15 cents; making transcript of the records and papers in any cause upon appeal or writ of error, with certificate and seal, each 100 words, 10 cents; recording re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turn of any writ, when any such return is required by law to be returned, the amount of 50 cents; where the return exceeds 300 words, for each 100 words in excess of 300 words, 10 cents; making a copy of all records of judgment, or papers on file in his office, for any party applying for same, with certificate and seal, where copy does not exceed 200 words, for each 100 words, 20 cents; where the copy exceeds 200 words, for each additional 100 words in excess of 200 words, 10 cents.</p>
<pb n="1453" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 23. The clerks of the county court shall receive for the following services the following fees:</p>
<p>Each final judgment or decree, 50 cents; every other order or decree, not exceeding 100 words, 15 cents; where such other order or decree con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tains 100 words and not more than 200 words, 25 cents; when any final judgment or decree, or any other order or decree, exceeds 200 words, an additional fee for each 100 words in excess of 200 words of 10 cents; each appearance to be charged but once, 5 cents; each additional name inserted in a subpoena, 5 cents; approving bond, except bond for cost and notarial bond, $1; approving notarial bond, 50 cents; copies of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terrogatories, cross-interrogatories and all other papers or records re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be copied by him, including certificate and seal, where the copy does not exceed 200 words, for each 100 words, 15 cents; where the copy exceeds 200 words, for each additional 100 words in excess of 200 words, 10 cents; transcript in any case where appeal or writ of error is taken, with certificate and seal, each 100 words, 10 cents; recording all papers required or permitted by law to be recorded, not otherwise pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for, including certificate and seal, for each 100 words, 10 cents; issuing and recording marriage license, $1; recording return of any writ, when any such return is required by law to be returned, the amount of 50 cents; where the return exceeds 300 words, for each 100 words in ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess of 300 words, 10 cents; qualifying a notary public, 50 cents. No county or district clerk shall receive any compensation for assessing dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages in any case.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. Sheriffs shall receive for the following services the following fees:</p>
<p>Serving each original citation in a civil suit, 75 cents; levying and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turning writ of attachment or sequestration, $2; levying each execution, $1; return of execution, 50 cents; serving each writ of garnishment or other process not otherwise provided for, 75 cents; serving each writ of injunction, $1; collecting money on an execution or an order of sale, when the same is made by a sale, for the first $100 or less, 4 per cent; for the second $100, 3 per cent; for all sums over $200 and not exceeding $1000, 2 per cent; for all sums over $1000 and not exceeding $5000, 1 per cent; for all sums over $5000, one-half of one per cent.</p>
<p>Sec. 25 Justices of the peace shall receive for the following services the following fees:</p>
<p>For filing each paper, 5 cents; each continuance, 10 cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. All laws or parts of laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed. It is not intended, however, by this act to repeal the present laws with regard to any fees, except where there is a conflict between the fees prescribed by now existing laws and the fees prescribed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. The fact that the session of the Legislature is fast growing to a close, and the importance of this bill, creates an emergency and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this bill be put on its third reading and final passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 16, 1897</date>.</dateline>
<dateline>Takes effect <date>December 1, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1454" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 7.] CHAPTER 6.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prescribe and define the liability of persons, receivers or corporations operating railroads or street railways, for injuries to their servants and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployes; to define who are fellow-servants, and to prohibit contracts between employer and employe, based upon the contingency of the injury or death of the employe, limiting the liability of the employer for damages.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That every person, receiver, or corporation operating a railroad or street railway the line of which shall be situated in whole or in part in this State, shall be liable for all damages sustained by any servant or em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ploye thereof while engaged in the work of operating the cars, loco<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />motives or trains of such person, receiver, or corporation, by reason of the negligence of any other servant or employe of such person, receiver, or corporation, and the fact that such servants or employes were fellow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servants with each other shall not impair or destroy such liability.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All persons engaged in the service of any person, receiver, or corporation, controlling or operating a railroad or street railway the line of which shall be situated in whole or in part in this State, who are intrusted by such person, receiver, or corporation with the authority of superintendence, control or command of other servants or employes of such person, receiver, or corporation, or with the authority to direct any other employe in the performance of any duty of such employe, are vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />principals of such person, receiver, or corporation, and are not fellow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servants with their co-employes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All persons who are engaged in the common service of such person, receiver, or corporation, controlling or operating a railroad or street railway, and who while so employed are in the same grade of employment and are doing the same character of work or service and are working together at the same time and place and at the same piece of work and to a common purpose, are fellow-servants with each other. Employes who do not come within the provisions of this section shall not be considered fellow-servants.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. No contract made between the employer and employe based upon the contingency of death or injury of the employe and limiting the liability of the employer under this act or fixing damages to be recovered shall be valid or binding.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Nothing in this act shall be held to impair or diminish the defense of contributory negligence when the injury of the servant or employe is caused proximately by his own contributory negligence.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The short duration of the special session of the Legislature, and the fact that the existing fellow-servant law is inadequate to accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plish its purposes, and the fact that a large portion of our citizens have no adequate remedy for personal injuries sustained, create an emergency, and an imperative public necessity exists, that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be, and the same is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 18, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate by a, vote of yeas 20, nays 5; and passed the House by a vote of yeas 64, nays 40.]</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1455" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 17.] CHAPTER 7.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 1331, Chapter 13, Title 30, of the Revised Statutes of Texas of 1895, relating to special verdicts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 1331, Chapter 13, Title 30, of the Revised Civil Statutes of 1895, be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Art. 1331. The special verdict must find the facts established by the evidence and not the evidence by which they are established; and it shall be the duty of the court when it submits a case to the jury upon special issues to submit all the issues made by the pleading. But the failure to submit any issue shall not be deemed a ground for reversal of the judgment upon appeal or a writ of error unless its submission has been requested in writing by the party complaining of the judgment. Upon appeal or writ of error, an issue not submitted and not requested by a party to the cause, shall be deemed as found by the court in such manner as to support the judgment; provided, there be evidence to sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain such a finding.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that much inconvenience and intolerable delay ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />crue to litigants in this State, the tendency of which is to prolong liti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation and crowd and burden the dockets of the courts, for want of a law authorizing a simple and expeditious method for the decisions of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troverted questions of fact by special verdict, creates an imperative pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic necessity requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule which requires bills to be read on three several clays, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 18, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 25, nays none; and passed the House by a two-thirds vote, yeas 86, nays 14.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 15.] CHAPTER 8.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 3051, Chapter 2, Title LVIII, of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas, giving the Commissioner of Insurance power to examine into the condition of any insurance company of this State or any other State, and to revoke the license of such company or companies upon refusal to sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit to such examination.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 3051, Chapter 2, Title LVIII, of the Revised Civil Statutes, be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 3051. The Commissioner of Insurance, for the purpose of ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aminations authorized by law, has power either in person or by one or more examiners by him commissioned in writing:</p>
<p>1. To require free access to all books and papers within this State of any insurance companies or the agents thereof doing business within this State.</p>
<p>2. To summon and examine any person within this State, under oath,<pb n="1456" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>which he or any examiner may administer, relative to the affairs and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition of any insurance company.</p>
<p>3. To visit, at its principal office, wherever situated, any insurance company doing business in this State, for the purpose of investigating its affairs and condition, and shall revoke the certificate of authority of any such company in this State refusing to permit such examination.</p>
<p>4. He may revoke or modify any certificate of authority issued by him when any conditions prescribed by law for granting it no longer exist.</p>
<p>5. He also has power to institute suits and prosecutions, either by the attorney general or such other attorney as the attorney general may designate, for any violation of the law of this State relating to insur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance, and he shall be made a party to any proceeding for the closing up of the affairs of any company when the same shall not be in the name of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the close of the session, and the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portance of the law empowering the commissioner of insurance to exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine into the affairs and conditions of any company that is authorized to do business in this State, create an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 18, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 21.] CHAPTER 9.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to fix the venue and regulate the proceedings in prosecutions for rape.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: Prosecutions for rape may be commenced and carried on in the county in which the offense is committed, or in any county of the judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict in which the offense is committed, or in any county of the judicial district the judge of which resides nearest the county seat of the county in which the offense is committed. When the judicial district com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prises only one county, prosecutions may be commenced and carried on in that county if the offense be committed there, or in any adjoining county. When it shall come to the knowledge of any district judge whose court has jurisdiction under this act that the offense of rape has probably been committed, it shall be his duty, immediately, if his court be in session, and if not in session, then at the first term thereafter in any county of the district, to call the attention of the grand jury thereto; and, if his court be in session but the grand jury shall have been dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charged, he shall immediately recall said grand jury for the considera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the accusation. Prosecutions for rape shall take precedence of all cases in all courts, and the district courts are hereby authorized and directed to change the venue in such cases whenever it shall be necessary to secure a speedy trial.</p>
<pb n="1457" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that there is no adequate law in this State for the suppression of rape creates an emergency and an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 18, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate by a rote of yeas 15, nays 6; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. S. B. No. 2.] CHAPTER 10.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making appropriations for the support of the State Government, for the years beginning March 1st, 1897, and ending February 28, 1899, and for other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following sums of money, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, are hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appropriated for the support of the State government, for the years beginning March 1st, 1897, and ending February 28th, 1899, and for other purposes:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Executive Office.</head>
<p>Year ending</p>
<p>Feb. 28, &#8216;98. Feb. 28, &#8216;99.</p>
<p>Salary of Governor.................... $4,000 $4,000</p>
<p>Salary of private secretary................... 1,700 1,700</p>
<p>Salary of stenographic clerk........... 1,100 1,100</p>
<p>Salary of porter.......... 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of State Revenue Agent........... 1,800 1,800</p>
<p>Traveling and other necessary expenses of State Revenue Agent........... 300 300</p>
<p>Payment of rewards and other expenses necessary in the enforcement of the law........... 7,250 7,250</p>
<p>Books and stationery....... 300 300</p>
<p>Freight, postage, and telegraphing............... 500 500</p>
<p>Ice....... 36 36</p>
<p>Office furniture......... 100 100</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, including new typewriter.... 200 100</p>
<p>Salaries of Board of Pardons.......... 2,400 2,400</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Mansion and Grounds.</head>
<p>For Governor&#8217;s Mansion, and furniture, including repairs to mansion and improvements to grounds surrounding mansion, and contingent expenses; to be expended in two years............ $2,500</p>
<p>Laborer, and keeping up grounds surrounding man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion....... 700 $700</p>
<p>Water and Ice......... 200 200</p>
<p>Fuel and Lights........ 450 450</p>
<p>Contingent expenses........ 200 200</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1458" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Department of State.</head>
<p>For salary of Secretary of State....... $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk.......... 1,550 1,550</p>
<p>Salary of two assistant clerks............. 2,280 2,280</p>
<p>Salary of one assistant clerk.................... 950 950</p>
<p>Salary of one stenographic and general clerk.......... 900 900</p>
<p>Salary of porter.......... 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of extra clerk to copy laws............ 250</p>
<p>Freight, postage and express........ 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Books and stationery.......... 400 400</p>
<p>Furniture and files......... 50 50</p>
<p>Contingent expenses.......... 100 100</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Comptroller&#8217;s Office.</head>
<p>Salary of Comptroller............... $2,500 $2,500</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk........... 1,700 1,700</p>
<p>Salary of chief bookkeeper........... 1,550 1,550</p>
<p>Salary of assistant bookkeeper............ 1,300 1,300</p>
<p>Salaries of two sheriff&#8217;s clerks, witnesses and attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />neys&#8217; accountants....... 2,600 2,600</p>
<p>Salary of clerk for registering city, county and other bonds...... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of receiving clerk...... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salary of warrant clerk..... 1,300 1,300</p>
<p>Salary of assistant warrant clerk......... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper in warrant department........ 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salaries of two corresponding clerks........ 2,280 2,280</p>
<p>Salary of chief tax clerk............ 1,350 1,350</p>
<p>Salary of assistant tax clerk.......... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of redemption clerk.... 1,300 1,300</p>
<p>Salary of assistant redemption clerk... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of examining clerk........ 1,300 1,300</p>
<p>Salary or assistant examining clerk....... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of auditing clerk.. 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Salary of assistant auditing clerk...... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of deposit warrant clerk....... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salaries of twelve first assistant clerks.............. 12,000 12,000</p>
<p>Salaries of nine second assistant clerks......... 8,100 8,100</p>
<p>Salary of messenger.............. 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of porter...................... 420 420</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman........ 150</p>
<p>Postage, telegraphing, express, office furniture and contingent expenses, the latter not to exceed $200. 3,500 3,500</p>
<p>Books and stationery....... 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Binding assessment rolls and tax collectors&#8217; reports. 1,000 1,000</p>
<p>Roller case and shelving......... 1,200</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1459" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Treasury Department.</head>
<p>Salary of Treasurer......... $2,500 $2,500</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk......... 1,700 1,700</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper........ 1,450 1,450</p>
<p>Salary of assistant bookkeeper........... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of receiving clerk........ 1,350 1,350</p>
<p>Salary of corresponding clerk...... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salaries of two bookkeepers in Land Department, at $1300 each........ 2,600 2,600</p>
<p>Salary of examining clerk.............. 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>For salaries of five assistant bookkeepers in Land Department, two at $1100 each, and three at $1000 each........ 5,200 5,200</p>
<p>Salary of collector, general office assistant, messen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ger and porter....... 600 600</p>
<p>Books and stationery.......... 400 400</p>
<p>Postage............... 750 750</p>
<p>Contingent expenses.......... 100 100</p>
<p>Keeping in repair time-locks, combinations and vaults, or so much thereof as may be necessary............... 150 150</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman.......... 600 600</p>
<p>Office furniture and files........ 150 150</p>
<p>For refunding to purchasers, assignees or lessees of public domain, public school, university or asylum lands, the money paid by them into the State Treasury in accordance with any of the laws of this State, and where, in accordance to the certificate of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, made under the provisions of the said chapter CXI, as amended by act of the 24th legislature in H. B. 358, it is shown that the title can not issue or pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />session pass, because of conflict, erroneous sales, and other causes patents can not issue, to be paid out of the respective funds to which said payments were credited, said claims to be approved by the Attorney General and the Governor, to be expend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed within two years........... 10,000</p>
<p>To pay C. C. Gibbs, trustee, or his order, out of the permanent school fund the sum of $74,560, and out of the general fund the sum of $74,560, for the purpose of refunding the amount paid into the Treasury of the State, on or about the 3rd day of January, 1891, for the purchase, under ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plications made by E. M. Bacon and E. G. Graves, of 291 sections of land, of 640 acres each, being surveys numbered from 1 to 291, both inclusive, in Block G, Borden and Scurry counties; 58 sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, of 640 acres each, being surveys numbered from 1 to 58, both inclusive, in block M, in Bor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />den and Scurry counties; and 117 sections, of 640<pb n="1460" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>acres each, being surveys numbered 1 to 117, both inclusive, in block B, in Scurry county, being the lands recovered by the State by a judgment against the said E. M. Bacon and E. G. Graves, and C. C. Gibbs, trustee, rendered on the 22nd day of December, 1891, by the district court in and for Mitchell county, Texas, and affirmed on appeal, amounting in the aggregate to the sum of............. $149,120</p>
<p>But the said sums shall not, nor shall any part thereof, be paid until Frederick P. Olcott, the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser under decree of foreclosure, rendered by the Circuit Court of the United States for the Eastern District of Texas, at Galveston, of lands of the Houston and Texas Central Railway Co., shall exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute to the State of Texas and deliver to the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller a release in writing unto the State of Texas, of any and all claims by him and those he repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sents, in any manner, in or to any of the above named sections of land; said release to be approved by the Attorney General, and to inure to the benefit of the State of Texas, and any persons claiming any of said lands under said State, and said release to settle forever the claims of the Houston and Texas Central Railway Company and Frederick P. Olcott and others interested with him as mortgagees in any of said above described 466 sections of land; and upon the delivery of said release, duly executed and acknowledged by said Olcott, to the Comptroller, the Comptroller shall draw his warrant upon the State Treasurer in favor of C. C. Gibbs, trustee, for the amount of money hereby appropriated.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">General Land Office.</head>
<p>Salary of Commissioner........... $2,500 $2,500</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk......... 1,700 1,700</p>
<p>Salary of first assistant chief clerk........... 1,400 1,400</p>
<p>Salary of receiving clerk......... 1,350 1,350</p>
<p>Salary of Spanish clerk............,350 1,350</p>
<p>Salary of legal examiner.......... 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Salary of corresponding clerk....... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salaries of two patent clerks....... 2,280 2,280</p>
<p>Salaries of two abstract clerks..... 2,160 2,160</p>
<p>Salary of two file clerks........... 2,280 2,280</p>
<p>Salary of one file-room clerk.......... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salaries of two transcript clerks..... 2,160 2,160</p>
<p>Salary of chief draughtsman....... 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Salaries of five compiling draughtsmen.. 6,500 6,500</p>
<p>Salaries of three assistant compiling draughtsmen.. 3,300 3,300</p>
<p>Salary of letter register..... 1,100 1,100</p>
<pb n="1461" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salary of index clerk............ $1,080 $1,080</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman........ 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of porter and janitor........ 420 420</p>
<p>Postage, telegraphing and contingent expenses.......... 1,800 1,800</p>
<p>Stationery, books and fixtures.... 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Wood............. 200 200</p>
<p>Lithographing and miscellaneous........... 450 450</p>
<p>Water and repairs to fixtures...... 300 300</p>
<p>Repairs to building....... 250 250</p>
<p>To pay for certified copies of judgments obtained in favor of the State against the several railroad companies in the recovery of lands where the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates were issued in whole or in part for sid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings and switches, and in the Bacon and Graves case if necessary; provided, the Attorney General shall approve the cost bill of the clerks for such copies, there is appropriated $750, or so much thereof as may be necessary.. 750</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">School Land Department.</head>
<p>Salary of chief clerk........ 1,400 1,400</p>
<p>Salaries of three lease clerks.......... 3,300 3,300</p>
<p>Salaries of two corresponding clerks........... 2,200 2,200</p>
<p>Salary of one draughtsman..... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper.......... 1,300 1,300</p>
<p>Salary of file clerk.......... 1,100 1,100</p>
<p>Salaries of two sales clerks.......... 2,280 2,280</p>
<p>Provided, that the Land Commissioner may dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge any clerk not needed in any particular de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment and apply the money to pay his salary for the purpose of employing help in any other depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment where additional help may be required; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, further, that no more shall be paid for such help than is provided for the compensation of clerks in the department to which the extra help may be assigned; and provided, further, that if any funds appropriated for this department be unexpended, the same, or so much thereof as may be necessary, may be used for the purchase or repair of typewrit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing machine.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Attorney General&#8217;s Office.</head>
<p>Salary of Attorney General........ $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>And the further sum each year, or so much thereof as may be necessary, to pay such fees as may be prescribed by law...... 2,000 2,000</p>
<p>Salary of first office assistant....... 2,500 2,500</p>
<p>Salary of second office assistant...... 2,000 2,000</p>
<p>Salary of third office assistant....... 2,000 2,000</p>
<pb n="1462" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salary of stenographic and corresponding clerk.... $950 $950</p>
<p>Salary of filing and recording clerk... 950 950</p>
<p>Stationery, postage and telegraphing...... 500 500</p>
<p>Law books and periodicals........ 200 200</p>
<p>Cost of depositions and procuring evidence......... 400 400</p>
<p>Porter and messenger........ 360 360</p>
<p>Actual traveling expenses incurred by Attorney General, or any of his assistants, in giving atten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to the State&#8217;s business pending elsewhere than in the courts held in the city of Austin, vouchers to be made under official certificates......... 600 600</p>
<p>Contingent expenses... 100 100</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Criminal Appeals.</head>
<p>Salaries of three judges....... $12,000 $12,000</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer.... 950 950</p>
<p>Sheriff&#8217;s attendance on the court...... 200 200</p>
<p>Postage.... 150 150</p>
<p>Contingent expenses...... 200 200</p>
<p>Fuel and lights.... 100 100</p>
<p>Law books, to be selected by the presiding judge.... 150 150</p>
<p>Record books and stationery... 400 400</p>
<p>Salary, fees and traveling expenses of Assistant At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney General......... 3,000 3,000</p>
<p>Salary of porter....... 360 360</p>
<p>Telegraphing and contingent expenses for Assistant Attorney General... 50 50</p>
<p>Clerks&#8217; fees in criminal cases, or so much thereof as may be necessary.......... 3,000 3,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Supreme Court.</head>
<p>Salaries of three judges........ $12,000 $12,000</p>
<p>Salary of clerk and librarian........... 2,500 2,500</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer and law clerk........... 950 950</p>
<p>Salary of bailiff.. 150 150</p>
<p>Porters hire for judge&#8217;s and consulting room.. 360 360</p>
<p>Porter&#8217;s hire for court room, library and clerk&#8217;s of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice.......... 360 360</p>
<p>Record books and stationery......... 500 500</p>
<p>Postage.. 150 150</p>
<p>Contingent expenses......... 150 150</p>
<p>Purchase of books for Supreme Court library, and books for consultation room........... 1,250 1,250</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Department of Education.</head>
<p>Salary of Superintendent...... $2,500 $2,500</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk... 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Salary of statistical clerk.......... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salary of auditing and index clerk....... 1,140 1,140</p>
<pb n="1463" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salary of stenographer......... $950 $950</p>
<p>Salary of corresponding and examining clerk....... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salary of corresponding and general clerk...... 1,080 1,080</p>
<p>Salary of mailing and bank clerk......... 900 900</p>
<p>Salary of porter...... 300 300</p>
<p>Traveling expenses of Superintendent, visiting schools and teachers&#8217; and trustees&#8217; meetings, and when on business relating to school interests........... 300 300</p>
<p>Postage, stationery, office furniture, files, binding reports and other books and pamphlets.. 1,100 1,100</p>
<p>Express, freight, telegraphing and incidental ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses....... 450 450</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Railroad Commission.</head>
<p>Salaries of three Commissioners........... $12,000 $12,000</p>
<p>Salary of secretary.... 1,800 1,800</p>
<p>Salary of one rate clerk.......... 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Salary of one general clerk........... 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Pay of experts and other necessary expenses........... 12,040 8,040</p>
<p>To pay necessary expenses ox Commissioners and experts in making investigations and enquiries, to be paid on verified vouchers approved by the Chairman of the Railroad Commission....... 1,000</p>
<p>Sheriffs&#8217; and witnesses&#8217; fees, and mileage...... 500 500</p>
<p>Transportation of the members of the commission and clerks........ 250 250</p>
<p>Postage, stationery, books, telegraphing and express charges.......... 500 500</p>
<p>Furniture, fixtures and files............ 100 100</p>
<p>Contingent expenses...... 100 100</p>
<p>Salary&#8217; of porter....... 300 300</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Department of Agriculture, Insurance, Statistics and History.</head>
<p>Salary of Commissioner......... $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk......... 1,700 1,700</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper, stenographer and statistical clerk.......... 1,140 1,140</p>
<p>Salary of agricultural clerk....... 1,140 1,40</p>
<p>Salary of historical clerk...........1,140 1,40</p>
<p>Salary of porter.......... 360 360</p>
<p>Subscription to newspapers and magazines, and bind<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing........... 100 100</p>
<p>Books and book cases and shelving for State Library, 450 450</p>
<p>Collecting historical data........ 150 150</p>
<p>Contingent expenses and telephone....... 100 100</p>
<p>Expenses of Commissioner in enforcing insurance laws........... 500 500</p>
<p>Postage, stationery and express......... 400 400</p>
<p>Book cases and shelving....... 100 100</p>
<pb n="1464" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>For the support and maintenance of the University of Texas, including such repairs and improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments and extensions as the board of regents may deem necessary, all the available fund, including under this head the interest from its land notes, the income from its leases, and the fees from its students, to be under the control of the Board of Begents, less the appropriation made for the Agri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cultural and Mechanical College; all yearly fees collected from students, to be fixed by the Be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gents, to be not less than $10 per year for aca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demic department from each student, with such laboratory fees as the Begents shall fix, and not less than $50 per year from each student in the law department.</p>
<p>To supplement the available fund in the support of the main university, from the general revenue............ $32,500 $32,500</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Medical Department, Galveston.</head>
<p>For support and maintenance out of general rev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enue........... $35,500 $35,500</p>
<p>For repairs out of general revenue, to be expended in two years....... 3,000</p>
<p>In addition to the above revenue, the Board of Regents shall charge each student in medicine and pharmacy the matriculation fee of not less than $50 per year, payable in advance, also a fee of five dollars annually, payable in advance, for each laboratory at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tended, to cover the cost of material used; the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of the above fees shall also be appropriated and supplemented to any of the above named items for the maintenance and support of the said medical branch of the University, and expended in any man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner the Board of Regents may deem for the best in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest of the medical college.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Civil Appeals&#8212;First District.</head>
<p>Salaries of three judges........ $10,500 $10,500</p>
<p>Salary of bailiff...... 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of porter..... 300 300</p>
<p>Postage.... 75 75</p>
<p>Record books and stationery....... 200 200</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, including ice, lights and fuel.. 150 150</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer and typewriter..........600 600</p>
<p>Books for library.... 250 250</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1465" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Civil Appeals&#8212;Second District.</head>
<p>Year ending&#8212;</p>
<p>Feb. 28, &#8216;98. Feb. 28, &#8216;99.</p>
<p>Salaries of three judges.......................... $10,500 $10,500</p>
<p>Salary of bailiff............................ 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of porter................................... 300 300</p>
<p>Postage...................................... 75 75</p>
<p>Record books and stationery............................ 200 200</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, including ice, fuel and lights.. 150 150</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer and typewriter................. 600 600</p>
<p>Books for library............................ 250 250</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Civil Appeals&#8212;Third District.</head>
<p>Salaries of three judges...................... $10,500 $10,500</p>
<p>Salary of bailiff............................. 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of porter............................... 300 300</p>
<p>Record books and stationery............................ 200 200</p>
<p>Postage................................. 75 75</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, including ice, lights and fuel.. 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer and typewriter................</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Civil Appeals&#8212;Fourth District.</head>
<p>Salaries of three judges.................................... $10,500 $10,500</p>
<p>Salary of bailiff................................... 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of porter.................................. 300 300</p>
<p>Postage............................................ 75 75</p>
<p>Books and stationery................................. 200 200</p>
<p>Contingent expenses, including ice, fuel and lights.. 150 150</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer and typewriter................... 600 600</p>
<p>Books for library............................ 250 250</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Court of Civil Appeals&#8212;Fifth District.</head>
<p>Salaries of three judges........................... $10,500 $10,500</p>
<p>Salary of bailiff................................... 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of porter................................... 300 300</p>
<p>Postage............................................ 75</p>
<p>Record books and stationery................................ 200 200</p>
<p>Contingent expenses.............................. 100 100</p>
<p>Salary of stenographer and typewriter................. 600 600</p>
<p>Books for library............................ 250 250</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Judiciary Department.</head>
<p>Salaries of fifty-four district judges............... $133,750 $135,000</p>
<p>Salaries of thirty-eight district attorneys.......... 19,000 19,000</p>
<p>Salary of criminal district attorney................. 500 500</p>
<p>Salaries of two criminal district judges.................. 5,000 5.000</p>
<p>Fees and costs of sheriffs, clerks and attorneys in felony cases.............................. 300,000 300,000</p>
<p>Nor shall the Comptroller approve the account of any sheriff for conveying a convict from the peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1466" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>tentiary to any county for trial on a felony charge, which if convicted would receive a sentence concur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rent with the sentence he was already serving; nor shall such attorneys, clerks or sheriffs be entitled to fees and costs in more than one case, where the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fendant is convicted in two or more cases, unless the judgment in the second and subsequent convictions shall be that the punishment shall begin when the judgment and sentence in the preceding conviction have ceased to operate; nor shall the district judge approve accounts for such fees and costs.</p>
<p>To pay costs in civil cases when such costs are ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />judged against the State, or when such costs can not be recovered from the defendant, in which only such costs as are incurred by the State in such civil cases, shall be said out of this fund.... $2,500 $2,500</p>
<p>Expenses of attached witnesses; provided, that nei<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther the district judge nor the Comptroller shall approve the claim of any person attached as a wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness while under indictment for a felony in the same court in which he is attached to testify...... 50.000 50.000</p>
<p>Salary of Supreme Court reporter..................... 3,000 3,000</p>
<p>Salary of Court of Criminal Appeals reporter....... 3,000 3,000</p>
<p>For compensation for assistant Supreme Court re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porter or reporters of Courts of Civil Appeals.... 2,500 2,500</p>
<p>Fees of county judges, justices of the peace, sheriffs and constables in examining trials................ 10,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Pensions.</head>
<p>Pay of veterans under general laws............. $51,000 $51,000</p>
<p>Mrs. S. L. Cole, special pensioner............ 150 150</p>
<p>P. H. Bell, special pensioner............... 150 150</p>
<p>Mme. Candelaria, special pensioner............. 150 150</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Public Debt.</head>
<p>For interest on public debt.................. $224,420 20 $224,420 20</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Miscellaneous.</head>
<p>To pay for surveying lands set apart for branch Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity of colored people, or so much thereof as may be necessary............................. $1,600</p>
<p>For relief of liquor dealers...................... $5,000 5,000</p>
<p>Refunding to Allison, a State convict.............. 225</p>
<p>To pay sheriff of Hardeman county, Texas, for boarding J. D. Adams, a prisoner convicted of murder in Greer county, and transferred to the jail of Hardeman county, for safe keeping, by or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der of the district judge, pending appeal to the Court of Criminal Appeals, Texas, or so much as may be necessary............................ 350</p>
<pb n="1467" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>All of the available fund belonging to the Asylum for the support and maintenance, in addition thereto from the general revenue the following:</p>
<p>Salary of superintendent............................ $1,000 $1,000</p>
<p>Salary of matron........................ 600 600</p>
<p>Salaries of six teachers.................... 2,400 2,400</p>
<p>Salaries of three cooks............................... 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of one baker........................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of three laundresses.................... 720 720</p>
<p>Salaries of two seamstresses..................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of one physician.......................... 660 660</p>
<p>Salary of farm labor...................... 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of trained nurse......................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of six assistant nurses.................... 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman............................. 360 360</p>
<p>Maintenance................................... 15,000 15,000</p>
<p>Fuel....................................... 500 500</p>
<p>Postage and stationery................................... 100 100</p>
<p>Bedding................................. 600 600</p>
<p>School books, maps, etc............................ 400 400</p>
<p>Window curtains, towels and table linen............ 200 200</p>
<p>Transportation............................... 150 150</p>
<p>Telephone............................. 60 60</p>
<p>Tableware, crockeryware and hardware............. 200 200</p>
<p>Electric lights................................... 550 550</p>
<p>Erecting school building...................... 12,000</p>
<p>Enlarging dining room............................. 2,500</p>
<p>Fire protection.................................. 2,000</p>
<p>Erecting hospital............................. 4,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">State Lunatic Asylum.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent....................... $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of first assistant physician................... 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Salary of second assistant physician................... 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper and steward................... 950 950</p>
<p>Salary of matron........................... 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of apothecary......................... 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of supervisor...................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of supervisoress......................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of outside supervisor......................... 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of chief engineer........................... 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of assistant engineer...................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of gardener........................ 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of chief cook............................ 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of first assistant cook........................ 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of three second assistant cooks................ 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of baker....................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of carpenter........................... 540 540</p>
<p>Salary of assistant carpenter and blacksmith...... 400 400</p>
<pb n="1468" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salaries of two firemen.................... $600 $600</p>
<p>Salaries of seven night watchmen................... 2,100 2,100</p>
<p>Salary of head laundress............................ 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of assistant head laundress.............. 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of six laundresses..................... 1,440 1,440</p>
<p>Salary of head seamstress.................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of six seamstresses...................... 1,440 1,440</p>
<p>Salaries of fifty attendants, or as many thereof as may be necessary, at not to exceed $20 per month, 12,000 12,000</p>
<p>Salaries of two trained nurses.................. 720 720</p>
<p>Salaries of three farm hands, at $15 per month.... 540 540</p>
<p>Salary of dairyman.............................. 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of plasterer and painter................ 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of storekeeper........................ 420 420</p>
<p>Salaries of three dining-room girls and chamber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />maids, at not to exceed $20 per month............... 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of scavenger.......................... 240 240</p>
<p>Groceries, fuel, light and water, including pay of Board of Managers at $5 per month for attend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance upon meetings of the board, and mileage.... 62,500 62,500</p>
<p>Dry goods and clothing.......................... 12,000 12,000</p>
<p>Furniture and beds............................ 1,000 1,000</p>
<p>General repairs....................... 3,000 3,000</p>
<p>Transportation of patients..................... 750 750</p>
<p>Medical stores and surgical instruments.................. 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Literature and amusement...................... 600 600</p>
<p>Contingent expenses...................... 500 500</p>
<p>Cows, horses, mules and hogs...................... 250</p>
<p>Hacks, wagons, harness and farm tools............. 200</p>
<p>Trees, seeds and flowers................. 75 75</p>
<p>Laundry machinery.............................. 300 300</p>
<p>Repairing roofs............................... 1,000 500</p>
<p>Engineers&#8217; and carpenters&#8217; tools................ 150</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Southwestern Insane Asylum.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent......................... $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of assistant superintendent.................. 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper and steward............... 950 950</p>
<p>Salary of engineer and plumber..................... 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of matron and supervisoress............... 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of ward supervisor................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of carpenter...................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of outside supervisor..................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of chief cook............................. 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of baker............................ 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of head laundress.................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of three laundresses....................... 730 730</p>
<p>Salary of gardener.............................. 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of dairyman............................. 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of first assistant cook............................ 300 300</p>
<pb n="1469" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salary of second assistant cook........................ $240 $240</p>
<p>Salary of head seamstress.............................. 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of assistant seamstress....................... 240 240</p>
<p>Salaries of two firemen........................... 600 600</p>
<p>Salaries of two night watchmen....................... 600 600</p>
<p>Salaries of two farm hands, at $15 per month........ 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of twenty-two attendants (or as many there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of as may be necessary), at not to exceed $20 per month........................................ 5,280 5,280</p>
<p>Groceries, fuel, lights and water, including pay of the Board of Managers at $5 per month for at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendance upon meetings of the board, and mile<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age............................................ 25,000 25,000</p>
<p>Dry goods and clothing............................ 3,500 3,500</p>
<p>Furniture and bedding................................. 1,000 1,000</p>
<p>Transportation of patients........................ 400 400</p>
<p>Medical stores and surgical instruments............. 500 750</p>
<p>General repairs and preservation.................... 1,000 1,000</p>
<p>Contingent expenses...................... 300 400</p>
<p>Expenses Board of Managers to Austin................. 15</p>
<p>Literature and amusements........................ 400 400</p>
<p>Trees, seeds, farm machinery and tools................. 200 200</p>
<p>Wagons, hacks and harness...................... 200</p>
<p>Painting roof and standpipe............................ 500</p>
<p>Cows, horses, mules and hogs...................... 200 200</p>
<p>Engineer&#8217;s and carpenter&#8217;s tools...................... 100</p>
<p>Bridges, culverts and grounds.................... 150 150</p>
<p>Anchoring and repairing ward buildings, to be used in two years.................................... 2,000</p>
<p>Erecting additional buildings under the supervision of a competent architect, to be appointed by the Governor of Texas, the salary of architect to be paid out of this appropriation....................... 75,000</p>
<p>Maintenance of inmates to be received in new build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings...................................................... 20,000</p>
<p>Purchasing new boiler and piping and necessary re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pairs for connection and fixtures....................... 1,500</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">North Texas Insane Asylum.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent.............................. $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of first assistant physician.................. 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Salary of second assistant physician 1,250 1,250</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper and steward............... 950 950</p>
<p>Salary of matron............................. 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of apothecary............................. 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of ward supervisor.............................. 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of head farmer and outside supervisor....... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of storekeeper.................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of head engineer and plumber.............. 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of assistant engineer and electrician.......... 480 480</p>
<pb n="1470" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salary of supervisoress........................... $480 $480</p>
<p>Salary of head carpenter........................ 540 540</p>
<p>Salary of assistant carpenter............................ 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of three firemen......................... 900 900</p>
<p>Salary of painter and plasterer..................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of gardener............................ 320 320</p>
<p>Salary of assistant gardener and florist............... 280 280</p>
<p>Salary of scavenger......................... 240 240</p>
<p>Salaries of three farm hands......................... 540 540</p>
<p>Salary of head cook.................................. 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of first assistant cook............................ 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of second assistant cook........................ 240 240</p>
<p>Salary of third assistant cook...................... 240 240</p>
<p>Salary of baker.................................. 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of assistant baker......................... 240 240</p>
<p>Salary of head laundress....................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of eight laundresses........................... 1,920 1,920</p>
<p>Salary of head seamstress........................ 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of seven seamstresses..................... 1,680 1,680</p>
<p>Salaries of sixty-three attendants................. 15,120 15,120</p>
<p>Salaries of four special nurses........................... 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Salary of outside watchman........................ 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of five night watchmen.................. 1,800 1,800</p>
<p>Salary of dairyman...................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of one assistant dairyman....................... 240 240</p>
<p>Groceries, fuel, lights and water........................... 70,000 70,000</p>
<p>Transportation of patients........................... 750 750</p>
<p>Contingent expenses................................ 750 750</p>
<p>Dry goods and clothing................................ 14,500 14,500</p>
<p>Medical stores and surgical instruments.................. 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Trees, seeds and stocks.............................. 250 250</p>
<p>Wagons, hacks and harness............................. 300</p>
<p>Carpenter&#8217;s tools............................ 100</p>
<p>Engineer&#8217;s tools..................................... 50</p>
<p>Mowers, Blows and farm implements................. 250 250</p>
<p>Furniture and beds........................... 1,500 2,000</p>
<p>Expenses Board to Austin........................ 37 50</p>
<p>General repairs and painting roof, to be expended in two years................................ 5,000</p>
<p>Purchase of mules, horses, cows and swine.......... 250 250</p>
<p>Literature and amusement..................... 500 500</p>
<p>Pipes and piping......................... 1,000</p>
<p>Basement floors (tiling or concrete)........................ 2,000</p>
<p>Bridges, culverts and grounds.................. 300</p>
<p>Laundry machinery.............................. 250 250</p>
<p>Repairing standpipe.................................... 100</p>
<p>Fencing........................................ 100 100</p>
<p>Hose for fire department............................ 500</p>
<p>New roof on administration building.............. 1,000</p>
<p>Laundry floor.............................. 500</p>
<p>Grated doors............................... 500</p>
<pb n="1471" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Erection of male hospital............................ $10,000</p>
<p>Erection of an associated dining hall and employes&#8217; room, to be done under the supervision of a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent architect, to be appointed by the Governor of Texas, salary of such architect to be paid out of the appropriation....................... 30,000</p>
<p>Additional appropriations made for North Texas Insane Asylum to comport with provisions made for additional buildings for the accommodation of more inmates:</p>
<p>Groceries, etc..................................... 3,000 $12,000</p>
<p>Dry goods and clothing......................... 750 3,000</p>
<p>Beds and furniture......................... 1,000</p>
<p>Assistant supervisor......................... 90 360</p>
<p>Salaries of five attendants........................... 300 1,200</p>
<p>Salaries of three laundresses............................ 150 600</p>
<p>Provided, that the interest on all securties held by the Lunatic Asylum Fund is hereby appropriated in part payment of the appropriations of the three Lunatic Asylums, the remainder of the appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions to be paid out of the general revenue. All mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />neys now in or which may hereafter be paid into the State Treasury for the board and treatment of nonindigent patients and from sales of personal property of the three lunatic asylums, shall be paid over to the State Treasurer monthly and credited by him to the general revenue account.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Blind Asylum.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent........................... $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of oculist......................... 900 900</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper and steward................ 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of first matron............................ 440 440</p>
<p>Salary of second matron......................... 440 440</p>
<p>Salaries of principal teacher and six assistant teach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers in literary department, teacher of kinderten and physical culture, and four teachers in music department...................................... 8,520 8,520</p>
<p>Salary of one music reader......................... 540 540</p>
<p>Salary of teacher of sewing, crochet and wool work 400 400</p>
<p>Salary of teacher of trades............................ 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of assistant teacher of trades............ 315 315</p>
<p>Salary of sick nurse and monitress for large girls.... 270 270</p>
<p>Salary of sick nurse and monitor for large boys.... 270 270</p>
<p>Salary of monitress and seamstress for small girls.. 180 180</p>
<p>Salary of monitress and seamstress for small boys.. 180 180</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman...................... 500 500</p>
<p>Salary of engineer and electrician............... 900 900</p>
<p>Salary of hostler and yard man................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of four cooks and one baker............... 900 900</p>
<pb n="1472" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salaries of head laundress and three assistants.... 800 800</p>
<p>Salary of housekeeper for large boys&#8217; department.... 180 180</p>
<p>Salaries of three chambermaids................... 472 472</p>
<p>Salaries of four dining-room girls................ 630 630</p>
<p>Salaries of five trustees.......................... 300 300</p>
<p>Transportation of indigent pupils.............. 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Clothing for indigent pupils.................... 900 900</p>
<p>Groceries, provisions, printing necessary for school, labor, contingent expenses and miscellaneous.... 16,500 16,500</p>
<p>Ordinary repairs................................ 750 750</p>
<p>Relaying and casing heating pipes.................. 500</p>
<p>Removing overhead plastering, and ceiling old build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing......................................... 1,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Deaf and Dumb Asylum.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent............................ $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of principal, educational department....... 1,350 1,350</p>
<p>Salary of first academic teacher..................... 950 950</p>
<p>Salaries of two second academic teachers........... 1,700 1,700</p>
<p>Salaries of two teachers....................... 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Salaries of four teachers....................... 2,400 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of five teachers..................... 2,400 2,400</p>
<p>Salary of first oral teacher.................... 720 720</p>
<p>Salary of second oral teacher................... 660 660</p>
<p>Salary of third oral teacher....................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of two oral teachers.......................... 800 800</p>
<p>Salary of art teacher....................... 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of secretary and steward.................... 800 800</p>
<p>Salary of first matron....................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of second matron...................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of monitor........................... 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of monitress for small girls..................... 280 280</p>
<p>Salary of monitress for small boys..................... 280 280</p>
<p>Salary of instructor in printing.................. 800 800</p>
<p>Salary of instructor in shoemaking.................... 660 660</p>
<p>Salary of instructor in carpentry................... 660 660</p>
<p>Salary of instructor in tailoring................ 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of teacher of sewing and dressmaking........</p>
<p>Salary of engineer........................ 800 800</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman........................ 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of farmer and gardner................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salaries of two laborers....................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of five laundresses................... 900 900</p>
<p>Salary of baker.......................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salaries of two cooks........................... 550 550</p>
<p>Supplies, provisions, etc........................... 22,500 22,500</p>
<p>Water and electric lights......................... 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>For furnishing............................. 500 500</p>
<p>Clothing and transportation for indigent pupils.. 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Art material and supplies......................... 100 100</p>
<pb n="1473" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Repairs on main building................... $4,000</p>
<p>Salaries of five trustees............................. 300 $300</p>
<p>Provided, that the interest on all securities held by the Deaf and Dumb and Blind Asylum funds are hereby appropriated in part payment of the above appropriations, the remainder to be paid out of the general revenue.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">House of Correction and Reformatory.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent......................... $1,800 $1,800</p>
<p>Salary of farm supervisor....................... 500 500</p>
<p>Salary of engineer.............................. 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of assistant engineer........................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper and steward..................... 800 800</p>
<p>Salaries of two teachers....................... 960 960</p>
<p>Salaries of four night guards........................ 1,440 1,440</p>
<p>Salaries of ten day guards....................... 3,000 3,000</p>
<p>Salary of baker........................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of physician........................ 400 400</p>
<p>Salary earned by chaplain, one-third year, 1897.... 66</p>
<p>Salaries of three trustees........................ 300 300</p>
<p>Maintenance............................... 16,000 16,000</p>
<p>Fuel................................. 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Books and slates................................ 100 100</p>
<p>Medicine...................................... 200 200</p>
<p>Postage and express............................... 150 150</p>
<p>Discharge and transportation of discharged inmates. 800 800</p>
<p>Literature and library for inmates..................... 150 150</p>
<p>Farm implements............................... 200 200</p>
<p>Bathing pool and contingent expenses................... 500 500</p>
<p>Provided that the products and labor of said re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formatory are hereby appropriated in part payment of the above appropriation, the remainder to be paid out of the general revenue; provided further, that the superintendent of the reformatory is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to rent sufficient land to keep all the inmates employed.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Confederate Home.</head>
<p>For maintenance of inmates, including compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion as prescribed by law to the members of the Board of Directors for attending meetings of the board, and mileage........................ $28,000 $32,000</p>
<p>Salary of superintendent........................ 1,500 1,500</p>
<p>Salary of quartermaster........................... 540 540</p>
<p>Salary of surgeon.......................... 800 800</p>
<p>Medicine................................... 400 400</p>
<p>Salary of chief cook.............................. 480 480</p>
<p>Salary of assistant cook........................... 240 240</p>
<pb n="1474" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Salaries of waiters, who shall do all the work required of them by the sperintendent.............. $720 $720</p>
<p>Salaries of nurses, who shall do all the work required of them by the superintendent and surgeon............ 1,440 1,440</p>
<p>Salary of one helper............................. 240 240</p>
<p>Salary of laundress........................ 240 240</p>
<p>Salary two assistant laundresses................... 360 360</p>
<p>Transfer of inmates to their homes................ 200 200</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman....................... 300 300</p>
<p>For moving stables............................ 100</p>
<p>For fire hose............................. 335</p>
<p>Dining-room and kitchen for hospital, and for neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary furniture therefor........................... 1,500</p>
<p>Kitchen for main building......................... 900</p>
<p>Salary of hospital cook......................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of assistant hospital cook................. 240 240</p>
<p>Salary of matron......................... 300 300</p>
<p>Building and furnishing one cottage, to be used when needed........................... 2.250</p>
<p>Laundry appliances............................. 300</p>
<p>Provided, that the money now to the credit of the available Confederate Home fund is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated in part payment of the above appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, the remainder to be paid out of general revenue.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Quarantine Department.</head>
<p>For maintaining quarantine department................... $33,000 $33,000</p>
<p>For moving quarantine station at Sabine Pass....... 3,000</p>
<p>Maintenance, of a quarantine guard at Corpus Christi Pass, to be under the supervision of the quarantine physician at Harbor Island, said guard to furnish his own boat and supplies, at a salary of $75 per month, for eight months each year.................... 600 600</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Deaf, Dumb and Blind Asylum for Colored Youths.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent..................... $1,500 $1,500</p>
<p>Salary of principal teacher.................. 675 675</p>
<p>Salaries of three class room teachers and one music teacher......................... 1,800 1,800</p>
<p>Salary of shoemaker............................ 450 450</p>
<p>Salary of seamstress............................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of matron.................................... 360 360</p>
<p>Salary of oculist............................ 600 600</p>
<p>Salary of night watchman.......................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of engineer and plumber................ 500 500</p>
<p>Salary of cook and assistant................. 500 500</p>
<p>Salary of farmer and gardner...................... 240 240</p>
<p>School apparatus................................ 125 125</p>
<p>Transportation of indigent pupils.............. 400 400</p>
<pb n="1475" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Clothing for indigent pupils...................... $450 $450</p>
<p>General repairs and erection of new building, to be done under the supervision of a competent archi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tect, to be appointed by the Governor or Texas; salary of such architect to be paid out of this ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation.................................... 12,000</p>
<p>Furniture.................................. 200 200</p>
<p>Tools and apparatus for shoe shop................ 25 25</p>
<p>Stationery and postage.......................... 50 50</p>
<p>Salary of monitor....................................</p>
<p>For groceries, provisions and miscellaneous, includ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing pay of members of the board at $5 per month for attending meetings of the board, and mileage, 8,000 8,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Sam Houston Normal Institute.</head>
<p>For support and maintenance....................... $37,500 $37,500</p>
<p>For library apparatus, repairs and improvements.... 2,000 2,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">State Penitentiaries.</head>
<p>For conveying convicts to the penitentiaries and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formatory............................... $18,000 $18,000</p>
<p>Penitentiary library......................... 250 250</p>
<p>Traveling expenses of superintendent............... 500 500</p>
<p>All the proceeds of convict labor, and in addition thereto for making up deficiences in monthly ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses and to purchase material to carry on prison industries, which shall be paid out of the treasury on the warrant of the Comptroller, whenever de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manded by the financial agent of the State peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiaries, to be used, if needed, for each year; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that this sum shall not be drawn out of the treasury except as needed........................ 40,000 40,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Agricultural and Mechanical College.</head>
<p>For the support and maintenance of the Agricul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tural and Mechanical College, out of the general revenue $19,500, and out of the available univer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity fund, each year, $500....................... $20,000 $20,000</p>
<p>Student labor fund.......................... 5,000 5,000</p>
<p>For experimental station............................. 2,500 2,500</p>
<p>Building and equipping mess hall................. 25,000</p>
<p>Repairs on buildings, to be expended in two years.... 5,000</p>
<p>Building two residences for professors.......... 3,000</p>
<p>In addition to the above, the interest on $209,000 of state bonds held by the Agricultural and Mechan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ical College fund is hereby further appropriated for the support of this institution; provided, that the board of directors of the Agricultural and Mechan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ical College of Texas shall include in their reports<pb n="1476" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>the number and salaries of the faculty and employes of the Agricultural and Mechanical College and of the Prairie View Formal School, and the receipts and expenditures, itemized, of each of these institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, in the same manner as the law requires the board of regents to report the salaries and number of the faculty and employes, and the receipts and expenditures of the University of Texas.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Prairie View State Normal School.</head>
<p>For the maintenance of forty-six students........... $10,000 $10,000</p>
<p>For the maintenance and support of the agricul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tural and mechanical department. 2,500 2,500</p>
<p>For the maintenance and support of the girls&#8217; indus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trial department............................... 350 350</p>
<p>Books and stationery.......................... 100</p>
<p>Erection of one barn.................................. 1,000</p>
<p>Water supply, wells and tanks........................... 1,500</p>
<p>Repairing and painting houses...................... 250 250</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Adjutant General&#8217;s Office.</head>
<p>Salary of Adjutant General......................... $2,000 $2,000</p>
<p>Salary of chief clerk.................................. 1,100 1,100</p>
<p>Salary of porter.................................... 300 300</p>
<p>Salary of custodian of Camp Mabry................... 180 180</p>
<p>Stationery, postage and telegraphing........................ 400 400</p>
<p>Incidental expenses.................................. 25 25</p>
<p>Handling of ordnance and quartermaster stores and clothing, labor in arsenal, and repairs of arms.. 250 250</p>
<p>Inspection of arms and troops.................... 250 250</p>
<p>Protection of the frontier, and suppression of law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lessness and crime...................... 25,000 25,000</p>
<p>Payment of the Volunteer Guard when called into active service under the law, including transporta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of troops, and for all other military expenses 5,000 5,000</p>
<p>Book cases for preservation of war records and maps. 100</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Public Printing.</head>
<p>For first, second and third classes of printing and binding, and for printing papers for first and sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond classes of public printing................. $20,000 $20,000</p>
<p>For publishing supreme court reports, three vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />umes............................................. 4,000 2,000</p>
<p>For publishing Court of Criminal Appeals reports, three volumes..................................... 4,000 2,000</p>
<p>Publishing Court of Civil Appeals reports, sis vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />umes.................................... 6,000 6,000</p>
<p>For salary of expert printer and secretary for the State Printing Board, who shall perform such<pb n="1477" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>other duties as the Board may require of him.... $1,500 $1,500</p>
<p>For publishing Constitutional Amendments, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed by the Twenty-fifth Legislature, or so much thereof as may be necessary.................... 17,000</p>
<p>(For printing for educational department, as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, the distribution to be made by the department of education:)</p>
<p>Printing and distributing county superintendent&#8217;s record books, treasurers&#8217; record books and blank forms........................................... 1,100 1,100</p>
<p>Printing and distributing scholastic census blanks, teachers&#8217; daily registers, trustees&#8217; reports and other blank forms for the use of school officers, teachers and trustees................................... 1,750 1,750</p>
<p>Printing and distributing school laws, courses of study, examination questions, circulars to school officers and teachers, and other matter for the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vancement of education........................... 875 500</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Live Stock Sanitary Commission.</head>
<p>For expenses of Live Stock Sanitary Commission... $4,000 $4,000</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Public Buildings and Grounds.</head>
<p>Salary of superintendent............................. $1,500 $1,500</p>
<p>Salary of bookkeeper....................................... 550 550</p>
<p>Salary of engineer................................ 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>Salary of assistant engineer, who shall perform all work required of him by the superintendent...... 720 720</p>
<p>Salaries of four watchmen........................ 2,640 2,640</p>
<p>Salaries of two firemen............................ 1,200 1,200</p>
<p>For traveling and other necessary expenses of Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent when away from Austin on official business......................................... 200 200</p>
<p>Salaries of four cleaners........................... 1,440 1,440</p>
<p>Salary of elevator man............................. 720 720</p>
<p>Labor in capitol grounds and keeping sewer in re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pair.................................... 700 700</p>
<p>Keeping cemetery grounds.................................... 300 300</p>
<p>Headstones for Confederate veterans buried in the State cemetery.................................... 300 300</p>
<p>Headstones for Texas veterans buried in the State cemetery...................................... 100 100</p>
<p>Water, fuel, lights and contingencies......................... 9,000 9,000</p>
<p>Oil and waste for engines, dynamos and steam pumps, oil for wainscoting, drawing paper for plans, stationery, and oil for lamps.................. 600 600</p>
<p>Repairs and painting for two years..................... 2,500 2,500</p>
<p>Tools........................................ 100 100</p>
<p>For the purchase of one painting of ex Governor Hogg, painted by Mr. McArdle.................. 250</p>
<pb n="1478" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be unlawful for the superintendent or head of any of the foregoing departments of the State government or public institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions herein provided for to draw out of the State treasury all or any part of the money for the maintenance of his respective department or insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution and deposit the same in a local bank to his own private account; but said amounts herein before appropriated shall remain in the State treasury, and may be drawn or checked out by such heads of depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments or superintendents of institutions monthly to pay salaries of em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployees, or whenever it may be needed to pay for supplies, repairs, im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements or any other thing permitted to be bought or had for the maintenance of such institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that the monthly expenses of the State government are due and it is important that the same be promptly paid creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and the same is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 18, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 18.] CHAPTEB 11.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 5051 of the Revised Civil Statutes of 1895, relating to county warrants and the payment of taxes and to repeal all laws in conflict herewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 5051 shall hereafter read as follows :</p>
<p>Article 5051. The taxes herein levied by this chapter are hereby made payable in the currency or coin of the United States; provided, that persons holding scrip issued to themselves for services rendered the county may pay their county ad valorem taxes in such scrip.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith are hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that but a few clays of the special session remain for the consideration of bills, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several clays be suspended, and that this bill be put on its third reading and final passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 19, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1479" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 14.] CHAPTER 12.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Sections 1069 and 1070 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, and to reduce the expenses of the State government.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Articles 1069 and 1070 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 1069. Whenever any case or cases, civil or criminal, are pend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in which the district judge is disqualified from trying the same, no change of venue shall be made necessary thereby; but the judge presiding shall immediately notify that fact to the Governor, whereupon the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor shall designate some district judge in an adjoining district to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />change and try such case or cases, and the Governor shall also notify both of said judges of such order, and it shall be the duty of said judges to exchange districts for the purpose of disposing of such case or cases, and in case of sickness or other reasons rendering it impossible to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />change, then the parties or their counsel shall have the right to select or agree upon an attorney of the court for the trial thereof.</p>
<p>Article 1070. Whenever a special judge is agreed upon by the parties for the trial of any particular cause, as above provided, the clerk shall enter in the minutes of the court, as a part of the proceedings in such cause, a record showing:</p>
<p>1. That the judge of the court was disqualified to try the cause; and</p>
<p>2. That such, special judge (naming him) was by consent agreed upon by the parties to try the cause; and</p>
<p>3. That the oath prescribed by law has been duly administered to such special judge.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that under the present law there is a heavy annual expense entailed upon the State for the payment of special judges which could be avoided by the regular district judges exchanging districts, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity requiring that the constitutional rule requiring all bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 19, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the senate, vote not given; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1480" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 30.] CHAPTER 13.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to fix the venue and regulate proceedings in prosecutions for murder by mob violence; define and punish murder by mob violence; provide for the sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pension and removal of sheriffs, deputy sheriffs, constables, chiefs of police, city marshals and other officers who permit it; and fix the venue and regulate proceedings in such cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That whenever two or more persons shall combine together for the purpose of mob violence, and in pursuance of said combination shall unlawfully and wilfully take the life of any reasonable creature in being by such vio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lence, such person shall be deemed guilty of murder by mob violence, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by death or confinement in the penitentiary for life, or according to the degree of murder, to be found by the jury; provided, nothing in this section shall be so construed as to in any way affect the law in regard to manslaughter, as defined in Chap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter 14, Title 15, of the Penal Code of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the district judges of the State to give this law specially in charge to the grand jury at the beginning of each term of court. Prosecutions for murder under this act may be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced and carried on in any county of the judicial district in which the offense is committed, except the county of the offense, or in any county of the judicial district the judge of which resides nearest the county seat of the county in which the offense is committed. When the judicial district comprises only one county, prosecutions may be commenced and carried on in any adjoining county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. If any sheriff, deputy sheriff, constable, chief of police, city marshal or other officer in this State shall permit or suffer any person in his custody charged with crime to be killed by one or more persons, or shall permit or suffer any such person to be taken from his custody and killed by one or more persons, he shall be deemed guilty of official mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />conduct, and removed from office; and the custody of a deputy shall be the custody of his principal. Proceedings to remove such officer from office may be commenced and carried on in any county named in Section 2 of this act. Said proceedings for the removal of said officers shall be conducted by the attorney general or under his direction in the name of the State of Texas, and shall be commenced by filing in the district court of the proper county a petition which shall be addressed to the judge of the court in which it is filed, and shall set forth in plain and intelligible language the facts as grounds of removal.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. After the filing of such petition, citation to the defendant shall issue as now provided by law in other civil cases. The trial and all the proceedings connected therewith shall be conducted as far as it is practicable in accordance with the rules and practices of the court in other civil cases; and appeals and writs of error may be sued out by either party to all appellate courts, as in other civil cases; provided, such cases shall take precedence in all courts of all other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The petition provided for in Section 3 shall be filed by the attorney general, or under his direction, as soon as practicable after he shall be informed of the facts, and within ten days after the same shall have been filed he shall make application to the district judge to whom it is addressed to [have] the officer against whom it is filed suspended tem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1481" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>porarily from office. Five days&#8217; notice of this application shall be given to the defendant, and, upon the hearing of such application, if it shall appear that the defendant permitted any person in his custody charged with crime to be killed by one or more persons, or permit or suffer any such person to be taken from his custody and killed by one or more per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, the judge shall forthwith suspend the defendant temporarily from office and appoint for the time being some other person to discharge the duties of the office, which person shall, before assuming the duties of the office, execute a bond in such sum as the judge may name, with at least two good and sufficient sureties, on such conditions as the judge may impose, to pay the defendant all damages and costs that he may sustain by reason of such suspension from office in case in should appear that the cause of removal is insufficient or untrue.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. In the trial of the case, the judge shall not submit special issues, but shall, under a proper charge applicable to the facts of the case, instruct the jury to find from the evidence whether the cause of the removal set forth in the petition is true in point of fact. Should the jury find that said cause of removal is true, judgment of ouster shall be entered against the defendant, and he shall not thereafter be elected or appointed to said office.</p>
<p>Sec. 7 All laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The fact that there is no adequate law in this State for the suppression of mob violence, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring all bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 19. 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the House; passed the Senate with amendments; and the House concurred in Senate amendments. Vote not given in either house.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 31.] CHAPTER 14.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the Thirty-eighth Judicial District and prescribe the times of holding District Courts in the various counties thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That an act of the Twenty-fourth Legislature of the State of Texas, approved April 16, 1895, entitled an act to amend Section 1, Chapter 29, of an act passed at the regular session of the Twenty-third Legislature of the State of Texas, approved March 15, 1893, entitled an act to amend Section 38, Chapter 141, of an act passed at the regular session of the Twenty-first Legislature of the State of Texas, approved March 30, 1889, entitled an act to amend Chapter 61, an act entitled an act to amend Section 38 of an act entitled an act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding courts therein, and to provide for the election of judges and district attorneys in such districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November, 1894, approved April 9, 1893, granting an extension of time for the holding of<pb n="1482" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>the District Court of Comal comity, extending the time for the holding of the District Court of Kerr county, be amended so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 38. The Thirty-eighth judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Bandera, Kendall, Kerr, Medina and Uvalde, and the district courts shall be held as follows:</p>
<p>In the county of Bandera, on the first Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Kendall, on the second Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Kerr, on the fourth Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, any may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Medina, on the seventh Monday after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Uvalde, on the eleventh Monday after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the end of the session, and the fact that one county has been taken out of the Thirty-eighth district, thereby causing a hiatus in the scheme for holding the district courts in said district, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding the suspension of the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in both houses, and said rule is hereby suspended, and it is further enacted that this act shall be in force and shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 21, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the House by a two-thirds vote, yeas 91, nays 1; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 23, nays none.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 22] CHAPTER 15.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to fix the fees of county and district clerks for recording returns, and to amend Section 10, of Substitute House bill for House bills Nos. 6 and 19, passed at the first special session of the 25th Legislature of the State of Texas, being a bill entitled, &#8220;An Act to fix certain civil fees to be charged by certain county and precinct officers, and to fix and limit the fees and compensation of clerks of the district court, district attorneys, county attorneys, sheriffs and constables in felony cases, to be paid by the State, and to fix the compensation of assessors and collectors of taxes, and to limit and regulate the compensation of the sheriff, clerk of the county court, county judge, district and county attorney, clerk of the district court, assessor and collector of taxes, justices of the peace and constables, and to prescribe penalties for the violation of this act, and to repeal all laws in conflict herewith,&#8221; relating to the excess of the fees collected by certain county officers over the maximum allowed them.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That hereafter Section 10, of the substitute House bill for House bills Nos. 6 and 19, passed at the first special session of the 25th Legislature of the State of Texas, being a bill entitled &#8220;An act to fix certain civil fees to be<pb n="1483" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>charged by certain county and precinct officers, and to fix and limit the fees and compensation of clerks of the district court, district attorneys, county attorneys, sheriffs and constables in felony cases, to be paid by the State, and to fix the compensation of assessors and collectors of taxes, and to limit and regulate the compensation of the sheriff, clerk of the county court, county judge, district and county attorneys, clerk of the district court, assessor and collector of taxes, justices of the peace and constables, and to prescribe penalties for the violation of this act, and to repeal all laws in conflict herewith,&#8221; shall be amended so as hereafter to read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 10. That hereafter the maximum amount of fees of all kinds that may be retained by any officer mentioned in this section as compensation for services shall be as follows: County judge, an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; clerk of the county court, an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; county attorney, an amount not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding $2000 per annum; district attorney, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum, inclusive of the $500 allowed by the Constitution and paid by the State; clerk of the district court, an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; collector of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; assessor of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2000 per annum; justices of the peace, an amount not exceeding $1500 per annum; constables, an amount not exceeding $1200 per annum; and in addition thereto one-fourth of the excess of fees collected by the said officers, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectively; provided, that this act shall not apply to justices of the peace and constables, except those holding office in cities of more than 15,000 in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants, to be determined by the next preceding city election on the basis of five inhabitants for each vote cast at such election; provided, that up to 1902, in counties in which there were cast at the last presidential election as many as 5000 votes, and thereafter any counties shown by the national census of 1900 to contain as many as 25,000 [inhabitants], the following amounts shall be allowed, viz.: County judge, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; clerk of the county court, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; county attorney, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; district attorney, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum, inclusive of the $500 allowed by the Constitution and paid by the State; clerk of the district court, an amount not exceeding $2250 per an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />num; collector of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum; assessor of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2250 per annum, and in ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition thereto one-fourth of the excess of the fees collected by the said officers, respectively; provided, further, that in counties containing a city of over 25,000 inhabitants, or in which there were cast at the last presiden<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tial election as many as 7500 votes, or by the census of 1900shall contain as many as 37,500 inhabitants, the following amounts of fees shall be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed, viz: County judge, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; clerk of the county court, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; county attorney, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; district attorney, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum, inclusive of the $500 allowed by the Constitution and paid by the State; clerk of the district court, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; collector of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2500 per annum; assessor of taxes, an amount not exceeding $2500 per an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />num; in addition thereto one-fourth of the excess of the<pb n="1484" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>fees collected by the officers, respectively; provided, that the county attorney in those counties having no district attorney, where he per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forms the duties of district attorney, may receive the same compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation as provided for the district attorney; provided the maxi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mum fixed for the compensation of the district attorney shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued to be the amount which that officer, is authorized to retain of fees allowed such officers in his district, whether composed of one or more counties; provided, that in counties where a county judge acts as su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent of public instruction, he shall receive such other salary as may be provided by the commissioners&#8217; court, not to exceed the sum of $600 per annum. The last United States census shall govern as to the population of the cities.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the clerks of the district court shall hereafter receive the following fees for the following services: For recording return of any writs when any such return is required by law to be recorded, the amount of 50 cents; when the return exceeds 300 words, for each 100 words in excess of 300 words, ten cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the clerks of the county court shall hereafter receive for the following services the following fees: For recording return of any writ, when any such return is required by law to be recorded, 50 cents; where the return exceeds 300 words, for each 100 words in excess of 300 words, 10 cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed, it not being intended to affect any fees as prescribed by other laws, except where thy conflict with this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The near approach of the end of this special session, and the importance of correcting errors and omissions existing in the law, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this bill be put upon its third reading and final passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 19, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate by a vote of yeas 20, nays 4, and passed the House by a vote of yeas 79, nays 14.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 2C.] CHAPTER 16.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 3964 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, adopted A. D. 1895, providing for the manner of taking the scholastic census, and repealing Articles 3965, 3966, 3967, 3968, 3969, 3970 and 3971 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas : That Article 3964, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, be so amended that it shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>The scholastic census of each school district of this State shall be taken in the year 1898, and every year thereafter.</p>
<p>The county superintendent of public instruction shall, on the first day of January of each year, or as soon as practical thereafter, appoint one of the trustees of each school district, or some other qualified person, to take said census, who shall be known as the census trustee of the district.</p>
<pb n="1485" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>It shall be the duty of the census trustee to take, between the first day of May and the first day of June after his appointment, a census of all the children that will be over eight and under seventeen years of age on the first day of the following September, and who are residents of the school district on said first day of May, and to make report under oath to the county superintendent on or before the first day of June next thereafter. In taking the said census he shall visit each home, residence, habitation and place of abode, and shall, by actual observation and inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rogation, enumerate the children thereof in the following manner: He shall use for each parent, guardian or person having control of any such children a prescribed form showing the name, color and nationality of the person rendering such children, the name and number of the school district in which the children reside, and the name, sex, and date of birth of each child of which he is the parent or guardian, or of which he has control, and which child will be over eight and under seventeen years of age on the first day of September next following. The census trustee shall require such form to be subscribed and sworn to by the person ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dering the children, and he is hereby authorized to administer oaths for this purpose.</p>
<p>When the census trustee or assessor visits any home or house or place of abode of a family and fails to find either the parent or any person having legal control, it shall be the duty of the census trustee to leave the prescribed census blanks for the use of parents at such home or place of abode, with a note to the parent or guardian having legal control of child or children, requiring that the form be filled out, sworn and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed to before the census trustee, or an officer authorized to adminis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter oaths, and that the blank, when so filled out, shall be delivered by the parent or person having legal control of the child or children to the census trustee.</p>
<p>Every person having control of any child which will be over eight and under seventeen years of age on the first day of September next there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after, and who, being requested by the census trustee to prepare said form giving the information required, or to give the information neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to enable the trustee to prepare the same, shall refuse to do so, or shall refuse to make oath to said form when filled according to his state<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of facts in regard to said children, or shall fail to return the form left at his home in his absence, as above required, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be fined not less than five nor more than ten dollars. And it shall be the duty of the census trustee at once to file with some justice of the peace of competent jurisdiction complaint against such person. Only children of the same family shall be listed on one form, and if one person has under his control children of different family name, he should use a separate form for each family name.</p>
<p>The census trustee shall arrange the forms for white and colored chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren separately in alphabetical order, according to the family name of the children reported thereon. He shall also make, on a prescribed form, separate census rolls for the white and colored children of his district, showing the name, age, sex and color of each child, and the name of the parent, guardian or person having control of said children by whom it is reported. He shall also make a summary of his rolls showing the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of children of each race that will be of the different ages from eight<pb n="1486" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>to sixteen, inclusive, on the first day of the next September, which shall continue to be the scholastic age, as is now provided by law. He shall make oath to his rolls and summaries, and to the faithful and accurate discharge of his duties, deliver the rolls, together with the forms ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ranged in alphabetical order, to the county superintendent on or before June 1st next after his appointment.</p>
<p>Any census trustee who shall wilfully fail or refuse to obtain the neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary information in regard to any child which will be over eight and under seventeen years of age on the first day of September next thereafter, or who shall wilfully fail or refuse to include any child within said ages in his rolls, or shall wilfully make any false report, roll or summary, shall be guilty of false swearing, and shall be punished as prescribed by law for that offense. And if the county superintendent finds or believes that any census trustee has violated any duty required under this act, such county superintendent shall report said census trustee to the grand jury of the county at its next session after discovering such breach of duty. The rolls and summaries of the census trustee shall be preserved by the county superintendent in his office for three years after they are filed. The county superintendent shall make on prescribed form separate con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />solidated rolls for the white and colored children of his county, showing the name, age and sex of each, together with the number of the district in which it lives, and the name of the parent or guardian, arranging the names of the children according to the alphabetical order of their family names. In making these consolidated rolls, he shall scrutinize carefully the work of the census trustees, and shall have power to summon wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses, take affidavits, and correct any errors he may find in any census trustee&#8217;s roll, and he shall carefully exclude all duplicates. If he deems it necessary, he may reject any roll, and appoint another census trustee, to take the census of the district, in which case he shall not approve the warrant to pay the census trustee, whose work has been rejected, for his services. When the county superintendent has prepared his consolidated census roll, one for each race, he shall make a duplicate of each, and he shall make affidavit to the correctness of both originals and duplicates. The originals he shall, on or before July 1st, forward to the State super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendent of public instruction at Austin, and the duplicates shall be filed with the county clerk and become permanent records of his office. The county superintendent shall forward with his consolidated rolls an abstract on the prescribed form, under oath, showing the number of children of each race, of the different years of the school age and the total number of children of each race, and the total of both races in his county. In making his consolidated rolls and in investigating the work of any census trustee, the county superintendent shall refer to the forms and rolls of previous years, when necessary, and they shall be carefully pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served for this purpose.</p>
<p>The State superintendent shall have authority to investigate the cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sus of any county, to correct errors, and in extreme cases when he be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lieves gross errors have occurred, or that fraud has been pacticed, he may, with the approval of the state board of education, reject any coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty&#8217;s roll and require the census of the county to be retaken.</p>
<p>For their services, the census trustee shall receive four cents per cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ita of the children of scholastic age taken by him in country districts and three cents per capita in towns of 2500 inhabitants and upwards to 5000<pb n="1487" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>inhabitants, and two cents per capita in cities of more than 5000 in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants, and the county superintendent shall receive one cent per capita of the scholastic population reported by him, but these amounts shall not be paid until the census of the county is accepted by the State superintendent, and shall be forfeited as follows: The trustee&#8217;s compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation, if his work is rejected by the county superintendent, and the cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sus of his district ordered retaken, and both the county superintendent&#8217;s and the trustee&#8217;s compensation, if the census of the county is rejected and ordered by the State superintendent and the State board of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to be retaken.</p>
<p>The provisions of this act shall apply to the taking of the census of community counties, except that in such counties the assessor of taxes shall take the scholastic census of all the county except such portion thereof as may be organized into school districts and independent dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts, and in his forms for parents and rolls, he shall show the justice precincts in which each child resides, instead of the school district as herein provided for district counties, and he may begin the work of tak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the census at any time after the first day of January, instead of May, as herein provided, and the children shall be enrolled where they reside on the first day of January. The assessor shall have the same powers, shall perform the same duties, and shall be subject to the same penalties for any neglect, failure or breach of duty as are provided for census trustees of the districts.</p>
<p>The provisions of this act shall govern the taking of the scholastic census in cities and towns constituting independent districts, except as, specially provided herein below, to-wit: The census trustee shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed by the president of the board of trustees, or by the mayor in an independent district having no board of trustees, and a census trustee may be appointed for each ward or school subdistrict, at the discretion of the president of the school board or the mayor making such appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment. The forms for the parent and the rolls shall show the street and house number, or location of the house or place in which each child resides.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed, and Articles 3965, 3966, 3967, 3968, 3969, 3970 and 3971, of the Revised Civil Statutes of 1895, are specially repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The crowded condition of the calendar and the near approach of the close of this session of the legislature, and the fact that the law is deficient in regard to enumerating the scholastic census, create an emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency requiring the supension of the constitutional rule that all bills to be read on three several days, and that this bill be placed on its third reading and final passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 23, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate, vote not given; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
<pb n="1488" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 23.] CHAPTER 17.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate and limit the expenditure of State, county and local public school funds, and regulate treasurers&#8217; reports thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That public school funds hereafter shall not be expended except for the following purposes:</p>
<p>1. That State available school funds shall be used exclusively for the payment of teachers&#8217; and supierintendents&#8217; salaries and fees for taking the scholastic census.</p>
<p>2. The county available school funds shall be used exclusively for the payment of teachers&#8217; and superintendents&#8217; salaries and for the payment of fees for taking the scholastic census.</p>
<p>3. Local school funds from district taxes, tuition fees of pupils not entitled to free tuition, and other local sources may be used for the purposes enumerated for State and county funds and for purchasing ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pliances and supplies, for the payment of insurance premiums, janitors and other employes, for buying school sites, buying, building, repairing and renting school houses, and for other purposes necessary in the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duct of the public schools, to be determined by the board of trustees, the account and vouchers for county districts and communities to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the county superintendent; provided, that when the State avail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able school fund in any city or county is sufficient to maintain the schools thereof in any year for at least eight months, and leave a surplus, such surplus may be expended for the purposes mentioned herein.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All treasurers receiving or having control of any school funds, shall keep a full and separate itemized account with each of the different classes of school funds coming into his hands, and shall, on or before the first day of October of each year, file with the State Superintendent of Public Instruction an itemized report in duplicate of the receipts and disbursements of the school funds for the preceding school year ending August 31st, which report and duplicate shall be on the prescribed form furnished by the department of education, and the duplicate report, after examination by the State superintendent, shall be returned to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners&#8217; court of the proper county for approval, and shall be accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panied by such objections or recommendations as the State superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent may make in regard to the same. The State superintendent, in examining any report, may call for the vouchers and make such investi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation of the correctness and legality of the different items as he may deem necessary, and when the duplicate is sent to the commissioners&#8217; court, all vouchers shall be presented to the court, and the present law in regard to treasurers&#8217; reports, except as hereinbefore modified, is hereby continued.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All laws, general and special, in conflict with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the close of the special session, and the importance of providing some adequate method by which the public schools of the State may be supplied with the necessities for their proper conduct, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity, that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be<pb n="1489" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>June 23, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the Senate, vote not given; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 24.] CHAPTER 18.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 5049 of Chapter 1, Title 104, of the Revised Statutes, relating to general occupation taxes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 5049, of Chapter 1, Title 104, of the Revised Civil Statutes of 1895, shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 5049. There shall be levied on and collected from every per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, firm, company or association of persons pursuing any of the occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pations named in the following numbered subdivisions of this article, an annual occupation tax, which shall be paid annually in advance, except when herein otherwise provided, on every such occupation or separate establishment, as follows:</p>
<p>Subdivision 1. From every merchant whose annual purchases amount to less than two thousand dollars, three dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to two thousand dollars or less than five thousand dollars, six dollars; from every merchant whose annual pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chases amount to five thousand dollars or less than ten thousand dollars, twelve dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to ten thousand dollars or less than fifteen thousand dollars, twenty dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to fifteen thousand dollars or less than twenty-five thousand dollars, twenty-five dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to twenty-five thousand dollars or less than fifty thousand dollars, sixty dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to fifty thousand dollars or less than one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, one hundred and twenty-five dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to one hundred and fifty thousand dollars or less than two hundred and fifty thousand dollars, one hundred and fifty dollars; from every mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chant whose annual purchases amount to two hundred and fifty thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars or less than five hundred thousand dollars, two hundred dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to five hundred thousand dollars or less than seven hundred and fifty thousand dollars, two hundred and fifty dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to seven hundred and fifty thousand dollars or more, three hundred dollars. Every person, firm, corporation or association of persons desiring to sell goods, wares or merchandise within this State shall, before pursuing such occupation, pay the tax for one year and take out a license to pursue the occupation of the merchant of the class to which he properly belongs, according to his annual purchases, as provided by law, and shall file with the tax collector an affidavit of the amount of his annual purchases for the past year, if previously engaged in such<pb n="1490" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>business, or a part of a year, if engaged in such business less than a year, and also of the estimated amount of his annual purchases for the ensuing year. Said affidavit shall be filed and preserved by the tax collector as a part of the records of his office, and shall be in substance as follows, viz:</p>
<p>&#8220;The undersigned, as the representative of.........., doing business at............, Texas, do solemnly swear that the estimate made of the annual purchases of said concern of goods, wares and merchandise for the next ensuing year does not exceed.............. thousand dollars. I further swear that the annual purchases of said concern for the past...... months did not exceed the sum of........ thousand dollars.&#8221;</p>
<p>Said affidavit shall be signed and sworn to before some officer author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to administer oaths, and for this purpose the tax collector of coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, cities and towns are hereby authorized to administer oaths.</p>
<p>Sub. 2. From every merchant who may remove from place to place and offer for sale &#8220;bankrupt stocks&#8221; of goods, or advertising &#8220;fire sales,&#8221; or &#8220;water and fire damaged stocks for sale,&#8221; for a limited period of time, there shall be collected one hundred dollars per month for the first month, or less than a month, for each and every place where such busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is located; and for each additional month that such sales are con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued, at any given place, said merchant shall pay an additional sum of twenty dollars; provided, that where they remain for six months in one place, in addition to the one hundred dollars charged for the first month, they shall pay an additional sum of ten dollars per month; and provided further, that if they remain in one place for the period of twelve months, they shall be required to pay, in addition to the one hundred dollars for the first month, the sum fixed in the preceding paragraph, according to class and amount of goods sold in one year.</p>
<p>Sub. 3. From every traveling person selling patent or other medicines, one hundred dollars; and no traveling person shall so sell until said tax is paid; provided, that this tax shall not apply to commercial travelers, drummers or salesmen making sales, or soliciting trade for merchants engaged in the sale of drugs or medicines by wholesale.</p>
<p>Sub. 4. From every fortune teller, ten dollars; from every clairvoyant or mesmerist, who plies his or her vocation for money, ten dollars for each and every county in which such vocation is carried on.</p>
<p>Sub. 5. From every person, firm or association of persons engaged in discounting or shaving paper, or engaged in business as money brokers or bankers, or dealers in stocks, securities or bills of exchange, or in buy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or selling bonds, State, county or city warrants, or other claims against the State, an annual tax of fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 6. From every operator or owner of any daguerrean, photograph, or other like gallery, by whatever name called, an annual tax of ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 7. From every auctioneer, an annual tax of ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 8. From every keeper of a toll bridge, an annual tax of seven dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 9. From every person, firm or association of persons following the occupation of ship brokers or ship agents, an annual tax of ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 10. From every person, firm or association of persons selling on commission, ten dollars.</p>
<pb n="1491" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sub. 11. From every land agent there shall be collected an annual tax of five dollars. The term &#8220;land agent&#8221; shall be construed to mean any person, firm or association of persons performing for compensation any of the following services; purchasing or selling real estate for others; purchasing or selling land certificates for others. But this term &#8220;land agent&#8221; shall not be construed so as to levy a tax upon an attorney in ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition to the one hereinafter levied.</p>
<p>Sub. 12. From every person practicing law, and from every convey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ancer or other person drawing deeds or other legal instruments for pay, five dollars; provided, that attorneys-at-law shall only pay county occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation tax in the county of his or their residence.</p>
<p>Sub. 13. From every physician, surgeon, oculist or medical or other specialist of any kind, traveling from place to place in the practice of his profession, an annual tax of fifty dollars; from every dentist, five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 14. From every local practicing physician, surgeon, veterinary surgeon, or any medical or surgical specialist, an annual tax of $5.</p>
<p>Sub. 15. From every person or firm keeping a shooting gallery at which a fee is paid or demanded, an annual tax of thirty dollars in each county.</p>
<p>Sub. 16. From every person or firm keeping a knife, cane or doll rack, or any other device upon which rings are pitched, or at which balls are thrown, an annual tax of twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 17. From every billiard, pool table, or anything of the kind used for profit, twenty dollars; and any such table used in connection with any drinking saloon or other place of business where intoxicating liquors, cigars or other things of value are sold or given away, or upon which any money or other thing of value is paid, shall be regarded as used for profit.</p>
<p>Sub. 18. From any person or persons who shall sell pools on horse races or other contests, five dollars for each and every day they may so sell said pools.</p>
<p>Sub. 19. From every nine or ten pin alley or any other alley used for profit, by whatever name called, constructed or operated upon the prin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciple of a bowling alley, and upon which balls, rings or other devices are used as substitutes thereof are rolled, without regard to the number of pins used, or whether pins are used or not, or whether the balls, rings or other device are rolled by hand or with a cue or any other device, one hundred dollars. Any such alley used in connection with any drinking saloon, or any drug store, or with any drug store where intoxicating liquors are sold, or given away, or upon which money or anything of value is paid, shall be regarded as used for profit.</p>
<p>Sub. 20. From all persons keeping or using for profit any hobby horse, flying-jenny, or device of that character, with or without name, fifteen dollars for each county wherein the same are kept or used.</p>
<p>Sub. 21. From every foot peddler, five dollars in each county in which he peddles. For every peddler with one horse or one pair of oxen, the sum of fifteen dollars in each county where he peddles; for every peddler with two horses or two pair of oxen, thirty dollars in each county in which he may pursue such occupation; for every peddler with sail or other boat in streams or along the coast of bays of this State, thirty dollars in each county in which he may pursue such occupation; provided, that any blind, deaf and dumb, or any wounded person who has lost a hand or foot<pb n="1492" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>shall not be required to pay any tax for peddling; provided, that all ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Confederate and ex-Federal soldiers who, from old age or other cause, may be incapacitated to do and perform manual labor, and who are actual residents of the State of Texas, and are not inmates of any soldiers&#8217; home, or drawing any pension from the United States or any State gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment, be and are hereby exempted from the payment of any such peddler&#8217;s occupation tax; provided, such persons shall not be exempt from such peddlers&#8217; tax if employed in peddling for any other person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons; nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to include travel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing vendors of tin or earthen ware; provided further, that nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to include traveling vendors of literature exclusively religious in character, or traveling vendors of poultry, vege<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tables or other country produce exclusively, fruit and fruit trees ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusively, if raised or produced by the vendor or his family.</p>
<p>Sub. 22. From every theatre or dramatic representation for which pay for admission is demanded or received in towns or cities of 1500 in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants or less, one dollar; in towns and cities of 1500 and not over 3000, two dollars, in towns and cities of over 3000 and not less than 5000, three dollars; in towns and cities over 5000 and not over 10,000, four dollars, and in towns and cities of over 10,000 inhabitants, five dollars per day for every day they may perform; provided, that theatrical or dramatic representations given by performers for instruction only, or entirely for charitable purposes, shall not be herein included. Provided, however, that this tax shall not be collected where the performances are exhibited in regularly recognized opera houses of theatres, but in lieu of said tax the managers of said opera house or theatres shall pay an an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual occupation tax of twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 26. From every circus where equestrian or acrobatic feats and performances are exhibited, for which pay for admission is demanded or received, for each performance or exhibition where an admission fee of one dollar is charged, two hundred and fifty dollars; for each perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance or exhibition where admission fee of 75 cents is charged, two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars; for each performance where 50 cents or less is charged, one hundred dollars; provided, that the amount of fee charged for reserved seats shall be considered as a part of such admission fee; provided, that where there is a combination of circus and menagerie, or circus and other exhibitions, the highest tax fixed by this act for any division or depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the combination shall be collected; provided further, that every show or exhibition which advertises itself as a circus or menagerie, or a combination of circus and menagerie, shall be held and construed to be a circus or a menagerie or a circus and menagerie whether it be such or not.</p>
<p>Sub. 24. From every menagerie, wax-works museum, side show or exhibition, whether connected with a circus or not, where a separate fee for admission is demanded or received, ten dollars for every performance or exhibition in which fees for admission are received.</p>
<p>Sub. 25. From every exhibition where acrobatic feats are performed and an admission fee charged for profit, not connected with the circus or theatre, ten dollars for each performance.</p>
<p>Sub. 26. From every sleight of hand performance or exhibition of legerdemain, not connected with a theatre or circus, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 27. From every person bringing off a fight between dogs and<pb n="1493" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>bulls, or between bears and dogs, or between bulls and any other animals, or between dogs and dogs, five hundred dollars for each performance.</p>
<p>Sub. 28. From every cock-pit, when kept for profit, or upon which any money or anything of value is bet or paid, fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 29. From every menagerie, wax-works or exhibition of any kind where a separate fee for admission is demanded or received, ten dollars for every day on which fees for such admission are received; provided, that exhibitions by associations organized for promotion of art, science, charity or benevolence, shall be exempt from taxation; and provided further, that persons who form a museum composed entirely of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducts of Texas shall have the right to exhibit the same for a fee without paying any occupation tax.</p>
<p>Sub. 30. From every concert where a fee for admission is demanded or received, two dollars; provided, that entertainments when given by the citizens for charitable purposes, or for the support or aid of literary or cemetery associations are exempt.</p>
<p>Sub. 31. From every livery or feed stable, thirty cents for each stall and thirty cents for each hack, buggy or other vehicle; and from every hack, buggy, dray, wagon or other vehicle let for hire not connected with a livery, feed or sale stable, two dollars; from every wagon yard used for profit, five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 32. From each and every person acting as general adjuster of losses, or agents of life, fire, marine and accidental insurance companies who may transact any business as such in this State, an annual occupa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion tax of fifty dollars. By &#8220;general agent,&#8221; as used in this law, is meant any person or firm, representative of any insurance company in this State or who may exercise a general supervision over the business of such in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />surance company in this State, or over the local agency thereof in this State, or any subdivision thereof; provided, that when such a general agent acts as a local agent, he shall pay an additional tax as a local agent, as hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sub. 33. From each and every person or firm acting as local agent or agents of life, fire, marine and accident insurance companies, who may transact any business as such in this State, an annual occupation tax of five dollars. By &#8220;local agent,&#8221; as used in this law, is meant any person or firm who may solicit, contract for or receive premiums for insurance in this State, for any insurance company or companies, or who may de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liver contracts or policies of insurance, including railway agents and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployes who may solicit or receive premiums for accident insurance in this State.</p>
<p>Sub. 34. From each and every person or firm acting as local agent or agents of industrial life insurance companies, who may transact any busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness as such in this State, an annual tax of two dollars. By &#8220;industrial life insurance, as used in this law, is meant insurance adapted to the wants and necessities of the wage-earners, in that the policies are small and the premium collected weekly at the homes of the insured, the maxi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mum policy or [of] insurance written on any one person being one thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 35. From every person, firm or association of persons, dealing in lightning rods, an annual tax of thirty-six dollars to the State and eight<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />een dollars as county tax to the county in which such business is carried on; and upon every person canvassing for the sale of lightning rods, an<pb n="1494" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>annual tax of one hundred dollars to the State and fifty dollars as county tax, in each county in which such canvassing is done.</p>
<p>Sub. 36. From every person, firm or association of persons following the occupation of cotton broker, cotton factor, or commission merchant, in a city of ten thousand inhabitants or over, thirty-five dollars; and in all cities and towns of less than ten thousand inhabitants, an annual tax of eighteen dollars; provided, that a merchant who pays an occupation tax under this law shall not be considered as a cotton broker. A &#8220;com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission merchant,&#8221; in the meaning of this article, is every person, firm or association of persons, receiving country produce, horses, cattle, sheep, hogs, grain, corn, hay, lumber, shingles, wool, coal, goods, wares and merchandise, or anything else for sale, to be accounted for to the owner when sold, and charging a commission therefor.</p>
<p>Sub. 37. From every pawnbroker, an annual tax of one hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 38. From every cotton buyer or buyer of wool or hides, ten dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; provided, that a merchant who pays an occupation tax, as herein prescribed, shall not be considered a cotton buyer or buyer of wool or hides.</p>
<p>Sub. 39. From every person, firm, agency, or association of persons dealing in sewing machines, an annual tax of fifteen dollars to the State and seven dollars as a county tax in every county where such business may be carried on; provided, that a merchant who pays an occupation tax, as required by this article, shall not be required to pay this special tax to sell sewing machines when sold in his place of business.</p>
<p>Sub. 40. From every person or firm who peddles out clocks, cooking stoves or ranges, wagons, buggies, carriages, surreys and other similar vehicles, washing machines and churns, an annual tax of two hundred and fifty dollars for the State, and one hundred dollars for each county in which they make a sale; provided, that a merchant who pays an occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation tax, as required by this article, shall not be required to pay this special tax for selling the articles named in this paragraph when sold in his place of business, or in the county in which his place of business is lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated.</p>
<p>Sub. 41. Each and every express company shall annually, on or before the first day of March, through its superintendent or other chief officer or authorized agent, file with the comptroller of public accounts a report under oath, showing the amount of charges and freights within this State paid to or uncollected by such companies on account of money, goods and merchandise carried within this State during the year ending December 31st next preceding, and said express companies, at the time of filing their required report, shall pay to the treasurer of the State one and one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half per cent of their gross receipts, as shown by their said report. The receipt of the State treasurer shall be evidence of the payment of such taxes, city or town corporation in this State; provided, that this article shall not be construed to prohibit the levy of State, county and muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipal taxes upon the real and personal property of such companies. Each and every express company failing or refusing to file the report herein required, and pay the required taxes, shall forfeit to the State twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five dollars for each day said report and payment are delayed. For the purpose of suit to recover the taxes and forfeitures, venue and jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion is hereby expressly conferred on the courts of Travis county, and<pb n="1495" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>service upon any agent or officer of such company within this State shall in all respects be held legal and valid.</p>
<p>Sub. 42. From every person, firm or association of persons owning or running any railroad cars or steamboats in this State, there shall be col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected quarterly, on the first day of January, April, July and October of each year, a tax of one per cent on their gross receipts from all their passenger travel within this State. The said gross receipts to be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned under oath by said owner, agents or manager to the comptroller, and said tax to be collected by said comptroller under such regulations as he may prescribe; provided, that nothing herein contained shall au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorize the levy of any county or municipal tax upon such person, firm or association of persons.</p>
<p>Sub. 43. From every chartered telegraph company doing business in this State, there shall be collected one cent for every full rate message sent by any person, firm or association of persons within this State to any person within this State, and one-half that for any message less than a full rate message so sent. This tax to be paid quarterly to the comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller on the sworn statement of the chief manager of said company or companies, or any other officer authorized by said companies to make said statement, who shall keep a record of such messages; and the receipt of the comptroller, under seal, shall be issued to said company or compa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nies, certified copies of which shall be evidence of the payment of the State tax; provided, railroad messages for running their trains and for company use shall not be taxed; and provided further, that nothing herein contained shall authorize the levy or collection of any county or municipal tax upon such chartered companies for messages sent, and messages sent on official business by officers of the United States.</p>
<p>Sub. 44. From each gas company, manufacturing gas in towns and cities of ten thousand or more inhabitants, thirty-five dollars; in a city or town of less than ten thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 45. From each electric light company operating an electric light plant in a town or city of ten thousand inhabitants or more, thirty-five dollars; in a city or town of less than ten thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 46. From each water works company operating a water works plant in a town or city of ten thousand inhabitants or more, thirty-five dollars; in a city or town of less than ten thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 47. From every person, firm or association of persons loaning money as agents or agents for any corporation, firm or association, either in this State or out of it, an annual occupation tax of one hundred, and fifty dollars for the State, for the principal office, and a county tax of fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen dollars from each agent for each county in which he may do busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, and no additional occupation tax shall be levied by any county, city or town in this State.</p>
<p>Sub. 48. From each person, party, partnership or corporation en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gaged in the business of inquiring into and reporting upon the credit or standing of persons engaged in business in this State, or acting as agent or business manager in this State for any such person, party, partner<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ship, joint stock association or corporation, three hundred dollars; and provided, further, that no county, city or town shall levy or collect any occupation tax upon or from, any such person, party, partnership, joint<pb n="1496" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>stock association or corporation. The payment of this tax, evidenced by the receipt of the comptroller of public accounts, shall exempt the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany or party paying the same from the payment of this tax in any other county; and payment of such tax shall not be required of any subagent or correspondent of the party or company carrying on such business in this State.</p>
<p>Sub. 49. From each and every owner or keeper of any skating rink, used for profit, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 50. From every manager of a base ball park in a city or town containing five thousand or more inhabitants, where an admission fee is charged, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 51. From each owner or keeper, of every steam laundry, ten dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>Sub. 52. From each person or corporation, who are wholesale dealers, selling imported or home-made ice to the trade to be sold again, in cities and towns of twenty thousand inhabitants, or more, fifty dollars; in cities and towns of less than twenty thousand inhabitants, or more than ten thousand inhabitants, thirty dollars; in cities and towns of less than ten thousand inhabitants, and more than five thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars; in cities and towns of less than five thousand inhabitants, ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 53. From every owner or manager of every race track, one mile or more in length, used for profit, one hundred dollars; from each owner or manager of every race track, one-half mile or less in length, fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per annum; provided, this shall not apply to race tracks owned by private individuals and used only for training purposes, or in connection with agricultural fairs and expositions.</p>
<p>Sub. 54. Prom every street car company in this State, two dollars per mile on each mile of track owned by said company or corporation.</p>
<p>Sub. 55. Prom each owner or manager of every grain elevator doing business for fees or toll with a capacity of over one hundred thousand bushels, fifty dollars; on each owner or manager of every elevator with a capacity of fifty thousand bushels and not over one hundred thousand bushels, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 56. From each owner or manager of every phonographic, elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iric battery, graphophone or other like machines or instruments, where a fee is charged, an annual tax of twenty-five dollars; provided, that when an electric battery is used by a regularly authorized physician on a pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tient no tax shall be charged.</p>
<p>Sub. 57. From each owner or keeper of every kinetoscope, cinetograph or similar machine or instrument used for profit, which shows the life<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />like motions of persons or animals, an annual occupation tax of twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five dollars.</p>
<p>Sub. 58. From each owner, manager or keeper of every panorama or view show, used for profit, exhibiting in a wagon, room, tent or else<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />where, an annual occupation tax of ten dollars and a county occupation tax of two dollars per annum. A panorama or view show in the meaning of this act is a show exhibiting pictures, statuary or other works of art which are viewed through stereoscopic or magnifying lenses.</p>
<p>Sub. 59. Prom every person, firm or association who are wholesale dealers in cotton seed oil or any of the products of cotton seed, selling such to the trade, a tax of twenty-five dollars; provided, that this tax<pb n="1497" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>shall not apply to a merchant who sells other goods and merchandise and pays an annual occupation tax therefor.</p>
<p>Sub. 60. Prom each owner, manager or keeper of every show or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany of persons giving exhibitions of music, songs, recitations, sleight of hand, gymnastic, dancing or other kinds of performances in a tent, house or elsewhere, which said exhibitions are used for profit by sale of medi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cines, electric belts or other articles of value, whether charge is made only for seats or not, an annual occupation tax of fifty dollars and a county occupation tax of two dollars and fifty cents for every such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance or exhibition. Provided, this tax shall not be assessed when these performances are given inside the grounds of any State or county fair during the time that said State or county fair is giving its annual exhibition.</p>
<p>Sub. 61. From every person, firm or association of persons selling on commission, if in a city of more than ten thousand inhabitants, fifty dollars; if in a city or town of less than ten thousand inhabitants, twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five dollars. This article is intended to cover every person, firm or asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation of persons selling on samples only, and who do not carry any stock of merchandise or anything else on hand; provided, that this tax shall not apply to commercial travelers or salesmen making sales or soliciting trade from merchants.</p>
<p>Sub. 62. From all dealers in cigarettes in this State, the sum of ten dollars per annum, a cigarette being within: the meaning of this act the same as defined by the laws of the United States government; provided, that this tax shall be in addition to the occupation tax levied on mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chants, and any other tax levied under the law; and provided, further that each dealer shall be required to procure an annual license from the county clerk of the county where he proposes to sell cigarettes which shall be granted for no shorter or longer period than one year; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, further, that the license shall describe the house and locality where the dealer proposes to sell cigarettes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. For the purpose of suit to recover the taxes and forfeiture, venue and jurisdiction is hereby expressly conferred upon the courts of Travis county, and service upon any officer or agent of such company within this State shall in all respects be held legal and valid.</p>
<p>When the Comptroller furnishes collectors with blank occupation tax receipts he shall furnish the commissioners&#8217; court with the numbers and value of the receipts furnished to their respective collectors, and such courts shall charge their respective collectors with the number and such proportion of the value of the receipts so furnished, as shall apply to the county tax, when such collectors shall make their settlements with the Comptroller. The Comptroller shall furnish the commissioners&#8217; court with the numbers and value of the receipts returned, and with the amount of the occupation taxes collected by their respective collectors.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, the occupation taxes collected are not adequate, and an imperative public necessity exists that they be in some instances in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />creased, in order that the State may immediately derive benefit of the same, therefore, an imperative public necessity exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and that the same take effect from its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<pb n="1498" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act passed the House by a vote of yeas 82, nays 15; passed the Senate with amendments by a two-thirds vote, yeas 22, nays 2; and the House concurred in Senate amendments, vote not given.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, an Sunday, the twentieth day of June, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 22.] CHAPTER 19.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to enforce the attendance of witnesses in criminal cases upon district courts, grand juries and magistrates sitting as examining courts, in counties other than that of their residence, under subpoena, and to provide for the pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ishment for disobedience of such subpoenas, and to repeal Articles 525, 526, 527, 528, 529, 530, 531, 532, 533 and 534, Title 7, Chapter 4, of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, adopted by the 24th Legislature, 1895, and all other laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: Where a witness resides out of the county in which the prosecution is pending, the defendant shall be entitled on application, either in term time or in vacation, to the proper clerk or magistrate, to a subpoena is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to compel the attendance of such witness. Such application shall be in writing and under oath, shall state the name and residence of the witness, and his exact location and avocation, if known, and that his tes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />timony is believed to be material to the defense. The State shall also be entitled to subpoenas under the provisions of this article upon the writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten application of the attorney representing the State, which application shall state the name and residence of the witness, and his exact location and avocation, if known, and that his testimony is believed to be mate<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rial for the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the officer receiving said subpoena to execute the same by delivering a copy thereof to the witness or witnesses therein named, and he shall make due return of said subpoena showing therein the time and manner of executing the same, and if not executed, such return shall show why not executed, the diligence used to find said witness, and such information as the officer has, if any, as to the where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />abouts of said witness.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. When a subpoena is returnable forthwith, it shall be the duty of the officer to immediately serve the witness with copy of the same, and it shall be the duty of said witness to immediately make his appear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance before the court magistrate or other authority issuing the same; and if said witness make affidavit of his inability from lack of funds to appear in obedience to said subpoena, it shall be the duty of the officer executing the same to provide said witness, if said subpoena be issued in a felony case, with the necessary funds or means to appear in obedience to said subpoena, taking his receipt therefor, and showing in his return<pb n="1499" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>on said subpoena under oath the amount furnished to said witness, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with the amount of his fees for executing said subpoena, and such officer shall be entitled to receive from the State, for executing such pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess, the sum of fifty cents for serving each witness, and five cents per mile for each mile actually traveled in the execution of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. It shall be the duty of the clerk of the court, the magistrate, or the foreman of the grand jury, issuing said process, immediately upon the return of said subpoena, if issued in a felony case, to issue to such officer a certificate for the amount furnished such witness, together with the amount of his fees for executing the same, showing the amount of each item, which certificate shall be approved by the judge of the district court, and recorded by the clerk of the district court in a well bound book kept for that purpose, and said certificate transmitted to the officer exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuting such subpoena, which amount shall be paid by the State as costs are paid in other criminal matters.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Witnesses shall receive from the State for attendance upon district courts, magistrates sitting as examining courts, and grand juries in counties other than that of their residence, in obedience to subpoenas issued under the provisions of this act, such compensation as is now re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived by witnesses attending such, under attachment, to be paid as now provided by law, and such magistrate, foreman of the grand jury or clerk of the district court, shall issue to such witness a certificate therefor after deducting therefrom the amount advanced by the officer serving said sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poena, as shown by the return on said subpoena, which certificate shall be approved by the district judge, and recorded by the clerk in a well bound book kept for that purpose; provided, that when an indictment can be found from the evidence taken before an inquest or examining trial, no subpoena or attachment shall issue for a witness who resides out of the county in which the prosecution is pending to appear before a grand jury; and provided further, that when the grand jury shall certify to the district judge that sufficient evidence can not be secured upon which to find an indictment except upon the testimony of non-resident witnesses, the district judge may have subpoenas issued as provided for in this act to other counties for witnesses to testify before the grand jurv not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed one witness to any one fact nor more than three witnesses to any one case pending before the grand jury.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. If the subpoena be returnable at some future date, the officer shall have authority to take a good and sufficient bail bond of such wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, for his appearance under said subpoena, which bond shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned with such subpoena, and shall be made payable to the State of Texas, in the amount in which the witness and his surety shall be bound, and conditioned for the appearance of the witness at the time and before the court, magistrate or grand jury named in said subpoena, and shall be signed by the witness and his sureties; but if said witness refuse to give bond he shall be kept in custody until such time as he shall start in obedience of said subpoena, when he shall be, upon affidavit being made, provided with funds necessary to appear in obedience of said subpoena.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The court or magistrate issuing said subpoena may direct therein the amount of the bond to be required, but in case the amount is not specified, the officer may fix the amount, and in either case shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire good and sufficient security, to be approved by himself.</p>
<pb n="1500" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 8. If a witness refuse to obey a subpoena as herein provided, he shall be fined by the court or magistrate in any sum not exceeding five hundred dollars, which fine and judgment shall be final unless set aside after due notice to show cause why it should not be final, which notice may immediately issue requiring the defaulting witness to appear at once or at the next term of said court, in the discretion of the judge, to answer for such default, and the court may, in his descretion, cause to be issued at the same time an attachment for said witness, directed to the proper county, commanding the officer to whom said writ is directed to take said witness into custody and have him before said court at the time named in said writ; in which case such witness shall receive no compensation unless it appears to the court that such dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />obedience is excusable, when the witness may receive the same compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation as if he had been attached; and said fine and all costs thereon shall be collected as in criminal cases; provided, that said fine and judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment may be set aside at the same or any subsequent term of the court or in vacation for good cause shown, after the witness shall have testi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied or been discharged.</p>
<p>The following words shall be written or printed on the face of such subpoena: &#8220;A disobedience of this subpoena is punishable by fine not exceeding five hundred dollars, to be collected as fines and costs in other criminal cases.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That Articles 525, 526, 527, 528, 529, 530, 531, 532, 533 and 534, of Title 7, Chapter 4, of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas adopted by the 24th legislature, 1895, be and the same are hereby repealed, and that all other laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>July 3, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, J. W. Madden, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the foregoing laws, passed by the first special session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature, have been carefully examined and compared with the orig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal enrolled bills, now on file in this department, and are true copies thereof.</p>
<p>I further certify that the said first special session of the Twenty-fifth Legislature convened in the city of Austin on the twenty-second day of May, A. D. 1897, and adjourned on the twentieth day of June, A. D. 1897.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have subscribed my name and <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[Seal.]</p></body></floatingText>have hereto affixed the seal of the State of Texas, in the City of Austin, this August 4, A. D. 1897.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. MADDEN, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1501" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>Adjutant General&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 36</p>
<p>Agricultural and Mechanical Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 35</p>
<p>Agriculture, Insurance, Statistics and History, Department of&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 23</p>
<p>Allison, State Convict&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 26</p>
<p>Appropriations&#8212;</p>
<p>Mileage and per diem first called session Twenty-fifth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture..... 1</p>
<p>Relief of citizens of El Paso and El Paso county..... 1</p>
<p>Contingent expenses first called session Twenty-fifth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture..... 2</p>
<p>Deficiency..... 3</p>
<p>For support of State govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment....... 17</p>
<p>Assessors of Taxes&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of..... 5</p>
<p>Attorney General&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 21</p>
<p>Bandera County&#8212;</p>
<p>Thirty-eighth judicial district.. 41</p>
<p>Blind Asylum&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 31</p>
<p>Collectors&#8212;of Taxes&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of...... 5</p>
<p>Comptroller&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 18</p>
<p>Confederate Home&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 33</p>
<p>Constables&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of...... 5</p>
<p>Corporations&#8212;</p>
<p>Certain, liable for injuries to fellow servants..... 14</p>
<p>County Attorneys&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of....... 5</p>
<p>County Clerks<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Fees of...... 5</p>
<p>County Judges&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of...... 5</p>
<p>Court of Civil Appeals, Second Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict&#8212;</p>
<p>Deficiency appropriation for... 3</p>
<p>Court of Criminal Appeals&#8212;</p>
<p>Deficiency appropriation for... 3</p>
<p>General appropriation for..... 22</p>
<p>Courts of Civil Appeals&#8212;</p>
<p>First district, appropriation for. 24</p>
<p>Second district, appropriation for...... 25</p>
<p>Third district, appropriation for...... 25</p>
<p>Fourth district, appropriation for....... 25</p>
<p>Fifth district, appropriation for 25</p>
<p>Deaf and Dumb Asylum&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for....... 32</p>
<p>Deaf, Dumb and Blind Asylum for Colored Youths&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 34</p>
<p>Department of State&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 18</p>
<p>District Attorneys&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of...... 5</p>
<p>District Clerks&#8212;</p>
<p>Fees of..... 5</p>
<p>District Judges&#8212;</p>
<p>Exchange of Districts..... 39</p>
<p>Education, Department of&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 22</p>
<p>El Paso&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for relief of citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens of.......... 1</p>
<p>El Paso County&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for relief of citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens of...... 1</p>
<p>Executive Office&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for...... 17</p>
<p>Fees&#8212;</p>
<p>Of certain precinct, county, and district officers...... 5</p>
<p>Amending above act...... 42</p>
<p>Fellow-Servants&#8212;</p>
<p>Liability of certain persons and corporations for injuries to.. 14</p>
<p>House of Correction&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 33</p>
<p>Insane Asylums&#8212;</p>
<p>Southwestern, appropriation for 28</p>
<p>North Texas, appropriation for 29</p>
<p>Insurance Commissioner&#8212;</p>
<p>Certain powers of...... 15</p>
<p>Insurance Companies&#8212;</p>
<p>Powers of Insurance Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner as to...... 15</p>
<p>Interest on Public Debt&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..... 26</p>
<p>Judicial Districts&#8212;</p>
<p>Thirty-eighth...... 41</p>
<pb n="1502" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>