<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="639" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="209" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION. (Leave of absence to Judge L. W. Goodrich.)</head>
<p>House Concurrent resolution No. 9.</p>
<p>Whereas, the Hon L. W. Goodrich, district judge of the nineteenth district, desires to leave the State on or about the first day of February, on important and private business: Therefore be it</p>
<p>Resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring: That the said Hon. L. W. Goodrich, district judge of the nineteenth district of Texas, be and the same is allowed to leave the State for a period of thirty days, from 1st of February until 1st of March, 1893.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing concurrent resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 2d day of February, A. D. 1893, but was not signed by him, nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature. Geo. W. Smith, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION. (Chicamauga and Chattanooga Commissioners.)</head>
<p>Whereas, Congress has purchased the battle field of Chicamauga, and established the Chicamauga and Chattanooga military park; and</p>
<p>Whereas the States of Georgia and Tennessee have ceded the roads through the field and over Lookout Mountain, and along the crest of Missionary Ridge, as approaches to and a part of said park; and</p>
<p>Whereas, a commission appointed by the Secretary of War is now en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gaged in locating both the Union and Confederate lines of battle: Therefore be it</p>
<p>Resolved, that the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, hereby authorize and empower the Governor of this State to appoint a commission of five gentlemen, each of whom participated in the battle of Chicamauga or Chattanooga, who shall serve without pay, and whose duty it shall be to co-operate with the national commission in ascertain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and marking the positions occupied in these battles by each regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, battery, and independent organization from this State, who were engaged there; and for this purpose they shall avail themselves of the knowledge and assistance of representatives of such regiments, bat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teries, and other organizations.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 29, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="640" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="210" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION. (To amend sec. 51, art 3, State Constitution.)</head>
<opener>
<salute>[H. J. R. No. 4.]&#8212;Joint resolution proposing to amend section 51, article 3 of the Constitution of the State of Texas, authorizing the establishment and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of a home for indigent and disabled Confederate soldiers and sailors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That section 51, article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 51. The Legislature shall have no power to make any grant, or authorize the making of any grant of public money to any individual, association of individuals, municipal or other corporation whatsoever: Provided, however, the Legislature may grant aid to the establishment and maintenance of a home for indigent and disabled Confederate sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers or sailors who are or may be bona fide residents of the State of Texas, under such regulations and limitations as may be provided by law: Provided, that such grant shall not exceed the sum of $100,000 for any one year: And provided further, that the provisions of this section shall not be construed so as to prevent the grant of aid in case of public calamity.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This resolution shall be submitted by the Governor to a vote of the qualified electors for members of the Legislature of the State of Texas at the next general election, to be held on Tuesday after the first Monday in November, 1894, at which election all voters favoring said proposed amendment shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;For the amendment to section 51, article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas,&#8221; and all those opposed to the amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;Against the amendment to section 51, article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Immediately after the election the officers of each precinct shall forward to the county judge of their county a duplicate return, showing the number of votes cast for and against the amendment, and on the following Monday the county judge shall open and count said returns, and forthwith forward to the Secretary of State, in a sealed package, a tabulated statement thereof, showing the total number of votes cast in the county for and against the amendment; and on the fortieth day after said election the Secretary of State shall, in the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence of the Governor and Attorney-General, open and count said re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns; and if it shall appear from the returns that a majority of the votes were cast for said amendment, it shall be the duty of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, on the following day, or as soon thereafter as practicable, to issue his proclamation setting forth the fact that said amendment has re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived a majority of all the votes cast upon that question at said elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and shall proclaim that said amendment has become and is a part of the Constitution of the State of Texas, and the amendment shall take effect from and after said publication.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 8, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="641" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="211" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION. (Acceptance of donation State Encampment Grounds.)</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. C. R. No. 9.]&#8212;Senate concurrent resolution. Concurrent resolution accepting the donation of the citizens of Austin of ninety-one acres of land, situated in Travis county, with improvements thereon, known and designated as &#8220;Camp Mabry,&#8221; for use as the place for holding the annual encampments of the militia of this State; and returning thanks for same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the citizens of the city of Austin, Texas, have, by private subscription, purchased a suitable tract of land, and at their own expense have erected thereon all improvements necessary for the comfort and, use of the volunteers of this State at their annual encampments; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the said citizens, through John L. Peeler, trustee, have do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated said tract of land and improvements thereon, known and desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated as &#8220;Camp Mabry,&#8221; to the State for the use of her volunteers.</p>
<p>Section 1. Therefore be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That James S. Hogg, Governor, be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to accept the deeds from said John L. Peeler, trustee, conveying to the State the title to the land indicated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Legislature of the State of Texas hereby tenders its thanks to Messrs. H. E. Shelley, J. J. Tobin, John Orr, W. H. To<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bin, Frank Maddox, T. J. Hume, A. C. Goeth, J. M. Day, A. S. Roberts, and others, the gentlemen who, by the expenditure of their own time and labor, were largely instrumental in inducing the generous citizens of Austin to bestow this munificent gift upon the volunteers of the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 1, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT resolution. (Relative to navigation of Trinity river.)</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. C. R. No. 18.] Concurrent resolution. Concurrent resolution requesting the Senators and Representatives of Texas in Congress to secure ail appropriation to open up the Trinity river for permanent navigation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, freight and transportation charges on all incoming and out<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going staple commodities in Texas about equal the first cost of the same at the place of production; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the United States government has now under construction, at heavy cost, several harbors on the Gulf coast of Texas, and to realize the full benefit of these expenditures of millions of dollars on the Texas coast, it is necessary to secure cheap transportation from the interior to these ports, and from these ports to the interior; and</p>
<p>Whereas, experience has taught us that for years to come this can not be obtained from the railroads alone, and that Texas has large rivers running through the State, from the interior to the Gulf, that might be made navigable for cheap transportation by the expenditure of reasonable sums of money by the general government; and</p>
<p>Whereas it is known that the Trinity river is a navigable stream, and that in 1873 as many as seventeen steamers were running on its waters,<pb n="642" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="212" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>coming within thirty miles of Dallas, and that as late as 1868 One landed at the foot of Main street, in Dallas; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the people along said river, appreciating the fact that the<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />same is navigable, and anxious to develop the same, are now spending one hundred thousand dollars in cleaning out snags and drifts and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moving overhanging timber; and</p>
<p>Whereas, it has been the policy of the United States government to improve the waterways of the land and thus afford cheap transportation to the people: and</p>
<p>Whereas, the improvement of the Trinity river so as to secure navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation for the entire year will save millions of dollars to the people of Texas: Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate, the House of Representatives concur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ring: That our senators and representatives in Congress be respectfully and earnestly requested, as speedily as possible, to secure an appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation sufficient to open the Trinity river for permanent navigation.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 11, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION. (Relative to improvement of Capitol Grounds. )</head>
<opener>
<salute>A concurrent resolution to refer back to the board to advertise for, receive, adopt, and reject plans and specifications for the improvement of the Capitol grounds, with power and instructions to adopt or reject any and all of such plans and specifications, and to return such as may be rejected back to the owner thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Twenty-second Legislature constituted the Governor, Attorney-General, and Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds, a board for the purpose of advertising for plans and specifications and an estimate of cost for improving the Capitol grounds, and appropriated, the sum of two thousand dollars for the payment of such plans and spec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ifications that should be adopted by said board or by the Legislature; and</p>
<p>Whereas, in response to the advertisement of said board, certain plans and specifications were prepared by competing architects and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted to said board, and through said board to the Legislature; and</p>
<p>Whereas, neither said board nor the Legislature has adopted any of said plans and specifications: Therefore</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the said plans and specification and estimates he and the same are hereby referred back to the board, with the power and instruction to adopt such of the plans and specifications as may be deemed by said board suitable and proper, and in case none of the plans and specifications are deemed suitable and proper, to reject all of them, and to turn over all such plans and specifications as may be rejected by said board to the owners thereof.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 11, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="643" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="213" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SENATE JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. J. R. No. 8.] Senate joint resolution, to amend section 30, article 16, of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section 30, article 16, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be amended so that it shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 30. The duration of all offices not fixed by this Constitution shall never exceed two years: Provided, that when a railroad commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion is created by law it shall be composed of three commissioners, who shall be elected by the people at a general election for State officers, and their terms of office shall be six years: Provided, railroad commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers first elected after this amendment goes into effect shall hold office as follows: One shall serve two years, and one four years, and one six years, their terms to be decided by lot, immediately after they shall have qualified. And one railroad commissioner shall be elected every two years thereafter. In case of vacancy in said office, the Governor of the State shall fill said vacancy by appointment until the next general election.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The foregoing amendment shall be submitted to the qualified voters of the State at the next general election. Those favoring its adoption shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;For election of railroad commissioners,&#8221; and those opposed to its adoption shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;Against elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of railroad commissioners.&#8221; And the Governor of the State is hereby directed to issue the necessary proclamation for such election, and have the same published as required by the Constitution and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isting laws of the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 11, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SENATE JOINT RESOLUTION. (Relative to navigation of Colorado River.)</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. J. R. No. 14.] Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Colorado river, one of the most important streams in Texas, and which is susceptible of being made navigable, is obstructed at its mouth by a great mass of raft wood and debris; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the opening of the mouth of said river is a matter of na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional importance and of particular interest and benefit to the State of Texas: Therefore be it</p>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: 1st. That our Senators and Representatives in Congress be requested to urge upon the Congress of the United States the necessity of an appropriation from the United States government to remove the obstructions to navigation above mentioned.</p>
<p>2d. That the President of the Senate and Speaker of the House of Representatives be requested to have a certified copy of these resolutions furnished our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 11, A. D. 1893</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<pb n="644" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="214" /><fw type="header" place="top">Certificate.</fw>
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, Geo. W. Smith, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the foregoing laws and resolutions, passed at the regular session of the Twenty-third Legislature, have been carefully examined and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared with the original enrolled bills, now on file in this department, and are true copies of said originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Twenty-third Legislature convened in the city of Austin January 10, A. D. 1893, and adjourned May 9, A. D. 1893.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have subscribed my name and <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[Seal]</p></body></floatingText>have hereto affixed the seal of the State of Texas, in the city of Austin, this June 3, A. D. 1893.</p>
<closer>
<signed>GEO. W. SMITH, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<pb n="645" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="215" />
<p>List of Bills with Emergency Clause, showing when they take effect.</p>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/0645_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>