<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="425" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. J. R. No. 1.] Authorizing the governor of Texas to collect the money due the State of Texas from the United States government by reason of the direct tax of 1861, and to provide for the disbursement thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, There is a large sum of money due the State of Texas by the United States government, by reason of the act of the 51st congress, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved March 2, 1891, which said act refunds to the states the money collected under the direct tax bill of 1861; and</p>
<p>Whereas, by the said act of March 2, 1891, the governor of the State of Texas, to whom said money is made payable, cannot collect the same until a resolution of the Legislature authorizing him so to do, and to provide for the disbursement thereof; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the governor of this State is hereby authorized and empowered to receive from the treasurer of the United States all moneys due the State of Texas under the act of the 51st congress, approved March 2, 1891, entitled &#8220;An act to credit and pay to the states and territories and the District of Columbia all moneys collected under the direct tax levied by the act of congress approved August 5, 1861,&#8221; and receipt therefor in such manner as may be required, and place the same in the treasury of the State of Texas: and the State of Texas accepts and receives such moneys in full satisfaction of all claims against the United States on ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count of the levy and collection of such tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The attorney general, treasurer and comptroller of the State of Texas shall constitute an auditing board to audit and pass upon all claims of individuals claiming any part of such moneys under such rules of procedure as such board may prescribe, and upon the allowance of any such claim the comptroller shall draw his draft upon the treasurer in payment therefor, and such board shall give such notice and hold such meetings as may be necessary to enable the people to whom such money belongs to readily obtain the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, the present session of the legislature is limited to thirty days, and it is impossible during that time to transact the business pending before the senate; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The money herein sought to be refunded is lying idle in the treasury in Washington;</p>
<p>Therefore an emergency and public necessity exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and said rule is hereby suspended, and this resolution shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution originated in the senate, and passed the same by a vote of 24 yeas and no nays; and passed the house by a vote of 84 yeas and no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SENATE CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>[S. C. R. No. 1.] The people of Texas having heard with profound sorrow of the death of General Walter P. Lane, which occurred at his home in Marshall, Texas, on the 19th day of January 1892, and<pb n="426" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>believing that we, as the representatives of the people, should give some expression in respect to the memory of this illustrious hero; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate and the House of Representatives: That by the death of General Lane the state has lost a citizen whose whole life was devoted to her welfare. In war he was the incomparable sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dier, and in peace the modest and dutiful citizen.</p>
<p>Resolved 2d: That the services he rendered Texas will be ever cher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished by patriotic people, and his glorious character will always be a splendid example for the coming generations of our state.</p>
<p>Resolved 3d: That these resolutions be spread upon the journals of the two houses and that an engrossed copy of the same be furnished to the family of the deceased.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 4, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Whereas, the committee appointed at the regular session of the 22d legislature to investigate the matters pertaining to the receivership of the I. &#38; G. N. Railroad; and</p>
<p>Whereas, said committee at its first meeting ascertained that no suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient appropriation was made to pay stenographers to aid said committee; and</p>
<p>Whereas, said committee did receive the services of competent stenog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />raphers, viz: Will P. Williams and W. J. Farwell, with the understand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing that the legislature would be asked at its first session after the meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of said committee to make an additional appropriation to pay said stenographers; and</p>
<p>Whereas, said stenographers have never been paid in full; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring: That the sum of two hundred and forty dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated out of the contingent fund of this legislature, one hundred and twenty dollars to pay said Farwell, and one hundred and twenty dollars to be paid said Williams.</p>
<p>And be it further resolved: That the further sum of thirty-nine dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars be appropriated from said fund to reimburse sergeant-at-arms Hen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson, for expenses incurred in summoning witnesses, said account not having been passed upon before the adjournment of the committee.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, George W. Smith, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the foregoing laws and resolutions, passed at the first called session of the Twenty-second Legislature, have been carefully examined and compared with the original enrolled bills now on file in this department, and are true copies of said originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the first called session of the Twenty-second Legislature convened, in pursuance to the proclamation of the governor, in the city of Austin, March 14, A. D. 1892, and adjourned April 12, A. D. 1892.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have subscribed my name, and have <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[SEAL]</p></body></floatingText>hereto affixed the seal of the State of Texas, in the city of Austin, May 21, A. D. 1892.</p>
<closer>
<signed>GEO. W. SMITH, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>