<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="361" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>FIRST CALLED SESSION OF THE TWENTY-SECOND LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>MARCH 14, 1892, AND ADJOURNED APRIL 12, 1892.</byline>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/0361_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<byline>AUSTIN 1892</byline>
<pb n="362" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" />
<pb n="363" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION BY THE GOVERNOR.</head>
<p>Executive Office, <lb/>Austin, Texas, February 18, 1892.</p>
<p>To Whom These Presents May Concern:</p>
<p>Whereas, The constitution requires the state to be reapportioned for certain purposes every ten years, and the time having about expired since the last apportionment, it is now necessary to perform that duty in obedience to organic law, that the people may have their full and just representation in the next congress and state legislature; and</p>
<p>Whereas, By vote of the qualified electors on the second Tuesday in August, A. D. 1891, five several amendments to the state constitution were adopted, and should be put in force at the earliest opportunity consistent with public interests; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The live stock industries of Texas are being seriously in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jured by restrictive laws passed by congress affecting transportation and sale of cattle under quarantine regulations, which can only be corrected by legislative action by the state; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The extravagant issuance of railway and municipal bonds, without valuable, just or proper consideration, but for speculative, fictitious purposes, threaten calamity to public prosperity, depreciate honest securities, cast opprobium on the state&#8217;s reputation abroad, and should be checked by just, restrictive laws.</p>
<p>For these and other good and sufficient reasons hereinafter named an extraordinary occasion has arisen, requiring the legislature to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vened.</p>
<p>Now, therefore, I, James S. Hogg, Governor of the State of Texas, do, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the constitution of said state, hereby call a special session of the Twenty-second Legislature, to be convened in the city of Austin, commencing at twelve o&#8217;clock, noon, on Monday, the fourteenth day of March, A. D. 1892, for the following purposes:</p>
<p>1. To reapportion the state into congressional, senatorial, judicial and representative districts, and to provide for election of officers therein.</p>
<p>2. To pass all laws necessary to put in force and give effect to each and all of the five amendments of the present state constitution, adopted by the people at an election duly held therefor on the second Tuesday of August, A. D. 1891, to-wit: Amendment to section four of article six; amendment to section five of article seven; amendment to section eleven of article sixteen; amendment to section twenty of article sixteen, and amendments to sections one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, eleven, twelve, sixteen, twenty-five; and twenty-eight of article five; of the said constitution.</p>
<p>3. To provide for the protection of the public and investors against the fraudulent and fictitious issuance and circulation of railway bonds and stock and county and municipal scrip and bonds; to restrict and regulate the issuance of bonds and stocks by such corporations; and to give full effect to the constitution on that subject.</p>
<p>4. To adopt such laws as may be necessary to protect live stock<pb n="364" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="IV" /><fw type="header" place="top">Proclamation by the Governor.</fw>within the state from contagions and infectious diseases, and from the rigor of Federal quarantine regulations with reference thereto.</p>
<p>5. To re-enact or amend and strengthen chapter 117, General Laws 1889, defining, punishing and prohibiting trusts and conspiracies against trade.</p>
<p>6. To accept by resolution, and authorize the governor to receive from the Federal government the return of and to appropriately dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />burse all money due the citizens or inhabitants of this state, collected as taxes from them under the act of congress approved August the fifth, eighteen hundred and sixty-one, and amendatory acts thereto.</p>
<p>7. To so change the laws that quarterly examinations or teachers shall not conflict with the time of holding their summer normal schools.</p>
<p>8. To receive and act on the report of the committee appointed to investigate the case of Jay Gould vs. The I. &#38; G. N. R. R., under a concurrent resolution passed at the general session of the Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />second Legislature.</p>
<p>9. To provide more secure liens for artisans, mechanics, material men, contractors, builders and laborers and their assigns for material and money furnished and services performed in building and construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>10. To so amend article 2899, Revised Statutes, and amendments thereto, that receivers of railways and other corporations may be held liable for damages when the death of or injury to persons is caused by the negligence or carelessness of themselves or their servants in exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuting their trusts.</p>
<p>11. To amend, modify, change or re-enact chapter 95, General Laws, passed by the Twenty-second Legislature, providing for uniform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity of public school text books.</p>
<p>12. To correct, modify, change, re-enact, repeal or amend chapter 62, General Laws, passed by the Twenty-second Legislature, limiting and regulating the right of aliens to own real estate in Texas.</p>
<p>13. To define perpetuities, and to restrict, regulate or prohibit cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porations owning land in this state, on prescribed conditions.</p>
<p>14. To make appropriation out of the general revenue to pay off public debt bonds issued in 1871 and to become due in March and April.</p>
<p>15. To elect a United States senator.</p>
<p>16. To consider and act on such other subjects of public importance as the executive may, from time to time during the session, submit by message or otherwise.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[Seal.]</p></body></floatingText>and caused to be impressed hereon the seal of the state, at Austin this 18th day of February, A. D. 1892.</p>
<closer>
<signed>[Signed] J. S. H<smcap>OGG</smcap>, <lb/>Governor of Texas.</signed>
<signed>By the Governor: <lb/>[Signed] G<smcap>EO</smcap>. W. S<smcap>MITH</smcap>, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="365" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS. FIRST CALLED SESSION TWENTY-SECOND LEGISLATURE, 1892.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPROPRIATION FOR MILEAGE AND PER DIEM OF MEM<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />BERS, OFFICERS AND EMPLOYES.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Forty thousand dollars appropriated for mileage and per diem pay of members, officers and employes of Called Session of Twenty-second Legislature.</p>
<p>2. How claims are audited.</p>
<p>3. Appropriates balance remaining of former appropriations.</p>
<p>4. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 1.&#8212;[H. B. No. 8.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation for mileage and per diem pay of members, and per diem pay of officers and employes of the First Called Session of the Twenty-second Legislature of Texas, convened March 14, 1892, by proclamation of the governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of forty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury of this state not otherwise appropriated, for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of mileage and per diem pay of the members and the payment of the per diem pay of the officers and employes of the First Called Ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Twenty-second Legislature of Texas, convened March 14, 1892, by proclamation of the governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the secretary of the senate, approved by the president thereof, or the certificate of the chief clerk of the house, approved by the speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the comptroller upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his warrants upon the treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the balance of the moneys remaining m the treasury heretofore appropriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers and the per diem pay of the officers and employes of any preced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing session of the legislature of the State of Texas, be and the same is hereby re-appropriated for the purposes specified in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The public importance of the objects herein contemplated creates an imperative public necessity and emergency fully authoriz<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is hereby suspended, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the house, and passed the same by a two-thirds vote&#8212;ayes 89, noes 3; and passed the senate by a two-thirds vote&#8212;ayes 26, noes 0.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 18, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPROPRIATION FOR CONTINGENT EXPENSES.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Ten thousand dollars appropriated for contingent expenses of Called Session of Twenty-second Legislature; auditing of claims.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 2.&#8212;[H. B. No. 24.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation to defray the contingent expenses of the First Called Session of the Twenty-second Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture convened March 14, 1892, by proclamation of the governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be<pb n="366" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay the contingent expenses of the First Called Session of the Twenty-second Legislature convened March 14th, 1892, by proclamation of the governor, and that the approval by the chairman of the committee on contingent expenses of either house, countersigned by the president of the senate or speaker of the house of representatives, as the case may be, shall be sufficient authority to authorize the comptroller to issue his warrant on the state treasurer for the payment of any account so drawn against said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the public importance of the objects herein contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated creates an imperative public necessity and emergency fully authorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is hereby suspended, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the house, and passed the same by two-thirds vote&#8212;yeas 91, nays 0; and passed the senate by two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote&#8212;yeas 25, nays 0.1</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 24, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">JUDICIAL DISTRICT&#8212;TWENTY-FIRST.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Counties composing twenty-first dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict; terms of court.</p>
<p>2. Return of process.</p>
<p>3. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>4. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 3.&#8212;[S. B. No. 27.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to organize and establish the twenty-first judicial district, to fix the times of holding courts therein, and to repeal all laws and parts of laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the counties of Washington, Burleson, Lee and Bastrop shall constitute the twenty-first, judicial district, and the district courts therein shall be held as follows: In the county of Washington on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session &#8226; six weeks; in the county of Lee on the seventh Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Burleson on the tenth Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session five weeks; in the county of Bastrop on the fifteenth Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session six weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All writs and process, civil and criminal, heretofore issued or which may be issued and made returnable to the terms of said dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict courts as said terms are now fixed by law at the time this act takes effect, shall be and are hereby made returnable to the next ensu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing terms of said courts as they are prescribed in this act; and all writ s and process issued by or from said courts after the adjournment of the term last held under the law as it exists at the time of the passage of this act shall be made returnable to the terms as prescribed in this act, and all such writs and process hereinbefore mentioned are hereby legalized and validated to all intents and purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the end of the session creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity requiring the suspen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="367" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>sion of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and said rule is hereby suspended.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the senate, and passed the same by a vote of, ayes 24, noes 0; and passed the house March 31, 1892, vote not given.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the governor of Texas for iris approval on the first day of April, A. D. 1892, hut was not signed by him, nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;Geo. W. Smith, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PUBLIC EDUCATION&#8212;TEACHERS&#8217; CERTIFICATES.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends section 2(a), chapter 116, acts of 1891.</p>
<p>2(a). Examinations, when made.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 4.&#8212;[H. B. No. 16.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section 2 (a) of chapter 116, acts of the Twenty-second Legislature entitled An act to provide for the issuance<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of certificates to teachers in the public schools of Texas and prescribing their duties as such,&#8221; approved April 28, 1891.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section 2(a), chapter 116, acts of the Twenty-second Legislature, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 2(a). Any one desiring to teach, a public free school shall, if required by the county superintendent or ex-officio county superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent, present a certificate from three good citizens known to the county superintendent or ex-officio county superintendent, that the applicant is of good moral character and exemplary habits. The county superintendent or ex-officio superintendent shall thereupon, unless some good cause exists for refusing the certificate hereinafter mentioned, recommend any applicant to the board of examiners for examination in this state. And the examination of white and colored teachers shall be held separately under such rules as the board of examiners may prescribe, which said board of examiners shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vened by the county superintendent or ex-officio superintendent on the third Friday and. Saturday of August, September, November, February, April and June of each year, for the purpose of examining applicants to teach in the public free schools of the state: The board of examiners shall use questions prescribed by the state superintendent of public instruction; provided, that [if] from any unavoidable cause the board of examiners can not hold their meetings on the days herein prescribed, the said board shall meet- as soon as practicable thereafter, on the call of the county superintendent or ex-officio superintendent, and in addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to the times above specified the board of examiners may be convened on the call of the superintendent or ex-officio superintendent at any time such superintendent shall deem necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. As summer normal schools will be begun before ninety days after the adjournment of the legislature, and as it is important that examinations shall be held at a time convenient for the commencement of summer schools, therefore an emergency and imperative public necessity exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and it is so sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is [so] enacted.</p>
<pb n="368" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the house, and passed the same by a two-thirds vote&#8212;ayes 81, noes 10; and passed the senate by a two-thirds vote&#8212;ayes 26, noes 2.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 4, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">STATE BONDED DEBT.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Two hundred and forty-eight thousand seven hundred dollars appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated to pay bonds due in March and April, 1892.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 5.&#8212;[S. B. No. 9.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation to pay the bonded debt of the State of Texas now held by individuals and falling due March 1st and April 1st, 1892.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of $248,700.00 be and the same is hereby appropriated out of the general revenue to pay state bonds now held by individuals and falling due March 1st and April 1st, 1892.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, certain of these bonds are now due, a public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity exists which demands that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be react on three several days be suspended and this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the senate, and passed the same by a vote of ayes 26, noes 0; and passed the house by a vote of ayes 85, noes 1.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">INTEREST.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends articles 2976, 2977, 2978, 2979 and 2980, Revised Statutes, and adds article 2981a.</p>
<p>Articles 2976. Legal interest on writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten contracts.</p>
<p>Article 2977. Legal interest on open accounts.</p>
<p>Article 2978. Conventional interest.</p>
<p>Article 2979. Penalty.</p>
<p>Article 2980. Interest on judgments.</p>
<p>Article 2981a. Recovery of illegal in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest paid.</p>
<p>2. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>3. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 6.&#8212;[H. B. No. 21.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend title 54, articles 2976, 2977, 2978, 2979, and 2980, of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas, regulating the rate of interest, and defining usury, and to add thereto article 2981a: to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late the rates of interest and prevent usury, and to repeal &#8220;An act to be entitled an act to define and punish usury&#8221; passed at the regular session of the Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />second Legislature, and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That articles 2976, 2977, 2978, 2979, and 2980, title 54, of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas, he and they are hereby so amended, and article 2981 (a) so added thereto, that the same shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 2976. On all written contracts ascertaining the sum payable, when no specified rate of interest is agreed upon by the parties to the contract, interest shall be allowed at the rate of six per cent per annum from, and after the time when the sum is due and payable.</p>
<p>Article 2977. On all open accounts, when no specified rate of inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est is agreed upon by the parties, interest shall be allowed at the rate of six per cent per annum from the first day of January, after the same are made.</p>
<pb n="369" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Article 2978. The parties to any written contract may agree to and stipulate for any rate of interest not exceeding ten per cent per annum on the amount of the contract.</p>
<p>Article 2979. All written contracts whatsoever, which may in any way, directly or indirectly, violate the preceding article by stipulating for a greater rate of interest than 10 per cent per annum, shall be void and of no effect for the amount or value of the interest only; but the principal sum of money or value of the contract may be received and recovered.</p>
<p>Article 2980. All judgments of the several courts of this state shall bear interest at the rate of six per cent per annum from and after the date of the judgment, except where the contract upon which the judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment is founded bears a specified interest greater than six per cent per annum and not exceeding ten per cent per annum, in which case the judgment shall bear the same rate of interest specified in such contract and after the date of such judgment.</p>
<p>Article 2981a. If usurious interest, as defined by the preceding ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticles, shall hereafter be received or collected, the person or persons paying the same, or their legal representatives, may by action of debt, instituted in any court of this state having jurisdiction thereof, within two years after such payment, recover from the person, firms or corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration receiving the same, double the amount of the interest so received or collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. &#8220;An act to be entitled an act to define and punish usury,&#8221; passed at the regular session of the Twenty-second Legislature, and all other laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact, that the laws of Texas regulating the rate of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest and defining usury are in great confusion and daily liable to work hardships on the people, and the necessity of putting into, immediate effect the provisions of the recent amendment to the constitution, creates an emergency and imperative public necessity that the rules requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and said rule is so suspended and it [is] so suspended [enacted].</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the house, and passed the same by a two-thirds vote&#8212;ayes 85, noes 6; and passed the senate April 9, 1892&#8212;vote not given.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">INJURIES RESULTING IN DEATH&#8212;ACTIONS FOR.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends article 2899 R. S. as amended by act of March 25, 1887. Article 2899. When damages for injuries resulting in death may be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />covered.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 7.&#8212;[H. B. No. 20.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 2899 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas as amended by an act entitled &#8220;An act to amend article 2899 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas in relation to the recovery of damages for injuries resulting in death,&#8221; passed by the Twentieth Legislature and approved March 25, 1887.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That article 2899 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 2899. An action for actual damages on account of injuries causing the death of any person may be brought in the following cases:</p>
<pb n="370" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>1. When the death of any person is caused by the negligence or care<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lessness of the proprietor, owner, charterer, hirer of any railroad, steam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />boat, stage coach, or other vehicle for the conveyance of goods or pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sengers, or by the unfitness, negligence or carelessness of their servants or agents; when the death of any person is caused by the negligence or carelessness of the receiver or receivers or other person or persons in charge or control of any railroad, their servants or agents, and the lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bility of receivers shall extend to cases in which the death may be caused by reason of the bad or unsafe condition of the railroad or machinery or other reason or cause by which an action may be brought for damages on account of injuries, the same as if said railroad were being operated by the railroad company.</p>
<p>2. When the death of any person is caused by the wrongful act, negligence, unskilfulness or default, of another.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact there is no law in force authorizing suits for damages for injuries resulting in death received on railroads in the hands of receiver&#8217;s, creates an emergency and imperative public necessity which requires that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so suspended and this act shall take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing bill originated in the house and passed the same by a two-thirds vote&#8212;ayes 93, noes 2; and passed the senate by a two thirds vote&#8212;ayes 2-3, noes l.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">ALIENS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. No alien to own lands except as herein provided.</p>
<p>2. Does not apply to present owners nor bona fide inhabitants; aliena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; naturalized citizens may hold real estate.</p>
<p>3. Aliens may enforce liens on land.</p>
<p>4. Non-resident aliens may hold land for ten years; minors, etc.</p>
<p>5. Conveyances to evade the law are void.</p>
<p>6. Escheat proceedings.</p>
<p>7. Judicial sales; proceeds.</p>
<p>8. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>9. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 8.&#8212;[S. H. B. Nos. 22, 23 and 31.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to limit and regulate the own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ership by aliens of real estate in the State of Texas, and to provide for the escheat of lands held contrary to law, and to repeal all laws in conflict with this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That no alien or person who is not a citizen of the United States shall acquire title to or own any land in the State of Texas except as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall not apply to land now owned in this state by aliens so long as it is held by the present owners, nor to any alien who is or shall become a bona, fide inhabitant of the State of Texas; and any alien who is or shall become a bona fide inhabitant of the State of Texas, shall have the right to acquire and hold lands in this state upon the same terms as citizens of the State of Texas, during the continuance of the bona fide residence of such alien in this state; provided, that if any such resident alien shall cease to be a bona fide inhabitant of this state, then such alien shall have ten years from the time he cases to be such bona fide inhabitant, in which to alienate such lands This act shall not be construed to prevent any persons no citizens of the United States from acquiring or holding lots or parcels of lands in any incorporated or platted city, town or village in this<pb n="371" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>state; provided further, that any alien who shall become an actual resident of this state, and shall, in conformity with the naturalization laws of tire United States, have declared his intention to become a citizen of the United States, shall have the right to acquire and hold real estate in this state in the same manner as if he was a citizen of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall not prevent aliens from acquiring lands, or any interest therein, in the ordinary course of justice in the collection of debts; nor from acquiring liens upon real estate, or any interest therein, nor from lending money and securing the same upon real estate, or any interest therein; nor from enforcing ary such lien, nor from acquiring and holding title to such real estate, or any interest therein, upon which a lien may have heretofore or may hereafter be fixed, or upon which a loan of money may have been heretofore or hereafter may be made and secured.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. All non-resident aliens who may hereafter acquire rear estate in Texas by devise, descent or by purchase, under the provisions of this act may hold the same for ten years; provided, that any such non-resident alien, if a minor, may hold such real estate for ten years from the time of reaching his or her majority, or if of unsound mind, for ten years after the appointment of a legal guardian.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Any alien who shall hereafter hold lands in Texas in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />travention of the provisions of this act may, nevertheless, convey the fee simple title thereof at any time before the institution of escheat proceedings as hereinafter provided; provided, however, that if any such conveyance shall be made by such alien, either to an alien or to a citizen of the United States, in trust and for the purpose and with the intention of evading the provisions of this act, such conveyance shall be null and void, and any such lands so conveyed shall be forfeited and escheat to the state absolutely.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It shall be the duty of the attorney general, or the district or county attorney, when he shall be informed or have reason to believe that lands in this state are being held contrary to the provisions of this act, to institute suit, in behalf of the State of Texas, in the district court of the county where such lands are situated, praying for the escheat of the same, on behalf of the state, as in cases of estates of per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons dying without devise thereof and having no heirs; provided, before any such suit is instituted, the attorney general, district or county attorney as the case may be, shall give ninety days notice by registered letter of his intention to sue, directed to the owner of said land or the person who last rendered same for taxes, or his agents, and to all other persons having an interest in such lands, of which the plaintiff has actual or constructive notice.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. If it shall be determined upon the trial of any such escheat proceedings that lands are held contrary to the provisions of this act, the court trying said cause shall render judgment condemning such lands and shall order the same to be sold as under execution; and the proceeds of such sale, after deducting cost of such suit, shall be paid to the clerk of such court so rendering judgment, and said fund shall remain in the hands of such clerk for one year from the date of such payment, subject to the order of the alien owner of such lands, or his heirs or legal representatives; and if not claimed within the period of one year, such clerk shall pay the same into the treasury of the state for the benefit of the available school fund of the State of Texas; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="372" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>vided, that when, any moneys shall have been paid to the treasurer as hereinbefore provided, an alien, his heirs or assigns, may recover the same from the state in the same manner provided in articles 2155, 2156, 2157, 2158, 2159 and 2163 of chapter 27, title 37, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, relating to the recovery of funds of estates of decedents by the heirs and etc, where the same has been paid into the treasury by the administrator or executor; provided that the defendant at any time before final judgment may suggest, that he has now conformed with the law, which being admitted or proved, said suit shall be dismissed on payment of costs and a reasonable attorney fee to be fixed by the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The short time of the remainder of the session of the leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature, and the large amount of business pending before the legislature, creates an imperative public necessity requiring that the constitutional rule which requires bills to be read on three several days be and the same is hereby suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PUBLIC EDUCATION&#8212;SCHOOL FUND.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. One per cent of permanent fund transferred to available fund.</p>
<p>2. Board of education to make esti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mates.</p>
<p>3. Transfer to be made by treasurer and comptroller; unsold public lands not included in estimates.</p>
<p>4. Annual cash reserve for transfer to available fund.</p>
<p>5. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 9.&#8212;[H. B. No. 14.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act carrying into effect constitutional amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to article 7, section 5, transferring annually one per cent of the perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent to the available school fund.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That one per cent of the full value of what is known, held and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trolled by the State of Texas, as the permanent school fund, shall be transferred annually hereafter to the credit of the available school fund of the state, as belonging to it, and a part of the same, and which hence<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forward shall constitute a part of the state&#8217;s available school fund and to be used and applied for the support, maintenance and benefit of the public free schools of the state, as now or hereafter may be provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted: It shall be the duty of the comptrol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler and the state treasurer to notify the state board of education of the amount to the credit of the permanent school fund on the first to the fifteenth day of July of each and every year. The said statement shall show the amount invested, in bonds, the amount of outstanding land notes, and the amount of cash on hand to the credit of the permanent school fund. Upon the receipt of this information the state board of education shall estimate one per cent of the said permanent school fund and shall issue directions to the said comptroller and state treasurer to transfer the one per cent of the permanent fund thus found to the credit of the available school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted: That it shall be the duty of the state comptroller and state treasurer, upon the receipt and delivery to them, by said board of education, of the showing and statement aforesaid, as set forth in section 2 of this act, to transfer and place to the credit<pb n="373" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>of the available school fund of the state the amount found and ascer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained by said board of education, as aforesaid, and accruing from the one per cent of the value of the permanent school fund, and trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred to the available school fund under section 1st of this act. Provided that no part or the value thereof, of the unsold public land belonging to said fund shall be included or considered by the comptroller and state treasurer in ascertaining the amount to be transferred from the permanent to the available free school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted: That it shall be the duty of the state board of education and comptroller, in the management and invest<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the permanent school fund, to provide, reserve and set apart in cash, annually, an amount sufficient of same to meet the one per cent annual transfer to the available fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The fact that the session is short, which renders it improb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />abie that this bill can be considered in three several days, and that it is desirable and proper that this bill should go into effect at once, cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ates an emergency and an imperative public necessity for the suspen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the constitutional rule, requiring bills to be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days, and said rule is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the house, and passed the same by a vote of ayes 64, noes 32, and passed the senate April 11, 1892 &#8212;vote not given.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">GUARDIAN AND WARD&#8212;SALES.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Adds articles 2589a and 2589b to Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vised Statutes, and amends arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cles 2578 and 2581.</p>
<p>Article 2578. Sales may be wholly or partly for cash, and public or pri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vate.</p>
<p>Article 2581. Terms of sale when made partly on credit; notes, etc.</p>
<p>Article 2589a. Real estate may be mortgaged, when.</p>
<p>Article 2589b. Renewal of evidences of debt, when allowed.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 10.&#8212;[S. B. No. 23.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend articles 2578 and 2581 of chapter ten (10) of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, and to add thereto article 2589a, providing for a hypothecation of lands belonging to an estate in the hands of a guardian, and article 2589b, providing for the novation of existing indebtedness of estates in guardianship.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That articles 2589a and 2589b be added to chapter ten (10) of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, and that articles 2578 and 2581 of said chapter 10 be amended so as to read as hereinafter set forth:</p>
<p>Article 2578. A sale of real estate may be ordered by the court for cash, or for part cash and part credit, or wholly on credit, and if wholly on credit then for no longer period than twelve months, at public auc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or at private sale as it may appear to the court to be most to the advantage of the estate.</p>
<p>Article 2581. The terms of sale of real estate when made partly on credit shall be that the cash payment be not less than one-fifth of the purchase price, and that the purchaser give his note or notes for the deferred payments maturing in equal annual amounts, the last note to mature not later than five years from date of deed, said notes to bear interest from date at a rate of interest of not less than six (6) per cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tum payable annually, and in default of the payment of principal or<pb n="374" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>interest or any part thereof when due: shall mature the whole debt; all notes for deferred payments to he secured by vendor&#8217;s lien, retained in deed and notes upon the property sold, except where improved prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty or timbered lands are sold, in which exceptions the cash payment shall not be less than one-third of the appraised value of the property so sold. If a sale be made wholly for credit the purchaser&#8217;s note must be secured by vendor&#8217;s lien upon the property sold, and he shall also be required to furnish good personal security in addition to said lien, and the rate of interest shall not be lower than is provided in case of sales for part credit, and in every case the deferred payments shall be made payable in the county where the guardianship is pending.</p>
<p>Article 2589a. Should an estate in the hands of a guardian be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />volved in debt, and upon proper showing made to the court it shall appear that the guardian can pay off and discharge existing debts to the advantage of the estate by the hypothecation or mortgage of real estate at a lower rate of interest; or upon more advantageous terms than the old indebtedness, the court may, in its discretion, by order made for that purpose, allow the guardian to pay off and discharge existing debts by the execution of a good and sufficient mortgage or deed of trust upon real estate to secure the person furnishing the money with which to discharge said indebtedness. Acts of guardians under this article to be reported to the court and approved as in case of sales. Nor shall any guardian renew any indebtedness or evidence thereof except by order of the court made upon application and notice as in case of sales of land.</p>
<p>Article 2589b. Should a guardian not have sufficient funds in hand belonging to the estate of his ward to pay and discharge any existing debt, he may renew the evidence of the same in like manner as his ward could were he able to act, and such act of the guardian shall have the same force and effect with reference to such novated paper as if done by the ward. Provided, no such order shall be made if any creditor of said ward interpose any objection to the same before said order is granted. Provided, that no such guardian shall renew the evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dences of any debt against the estate of his ward which shall become barred by the statutes of limitations, nor shall such guardian renew the evidences of any debt that may have been made or contracted by his ward during his minority or other disabilities.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that the law upon the subject of guardian and ward is in a most unsatisfactory condition, and that the enactment of a law providing for the amendments herein set out is of great import<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance, creates an emergency and imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the senate, and passed the same April 9, 1892, and passed the house April 11, 1892&#8212;vote not given.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="375" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">LIVE STOCK&#8212;PROTECTION OF.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. County judge on affidavit made, to order examination of animals; oath of inspectors.</p>
<p>2. Reports to county judge; duty of inspectors.</p>
<p>3. Condemned animals to be killed.</p>
<p>4. Payment for animals killed; sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iff&#8217;s fees.</p>
<p>5. Penalty for riding or driving in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fected animal on public highway.</p>
<p>6. This act is cumulative.</p>
<p>7. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 11.-[H. B. No. 27.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prevent the spread of glanders and farcy among horses and other live stock in this state, and to provide a penalty for driving, riding or leading any animal infected with such diseases along or across any public highway in this state knowing them to be so infected, or permit such to run at large.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That if at any time it shall come to the knowledge of any county judge of any county in this state, by affidavit of any credible citizen of his county, stating that affiant has reason to believe and does believe that glanders or farcy exists among any horses, mules, jacks or jennets in said county, naming owner or owners of such animal or animals so in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fected, if known, if unknown so stating, it shall be the duty of such county judge, upon the filing of said affidavit, to immediately appoint three disinterested and intelligent citizens of said county, whose duty it shall be to carefully and minutely examine said animal or animals so reported to be diseased with glanders or farcy; said three citizens before entering upon the duties required of them by this act, shall take an oath before some officer legally qualified to administer oaths, that they will discharge their duties as prescribed by this act in a fair and impartial manner.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. If, after carefully and minutely examining the animal or animals so reported to be affected with glanders or farcy, said three citizens shall be of the opinion that the animal or animals so examined by them are diseased with glanders or farcy, they shall condemn the same and it shall be their duty to appraise such animal or animals at their just and full value at the time of such examination and condem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation, and shall forthwith report their action in writing to the county judge, giving in said report the number of animals condemned, if any, the owner or owners of same if known, and if unknown so stating it, with the appraised value of same. But if the said citizens have any rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonable doubt as to the diseased animals being affected with glanders or farcy, before condemning as above provided for, they shall require the owner or owners to have said diseased animals separated from con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tact with all other animals subject to contagion, for a reasonable time, and when they are fully satisfied that the disease is glanders or farcy, then they shall proceed to condemn and destroy said animals as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in this section.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The county judge, upon the receipt of the report named in section 2 of this act, shall issue his order to the sheriff or any consta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble of his county commanding him to seize said diseased animal or animals and take same to some secluded place and kill them and bury or burn the carcass.</p>
<p>See. 4. After the said diseased animal or animals are killed, as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in section 3 of this act, it shall be the duty of the county clerk, upon the written order of the county judge, to issue a warrant or war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants of the county, payable out of the general revenue, in favor of the owner or owners of said animal or animals so killed, for the amount of the value, as diseased, if the animal has any value, as appraised<pb n="376" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>by said citizens who examined and condemned same. The sheriff or constable killing, burning or burying said animal or animals shall be paid by the county such sum as the commissioners&#8217; court thereof may determine their services worth.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Any person who may drive, lead or ride any animal infected with said diseases of glanders or farcy, knowing them to be so infected, on, along or across any public highway in this state, or allow any such animal so diseased (knowing them to be so diseased and owning such animal) to run at large on the open range of any county in this state, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in any sum not less than ten dollars nor more than two hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act does not repeal any law now in force for the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention of glanders or farcy, but is cumulative thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Whereas, there is now no existing law to protect the live stock of this state from the spread of the diseases of glanders and farcy, an imperative public necessity and emergency exists, requiring that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and it is hereby suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">LIENS&#8212;MECHANICS, ETC.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Repeals section 17, act of April 5, 1889.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 12.&#8212;[H. B. No. 47.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to repeal section seventeen of an act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the speedy and efficient enforcement of the liens of mechanics, contractors, sub-contractors, builders, laborers, and material men, and to repeal all existing laws and parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act,&#8221; approved April 5, 1889.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section seventeen of the above entitled act, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The shortness of the present session of tins legislature, the vast amount of business now pending before the legislature, and the crowded condition of the calender of same, creates and there exists an imperative public necessity requiring that the rule requiring that bills be read on three several days be and the same is hereby suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="377" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">ELECTIONS&#8212;REGISTRATION.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Registration in cities of 10,000 inhabitants or more on petitton of 500 citizens.</p>
<p>2. No elector shall vote without registering.</p>
<p>3. Information to be given the registrar.</p>
<p>4. Appointment of registrar; term of office.</p>
<p>5. Duty of registrar.</p>
<p>6. Oath of office; certificate of appointment.</p>
<p>7. Appointment of deputies.</p>
<p>8. Registration books.</p>
<p>9. Place of registration; notice.</p>
<p>10. Fees of registrar.</p>
<p>11. Books and stationery.</p>
<p>12. Books and certificates shall show what (See Sec, 17.)</p>
<p>13. List of registered voters to be furnished managers of elections.</p>
<p>14. Penalty for illegal registration.</p>
<p>15. Registrar authorized to administer oaths; penalty for false swearing.</p>
<p>16. Registrar may demand proof of right to register.</p>
<p>17. Certificates to show what; to be presented to judges of election.</p>
<p>18. Voted certificates, how marked and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served.</p>
<p>19. List of registered voters to be delivered to county clerk or city secretary; how pre served.</p>
<p>20. Evidence required in case of lost certificate.</p>
<p>21. Who are entitled to register.</p>
<p>22. Penalty for issuing illegal certificates.</p>
<p>23. Arrangement of voting booths.</p>
<p>24. Ballots, how prepaired and furnished.</p>
<p>25. Same.</p>
<p>26. Not more than one person at one time to occupy a compartment.</p>
<p>27. Judges may prepare ballots when voter is unable to write.</p>
<p>28. Electioneering at polls, removing or marking of ballots, etc., prohibited; penalty.</p>
<p>29. Other offenses declared and penalty pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed.</p>
<p>30. Cities may adopt methods to protect the purity of the ballot box.</p>
<p>31. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>32. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 13.&#8212;[H. B. No. 10.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the registration of all votes in all cities containing a population of ten thousand, inhabitants or more, and to protect the purity of the ballot in said cities, and to provide penalties for the violation of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That in all cities in this state having a population of ten thousand in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants or more, to be determined by the last; United States decennial census, or by a census provided for by the commissioners court of the county where said election is to be held, there shall, upon the petition of five hundred citizens of such city, be, prior to each general election, either state, county or municipal, had a registration of all voters in said city in the manner hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Each qualified elector of such city, under the constitution and laws of this state, shall be entitled to register; but no elector of such city who fails to register under the provisions of this act shall vote at any state, county, or city election for which registration is had under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Each person, offering to register under the provisions of this act shall give to the registrar hereinafter provided for, under oath if demanded, the following information, to-wit: His name, the street and number of his place of residence, the number of the ward in which he resides, and such other information touching his qualification as a voter in the city as may be necessary to establish his right to registra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion. Should the place of his residence not be numbered, then he shall give such description of his place of residence as will enable the same to be correctly located.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. There shall be appointed by the commissioners&#8217; court of each county in which there is located a city having a population of ten thousand inhabitants or more, one registrar of all the voters of each such city in said county, who shall be a qualified elector of the city, and shall hold his office for two years, and until his successor shall have been appointed and qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. It shall be the duty of the registrar provided for in the preceding section, to register all the qualified electors of such city as is hereinafter provided, and to do and perform all other duties required of him by the provisions of this act.</p>
<pb n="378" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. Said registrar shall when appointed, and before entering upon his duties as such, take and subscribe before some officer author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized by law to administer oaths, the oath of office prescribed by the state constitution for all state and county officers; which said oath of office shall be filed with the county clerk of the county in which such registrar is appointed. Upon the filing of said oath of office with the county clerk as herein provided, the county clerk shall issue to said registrar a certificate of his appointment and qualification, which said certificate shall be sufficient authority for the said registrar to do and perform all the official duties herein prescribed and required.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said registrar shall have authority to appoint and employ as many deputies, or assistants, who shall be qualified electors of said city, as may be necessary to the prompt and efficient discharge of his official duties; provided, there shall be appointed one deputy from each political party, if demanded by the chairman of the county executive committee of the party in said county two days prior to the opening of the registration books as in [is] hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Said registrar shall open the books of his office for the reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istration of all the voters in the city, on the first Tuesday of the month preceding and prior to the month in which the election is held for which registration is required under the provisions of this act; and said registrar shall keep the same open for the registration of voters for twenty consecutive days, Sunday excluded, from 8 a. m. till 8 p. m. of each day and no longer.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Said registrar shall keep his office during the registration of the voters, in some convenient room or place; notice of the time and place of each registration of voters shall be given in some daily news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper published in said city, for at least five consecutive days prior to the day of beginning such registration and during the time, of such registration. But should there be no daily newspaper published in the said city, then notice may be given by printed hand bills, posted through<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out the city for five consecutive days prior to the beginning of the reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istration and during the time of such registration. The publication of which notice shall be paid for in all state and county elections by the commissioners&#8217; court of the county, out of the general revenue fund of said county; and for all city elections, by the city council, out of the general revenue funds of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The registrar shall receive as compensation in full, for all services herein required, eight cents for each certificate of registration issued, to he paid in all state and county elections by the commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers&#8217; court of the county out of the general revenue funds of the county; and in all city elections, by the city council of the city, out of the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral revenue funds of the city. Upon the completion and delivery of the work as hereinafter provided, to the county clerk in all state and county elections, and to the city secretary in all city elections, the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners&#8217; court, or the city council, as the case may be, shall cause to be issued to the registrar a warrant on the treasurer for the full amount due on said work as herein provided, which shall be full com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation for all services performed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The commissioners&#8217; court shall furnish and supply the registrar with all necessary books, stationery and blank certificates of registration, and an office in which to perform all the necessary work of registration during the time he is necessarily engaged in the regis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="379" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>tration of voters as herein provided; but in all city elections the city council shall furnish and supply them.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. The registrar&#8217;s books shall contain a list of all registered voters of the city, with the number of the certificate issued written op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posite the name of the holder of the certificate, and the number of the ward in which the voter resides, and shall also indicate the color, or nationality of the holder of the certificate, or such other information as will enable the judges of election to determine the identity of the holder of the certificate, and shall also show the street and number of the resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence of the voter, or such other information as will enable his place of residence to be correctly located.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The registrar shall make a list of all the registered voters of his city for the use of the managers of the election of each ward in the city, which list shall be a true copy of his hooks as is required and provided for in section 12 of this act, which said lists shall be made out and filed with the county clerk, or city secretary as the case may he, at least five days prior to the day of election, which said lists shall then he furnished the presiding officer of the election of each ward in the city, as other election papers are furnished such presiding officers of election.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Any person who shall illegally register as a qualified voter of any city under the provisions of this act, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and upon conviction in any court of competent jurisdiction, shall be punished by confinement in the penitentiary for not less than one year, nor for more than two years.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. The registrar herein provided for is hereby authorized and empowered to administer all necessary oaths to applicants for registra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and also to all witnesses touching the qualifications of applicants for registration, and any person who shall swear falsely about his own quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fications as a voter of the city, or any person who shall, as a witness for the applicant for registration, swear falsely about the qualifications of such applicant, shall be deemed guilty of false swearing, and upon con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction in any court of competent jurisdiction, shall be punished as is provided by law for the punishment of false swearing in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Should the registrar have doubts, or not be satisfied as to the qualifications of the applicant for registration, he may, in addition to the oath of the applicant for registration, demand proof of the right of such applicant to register, before he shall issue to such applicant a certificate of registration; which proof shall consist of the sworn testi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mony of two well known citizens of the city, if demanded. Which oath or oaths shall be sworn and subscribed to by the applicant and by each of his witnesses separately, and the said oaths shall be filed and kept as a part of the records of the registrar&#8217;s office.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Each person who shall register under the provisions of this act shall receive a registration certificate, which shall be numbered to correspond with the number of registered certificates issued, and which shall in addition to the name of the holder, be dated and signed by the registrar, which certificate shall be preserved and presented to the judges of the election, and should the person presenting such certificate not cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />respond with the description of the person to whom issued, as appears on the registrar&#8217;s books, then he shall not vote until he shall have satisfied the judges of the election of his right to vote.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Each certificate of registration when presented and voted,<pb n="380" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>shall have stamped or written thereon, by one of the judges of election, the word &#8220;Voted.&#8221; No certificate shall be voted unless it corresponds with the name and number on the list of registered voters herein pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for, and the holder shall correspond with the other information contained on the list of registered voters furnished the managers of the election as herein provided, or that the judges of the election are satis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied that the holder of the certificate is the person to whom it was issued; and when voted, one of the judges of the election shall write or stamp opposite the name of the holder, the word &#8220;Voted&#8221; on the list. And when a certificate has been voted it shall be considered as exhausted, and shall be placed by one of the judges of the election in a closed box, and when the election is closed said box and contents shall be sealed up and deposited with the county clerk or city secretary, as the case may be, after having been labeled &#8220;Registered Certificates,&#8221; and said box and contents shall be preserved by the said clerk or city secretary as is provided by law for the preservation of the ballots of the election.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. The list of registered voters shall at the close of the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion be placed by the managers of the election in the envelope cover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the returns to be delivered to the county clerk or city secretary as is provided by law, and shall be preserved by such officer in the same manner as is provided for the preservation of election returns thus made.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. Any person offering to vote in a city at any election for which registration has been had of all the voters of such city, shall not vote unless he presents a certificate of registration, as herein provided, or in case he has lost or mislaid his certificate, he shall so state, and if his name shall appear on the registered list, and he is known to the judges to be the person whose name thus appears on the registered list, or can furnish satisfactory evidence that he is the person whose name appears on the said list, then he shall be entitled to vote, provided the certificate has not been previously voted, in which case he shall not vote; and, provided further, that when any person does vote with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out presenting his certificate of registration as herein provided, then one of the judges or managers of the election shall stamp or write op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posite his name on the registration list, the words &#8220;Voted. Certificate lost,&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 21. Every male person who shall have become of the age of twenty-one (21) years by the clay of election, and shall be otherwise a qualified elector, or shall have become a qualified voter of the city by the clay of the election for which the registration is made, and is a bona fide citizen of the city in which he offers to register, shall be enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to register as a qualified voter of the city, provided he shall estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish the same as is herein provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. Any registrar who shall knowingly issue a registration certificate to any person not legally entitled to register under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, or who shall knowingly issue, or cause to be issued, a certificate of registration to any imaginary or fictitious person, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and upon conviction in any court of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent jurisdiction shall be punished by confinement in the penitentiary for not less than one year, nor more than two years, for each and every such registration certificate so issued.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. The following safeguards and regulations shall be ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served to secure the voter from interference while casting his ballot<pb n="381" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>at said elections, to-wit: The polling places in the several precinct [s] in the city shall be provided with a guard rail, so constructed and placed that only such persons as are inside said rail can approach within six feet of the ballot boxes or compartments or booths at which electors are to prepare their ballots for voting. The arrangements shall be such that neither the ballot boxes, or the voting booths or the electors while preparing their ballots shall be hidden from view of those just outside of the said guard rail or from the judges; and yet the same shall be far enough removed and so arranged that the elector may conveniently prepare his ballot for voting with secrecy. There shall be provided in each polling place not less than one such compartment or booth for every fifty electors to vote at such polling place; and every polling place shall have at least three of such compartments or booths which shall be made with three sides closed and the front side open and in size 32 inches wide, 32 inches deep, and 6 feet 4 inches high, containing a shelf, and shall be arranged with hinges to fold up when not in use, convenient for storage. The county judge, county clerk, and sheriff of each county shall constitute a board, a, majority of whom may act, to provide the voting booths or compartments and guard rails required by this act. When said appliances have been provided, said board shall file with the county commissioners court a written report of their action, giving a detailed statement of the expenses incurred in providing said booths and guard rails, and it shall be the duty of said court to certify to the comptroller of public accounts the amounts due and to whom due and the number of booths and feet of guard rails provided. Upon receipt of said certificate the comptroller shall issue his warrant upon the state treasurer in favor of the parties to whom said account is due for one-half of said amount and the same shall be paid out of the state treasurer [treasury] and the residue thereof shall be paid by the res<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pective counties. During the election and counting of ballots, no per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son other than the judges and clerks of elections, and the electors, ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted as herein provided for the purpose of providing their ballots and voting, shall be admitted or permitted to be within said rail.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. All ballots used by the voters at said elections shall be furnished by the officers conducting said election upon which shall be printed the names of all candidates for state, county, precinct, or city officers [offices] upon one ticket and arranged according to the respective parties to which the candidates may belong, and whenever a voter has been furnished with a ballot by any officer conducting the election the presiding officer shall stamp with a rubber stamp provided for this purpose the words &#8220;Official ballot&#8221; and no ballot cast without said words stamped upon it by the said presiding officer shall be counted at said election.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. All ballots used at any election shall be upon substantially the same character of paper which shall be white and any candidate shall have the right to have ballots printed such as are named in the preced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing section which he must furnish to the presiding officer at least one day before the day of the holding of the election.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. Not more than one person shall at one time be permitted to occupy any one compartment or place provided for electors to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pare their ballots, except when an elector is unable to prepare his ballot he may [be] accompanied by the two judges to assist him, and<pb n="382" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>no person shall remain in or occupy any such compartment longer than may be necessary to prepare his ballot.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. Any elector who declares to the presiding officer that he cannot read or write or that by blindness or other physical disability he is unable to prepare his ballot, shall upon request receive the assist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of two of the judges in the preparation thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. Any officer upon whom a duty is imposed by this act, who shall disclose to any person the name of any candidate for whom any elector has voted or gives any information by which it can be ascer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained for whom any elector has voted, or any judge or clerk of election or other officer about the polls who shall do any electioneering on elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion day, or any person who shall do any electioneering on election day within any polling place or within thirty feet of any polling place, or any person who shall remove any ballot from any polling place, or any person who shall knowingly apply or receive any ballot in any polling place other than that in which he is entitled to vote, or any person who shall show his ballot after it is marked to any person in such a way as to reveal the contents thereof, or the name of the candidate or can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />didates for whom he marked his ballot, or any person who shall, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary to this act, examine his ballot or solicit the voter to show the same, or person other than an officer of election who shall deliver any ballot to an elector, or any elector who shall deliver a ballot to the presiding officer to be voted, except the one he received from the election officer, or any elector or any one who shall, contrary to the provisions of this act, place any mark upon or do anything to his ballot by which it may afterward be identified as the one voted by any particular individual, upon conviction shall be punished by a fine not less than fifty dollars and not more than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment in the county jail not less than three months nor more than one year or both, in the discretion of the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. Any judge or clerk of election who shall wilfully disre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gard any of the provisions of this act, or who shall negligently fail to enforce any of the provisions of this act or who shall, in counting the ballots or making the returns thereof, wilfully disregard any of the directions or requirements of this act, or any person who shall wilfully alter or destroy any ballot cast at an election or any of the returns of an election regulated by this act, or who shall introduce among the genuine ballots a fraudulent ballot, or any person who shall falsely write the initials of the presiding officer or any writing upon the ballot purporting to be written by the clerk or presiding officer, or any person who shall steal any of the ballots or returns, or wilfully or fraudulently hinder or delay the delivery of any election returns to the county clerk, or wilfully break open any of such sealed returns of any election regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated by this act, upon conviction shall be punished by imprisonment in the penitentiary not less than one year nor more than three years, or by fine of not less than five hundred dollars, nor more than two thousand dollars, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. Cities containing a population of ten thousand inhabitants or more may through their city councils adopt such methods not in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consistent with this act to protect the purity of the ballot in elections held at their municipal elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed, in so far as they conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<pb n="383" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>See. 32. The importance of preserving the purity of the ballot box, and limited time allotted this session of the legislature for the consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration of the business before it, creates an imperative public necessity which justifies the suspension of the constitutional rule which requires bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SUPREME COURT.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends certain articles in title 39 of Revised Statutes.</p>
<p>Article 1002. Election and tenure of office of juderes.</p>
<p>Article 1005. Term of court.</p>
<p>Article 1011. Appellate jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Article 1011a. Writs of error, when granted.</p>
<p>Article 1011b. Petition for writ of error, requisites of; bond.</p>
<p>Article 10011c. Writ granted when petition shows error.</p>
<p>Article 1011d. Court to make rules, etc., to carry foregoing articles into effect.</p>
<p>Article 10lle. May ascertain mat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters of fact.</p>
<p>Article 1012. May issue what writs. Article 1014. May make rules and regulations.</p>
<p>Article 1017. Clerk, appointment of; bond.</p>
<p>Article 1019. Clerk&#8217;s term of office; salary.</p>
<p>Article 1023. Clerk may appoint dep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uties; salary.</p>
<p>Article 1024. Clerk is librarian.</p>
<p>Article 1025. Duties of librarian.</p>
<p>Article 1033. Trial to be on ques<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of law.</p>
<p>Article 1039. Filing of briefs.</p>
<p>Article 1043. No reversal or dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missal for want of form.</p>
<p>Article 1044. No abatement on death of parties, when.</p>
<p>Article 1049. Judgment against plaintiff in error, and his sureties.</p>
<p>Article 1050. When judgments be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come final; issuance of mandate.</p>
<p>Article 1056. Process, how tested, directed and executed.</p>
<p>Article 1057. Judgment enforced, how.</p>
<p>Article 1058. Clerk not compelled to issue mandate until costs are paid.</p>
<p>Article 1060. Officer failing to make return.</p>
<p>2. Reporter to supreme court.</p>
<p>3. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>4. Transfer of causes to courts of civil appeals.</p>
<p>5. Records at Tyler and Galveston transferred to Austin.</p>
<p>6. Emergency clause; law takes effect on September 1, 1892.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 14.&#8212;[J. C. S. for S. B. No. 33 and H. B. No. 12.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cles numbers 1002, 1005, 1011, 1012, 1014, 1017, 1019, 1023, 1024, 1025, 1033, 1039, 1043, 1044, 1049, 1050, 1050, 1057, 1058, 1060, of the Revised. Civil Statutes of Texas, and to add articles 1011a, 1011b, 1011c, 1011d, 1011e, and to repeal articles numbers 1006, 1007, 1008, 1009, 1034, 1035, 1036, 1037, 1038, 1045, 1046, 1048, of the same title of the Revised Civil Statutes of Texas, and to provide for the transfer of cases pending in the supreme court to the court of civil appeals.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That articles, numbers 1002, 1005, 1011, 1012. 1014, 1017, 1019, 1023, 1024, 1025, 1033, 1039, 1043, 1044, 1049, 1050, 1056, 1057, 1058, 1060, title 39, of the Revised Statutes of Texas be and the same are hereby so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 1002. That the chief justice and associate justices of the supreme court shall be elected by the qualified voters of the state at a general election. The judges of said court now in office shall hold their office until the expiration of the term for which they were elected, and until their successors are elected and qualified. As soon as prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable after the election of the successors to the present incumbents, the newly elected judges shall cast lots for the term of office. That one who shall draw number one shall hold his office for two years; the one drawing number two shall hold his office for four years, and the one drawing number three shall hold his office for six years; each to hold his office until his successor is elected and qualified; and each justice of the supreme court elected thereafter shall hold his office for<pb n="384" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>six years and until his successor is elected and qualified, and shall each receive an annual salary of four thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Article 1005. The supreme court shall hold one term each year at the city of Austin, commencing on the first Monday in October of each year and may continue until the last Saturday in the next June.</p>
<p>Article 1011. That the supreme court shall have appellate juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction co-extensive with the limits of the state, which shall extend to questions of law arising in all civil cases of which the courts of civil appeals have appellate but not final jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Article 1011a. All causes shall be carried up to the supreme court by writs of error issuing from the supreme court to the courts of civil ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals upon final judgment and not on judgments reversing and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding causes except in the following cases, to-wit:</p>
<p>(1) Where the state is a party or where the railroad commissioners are parties.</p>
<p>(2) Cases which involve the construction and application of the constitution of the United States or of the State of Texas or of an act of congress.</p>
<p>(3) Cases which, involve the validity of a statute of the state.</p>
<p>(4) Cases involving the title to a state office.</p>
<p>(5) Cases in which, a civil court of appeals overrules its own de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cisions or the decision of another court of civil appeals or of the supreme court.</p>
<p>(6) Cases in which the judges of any court of civil appeals may disagree.</p>
<p>(7) Cases in which any two of the courts of civil appeals may hold differently on the same question of law.</p>
<p>(8) When the judgment of the court of civil appeals reversing a judgment practically settles the case, and this fact is shown in the peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for writ of error.</p>
<p>Article 1011b. Any party desiring to sue out a writ of error before the supreme court, shall present his petition to said court stating the names and residences of the parties adversely interested, with a brief statement of the nature of his case and the ground upon which the writ of error is prayed, and it must appear that the errors complained of arose upon questions of law, the determination of which were neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to the decision of the cause in the court of civil appeals, and that said questions was [were] properly presented to said court, and it must further appear that the supreme court would have jurisdiction thereof; and the petition shall contain such other requisites as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the supreme court. The petition must be accompanied with a certified copy of the conclusions of law and fact filed in the cause by the court of civil appeals, with the opinion thereof, together with a certified copy of the judgment in the trial court and of the bond given in the lower court, if any, and if plaintiff in error has given no bond, then the supreme court in granting the writ shall specify what bond shall be given, and the plaintiff in error shall file said bond in the trial court to be approved by the clerk of said court, and a certified copy thereof shall be at once transmitted to the supreme court, and upon the filing of said certified copy, the clerk of the supreme court shall issue citation in error as my be prescribed by the rules of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Article 1011c. If it shall appear to the supreme court from an inspection of the petition and record that there is error in said judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="385" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>ment of the court of civil appeals, it shall grant a writ of error return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble in thirty days, in such manner as may be prescribed by said court.</p>
<p>Article 1011d. The supreme court shall from time to time make and promulgate suitable forms, rules and regulations for carrying into effect the foregoing articles relating to the jurisdiction and practice of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Article 1011e. The supreme court shall have the power, upon affi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />davit or otherwise, as the court may determine, to ascertain such mat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters of fact as may be necessary to the proper exercise of its jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Article 1012. The supreme court, or any justice thereof, shall have power to issue writs of habeas corpus as may be prescribed by law; and the said court, or the justices thereof, may issue writs of mandamus, procedendo, certiorari and all writs necessary to enforce the jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said court; and in term time or vacation may issue writs of quo warranto or mandamus against any district judge or officer of the state government, except the governor of the state.</p>
<p>Article 1014. The supreme court shall have power to make, estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish and enforce all necessary rules of practice and procedure, not in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consistent with the laws, of this state, for the government of said court and all other courts of the state, so as to expedite the dispatch of busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness in said courts.</p>
<p>Article 1017. There shall be appointed for the supreme court one clerk who shall reside at the place of holding court, which appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be made by the court or the judges thereof and shall be entered of record in the proceedings of the court; and each person so appointed shall, before he enters upon the duties of his office, take and subscribe the oath prescribed by the constitution, before some officer authorized to administer oaths generally, and shall enter into a bond with two good and sufficient, sureties, to be approved by the court or judges thereof, payable to the governor and his successors in office, in the penalty of five thousand dollars, conditioned for the faithful performance of the duties of his office, and that he correctly records the judgments, decrees, decisions and orders of the said court, and deliver over to his successor in office all records, minutes, books and papers and whatever belongs to his said office of clerk, which bond and oath shall, without delay, be deposited in the office of the secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of state, and shall not be void on first recovery, but may be put in suit and prosecuted by any party injured until the amount thereof be recovered.</p>
<p>Article 1019. The clerk of the supreme court shall hold his office for the term of four years from his appointment, hut may be removed therefrom for neglect of duty or misconduct of office, by the supreme court, on motion, of which the clerk against whom complaint is made shall have ten days previous notice, specifying the particular charges of negligence or misconduct in office preferred; and in every such case, the court shall determine the law and the facts; and whenever the necessity occurs, the supreme court may appoint a clerk pro tempore. The clerk of the supreme court shall receive as compensation for his services, a salary of twenty-five hundred dollars per annum, and he shall collect and pay into the treasury of the state all fees and costs to be collected by him over and above the salaries allowed him and his deputies, under such further rules and regulations as shall be prescribed by the comptroller, not in conflict with this act: such rules and regulations to be subject to the approval of the judges of the<pb n="386" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>supreme court, to be entered of record in the minutes of said court. The supreme court shall also appoint a stenographer for said court at an annual salary of fifteen hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Article 1023. The clerk of the supreme court may appoint not more than two deputies at any time, whenever authorized to do so by a majority of the judges of the supreme court, which authority shall appear of record in the minutes of said court. Said deputies may dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge all the duties required by law of said clerk, and said deputies shall be required to give bond in the same manner and amount as the clerk of said court and to be approved by the judges of said court. Said deputies shall receive as compensation for their services such sum as shall be unanimously agreed on by the judges of the supreme court, this action to appear of record in the minutes of the court, not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed rifteen hundred dollars per annum, to be paid out of the fees collected by the clerk of said court; and the judges of the supreme court may dispense with the services of any or all of such deputies, or for any length of time whatever, as in their discretion they may deem to be to the public interest.</p>
<p>Article 1024. The clerk of the supreme court shall be librarian in charge of the library of said court.</p>
<p>Article 1025. It shall be the duty of such librarian to take charge of and keep together and in good order, and make catalogues of the books of said libraries, which shall be open to the public use under such rules as may be prescribed by the court for the safe keeping thereof; provided, the books shall not be removed from the library room except by the judges of the court and by members of the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature during the session of the legislature, upon their receipt for the same to the clerk.</p>
<p>Article 1033. In all cases of writs of error or certificates of error to the supreme court, the trial shall be only upon the question of law upon which the writ of error was allowed, or which was certified to the supreme court from a court of civil appeals; hut the supreme court may require at any time the original transcript to he sent up.</p>
<p>Article 1039. When any cause or suit may be taken to the supreme court by writ of error, the briefs and arguments filed in the court of civil appeals shall be submitted to the supreme court, and in addition thereto, the attorney for either party may file additional briefs, under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the supreme court. In cases appealed to the supreme court before the organization of the court of civil appeals, parties thereto shall not be required to file briefs in the supreme court, and shall have the time provided in the act of civil appeals for filing their briefs in the civil court of appeals after the cases have been transferred from the supreme court to the court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Article 1043. There shall be no reversal or dismissal for want of form; provided, that the requirements of the law and the rules of the court be sufficiently complied with in presenting the case to enable the court to determine the same upon its merits. In each case the supreme court shall affirm the judgment, reverse and render the judgment which the court of civil appeals ought to have rendered, or reverse the judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and remand the case to the lower court, if it shall appear that the justice of the case demands another trial.</p>
<p>Article 1044. If any party to the record, in any cause now pending in or hereafter taken to the supreme court or court of appeals, by ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="387" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>peal or writ of error, shall have died heretofore, or shall hereafter die, after the appeal bond has been filed and approved, or after the writ of error has been served, and before such cause has been decided by the supreme court or court of civil appeals, such cause shall not abate by such death, but the court shall proceed to adjudicate such cause and render judgment therein as if all the parties thereto were living, and such judgment shall have the same force and effect as if rendered in the lifetime of all the parties thereto.</p>
<p>Article 1049. Whenever the supreme court on the trial of a cause brought from any court of civil appeals, shall affirm the judgment or decree of such court, or when said court shall proceed to render such judgment or decree as should have been rendered by the court of civil appeals, and such judgment shall be for the same or a greater amount, or of the same nature as rendered in the court below, said court shall render judgment against plaintiff in error and his sureties on his bond, a copy of which shall always accompany the transcript of the record.</p>
<p>Article 1050. The judgment of said court shall be final at the expira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of fifteen days from the rendition thereof, when no motion for rehearing has been filed; and upon the rendition of final judgment, the clerk of the supreme court, upon payment of costs, shall issue the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />date in the case If for any cause the said court should set aside its judgment after the mandate has been issued, the clerk of the supreme court shall at once notify the party to whom the mandate was delivered, and the clerk of the court to which it was directed, to return it at once. All mandates from the said court shall issue to the court in which the original judgment was entered.</p>
<p>Article 1056. All writs and process issuing from the supreme court shall hear the test of the chief justice or presiding judge of said court, and be under the seal of said court and signed by the clerk thereof, and may be directed to the sheriff or any constable of any county in the state, and shall be by such officer executed according to the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand thereof, and returned to the court from which they emanated; and whenever such writs or process shall not be executed, the clerk of the said court is hereby authorized and required to issue another like process or writ upon the application of the party suing out the former writ or process to the same or any other county.</p>
<p>Article 1057. Upon the rendition by the supreme court of any such judgment or decree as is contemplated by article 1049, it shall not be necessary for the lower court from which the cause was removed to make any further order or decree therein, but the clerk of said lower court, on the receipt of the mandate of the supreme court or court of civil appeals, shall proceed to issue execution thereon as in other cases.</p>
<p>Article 1058. The clerk of the supreme court shall not deliver the mandate of the court until all costs of that court and of the court of civil appeals have been paid. If the costs have not been paid at the end of fifteen days from the date of judgment or from the overruling of a motion for rehearing, the said clerk may issue an execution for the costs of the supreme court and the court of civil appeals, specifying the amount of each, and attaching to said execution a correct list of all costs accruing in each of said courts. Said execution shall be directed to the sheriff or any constable of the county from which the cause was removed, or to any county in which the person or persons, liable under such execution, or either of them, may have property. It shall be the duty of every sheriff or constable receiving such execution to execute<pb n="388" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>and return the same under the same rules, regulations and liabilities as provided for executions from the district court.</p>
<p>Article 1060. In case any officer shall fail or refuse to make such return with the amount of such costs, if he has collected the same, within the time prescribed herein, or shall make a false or fraudulent return of any such execution, the clerk of said supreme court may issue citation returnable forthwith to such officer to appear before the said supreme court, and show cause, if any he can, why he has not collected and returned such costs and execution; and failing to show cause, said court may enter judgment against such officer and the sureties on his official bond for twice the amount of said costs, together with the cost of such proceeding. It shall be the duty of the clerk of the supreme court, when he shall receive any money due the clerk of any court of civil appeals, to pay the same over to such clerk of the court of civil appeals, and if he refuses to do so upon demand, the clerk of the said court of civil appeals may file in the supreme court a motion against the said clerk so failing, and upon ten days notice given to him the said supreme court may enter judgment against said clerk of the supreme court and the sureties on his official bond for double the amount of the costs so collected by him and due to said clerk of the court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The supreme court is authorized and required to appoint a reporter for its decisions, whose duties and compensation shall be the same as are now fixed by law, and he shall be subject to removal by the court for inefficiency or neglect or other good cause. The reporter shall be allowed such additional compensation for reporting the decisions of the civil courts of appeal as the supreme court shall deem just; and the court may appoint a bailiff to attend the sitting of the court who shall receive an annual salary of three hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That articles numbers 1006, 1007, 1008, 1009, 1034, 1037, 1038, 1045, 1046, 1048, of title 36, of the Revised Civil Statutes of Texas, be and the same are hereby repealed. All laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. All causes that may be pending in the supreme court of Texas, when the civil courts of appeals shall have been organized, shall be transferred by said supreme court to the court of civil appeals to which it would be returnable under the law organizing such courts, and shall be decided under the same rule as obtained when any such appeal was perfected. Said causes shall be accompanied by a certified copy of all orders made by said supreme court, together with a certified copy of all costs which have accrued therein; and when said cause has been finally disposed of by said court of civil appeals, the clerk of said court shall include said costs in the bill of costs accruing in said court of civil appeals, and shall collect the same at the same time and in the same manner as the costs which have accrued in the court of civil appeals, and when so collected he shall pay the same over to said clerk of the supreme court. That all bonds and obligations theretofore given in said cause to abide the judgment, sentence or decree of said court, or to pay the costs of said court, shall be deemed and held to apply to said civil court of appeals as if hereafter given under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. All records that have been finally disposed of by the supreme court, remaining at the Tyler and Galveston branches, when this act<pb n="389" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>goes into effect, shall be transferred to said court at Austin; and the supreme court shall make such orders as may be necessary to carry this law into effect, and shall allow the clerk at Austin such compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation as they may deem just and reasonable for arranging and classi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fying said records and placing them in the transcript rooms.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The fact that the present session of the legislature is limited and rapidly drawing to a close, and the importance of this bill becoming a law, creates an emergency and imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and said rule is suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after September 1, 1892.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 13, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">COURTS OF CIVIL APPEALS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Court to consist of chief justice and two associates.</p>
<p>2. Election and tenure of office.</p>
<p>3. Qualifications of judges.</p>
<p>4. Vacancies, how filled.</p>
<p>5. Appellate jurisdiction of the courts prescribed.</p>
<p>6. Power to issue writs of mandamus, etc.</p>
<p>7. May ascertain matters of fact.</p>
<p>8. May punish for contempt.</p>
<p>9. May compel district judge to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to trial.</p>
<p>10. One clerk for each court; bond; salary.</p>
<p>11. Vacancy in office of clerk, how filled.</p>
<p>12. Term of office of clerk.</p>
<p>13. Seal of the courts.</p>
<p>14. Clerks shall file and preserve tran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scripts and docket causes.</p>
<p>15. Clerks shall record proceedings, etc.</p>
<p>16. Deputy clerks; salary, bond, etc.</p>
<p>17. Clerk is librarian.</p>
<p>18. Duty of librarian.</p>
<p>19. Report of costs collected by clerk.</p>
<p>20. Transcript to be filed in ninety days.</p>
<p>21. Certificates may be filed when; af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmance on certificate.</p>
<p>22. May permit transcript to be filed after affirmance on certificate.</p>
<p>23. Docketing and hearing causes.</p>
<p>24. Trial to be on statement of facts, etc.; bills of exception.</p>
<p>25. Appellant to file assignments of error.</p>
<p>26. Filing of briefs.</p>
<p>27. Disqualification of judges.</p>
<p>28. Order of trial of cases.</p>
<p>29. No reversal or dismissal for want of form.</p>
<p>30. No abatoment on death of parties, when.</p>
<p>31. After decision, conclusion of facts and law to be filed.</p>
<p>32. Dissenting opinion to be entered of record.</p>
<p>33. When certificate of dissent is sent up, the clerk to send judgment, etc</p>
<p>34. After decision, supreme court to no<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tify court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>35. Issues of law which are novel to be certified to the supreme court.</p>
<p>36. When judgment of court below is reversed, court, shall render judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment; exceptions.</p>
<p>37. Judgment against appellant for damages, etc.</p>
<p>38. Clerk to issue mandate, when.</p>
<p>39. When bond may be amended.</p>
<p>40. A majority of the court shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum for business.</p>
<p>41. Motion for rehearing.</p>
<p>42. Duty of clerk on filing such motion.</p>
<p>43. Duty of sheriff on receiving precept.</p>
<p>44. Motion for rehearing when to be heard.</p>
<p>45. Process how tested directed and served.</p>
<p>40. Judgment enforced, how.</p>
<p>47. Clerk not compelled to issue man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />date until costs paid.</p>
<p>48. Executions returnable, when.</p>
<p>49. Officer failing to make returns.</p>
<p>50. Salary of clerks; fees to be paid into state treasury.</p>
<p>51. Courts may appoint stenographers.</p>
<p>52. Reporter to courts of civil appeals.</p>
<p>53. Notice, how given.</p>
<p>54. Emergency clause; law to take ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect September 1, 1892.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 15.&#8212;[J. C. S. for S. B. No. 32 and H. B. No. 11.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to organize the courts of civil appeals, to define their jurisdiction and powers and to prescribe the mode of procedure therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That each of the courts of civil appeals now or hereafter organized in this state shall consist of a chief justice and two associate justices, and the concurrence of two justices shall be necessary to the decision of a case.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The chief justice and associate justices of each of the courts of civil appeals shall be elected by the qualified voters of the respective districts composed of the counties returnable to the several courts at a general election. Upon their qualification, after the first election after the creation of any court of civil appeals in this state, the justices<pb n="390" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>thereof shall draw lots for the terms of office, and those drawing No. 1 shall hold their offices for the term of two years; those drawing No. 2 shall hold their offices for a term of four years, and those drawing No. 3, shall hold their offices for a term of six years from the date of their election and until their successors are elected and qualified. Each of said offices shall be filled by election at the next general election at which terms as aforesaid would expire, and the person elected shall thereafter hold his office for six years and until his successor is elected and qualified, and shall receive each an annual salary of three thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand and five hundred dollars, and no more.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. No person shall be eligible to the office of chief justice or associate justice of the court of civil appeals unless he be at the time of his election a citizen of the United States and of this state, and a resident of the district for which he is elected, and unless he shall have attained the age of thirty years, and shall have been a practicing lawyer or a judge of a court in this state, or such lawyer and judge together, at least seven years.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. In case of a vacancy in the office of chief justice or asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciate justice of any court of civil appeals, the governor shall fill the vacancy until the next general election for state officers, and at such general election the vacancy for the unexpired term shall be filled by election by the qualified voters of the district composed of counties returnable to said court.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The appellate jurisdiction of the courts of civil appeals shall extend to civil cases within the limits of their respective districts:</p>
<p>(1) Of which, the district court has original or appellate jurisdiction.</p>
<p>(2) Of which the county court has original jurisdiction.</p>
<p>(3) Of which the county court has appellate jurisdiction when the judgment or amount in controversy shall exceed one hundred dollars exclusive of interest and costs. The judgment of the courts of civil appeals shall be conclusive in all cases upon the facts of the case and a judgment of such courts shall be conclusive on facts and law in the following cases; nor shall a writ of error be allowed thereto from the supreme court, to-wit:</p>
<p>(1) Any civil case appealed from a county court or from a district court when under the constitution a county court would have had original or appellate jurisdiction to try it, except in probate matters and in cases involving the revenue laws of the state or the validity of a statute.</p>
<p>(2) All cases of boundary.</p>
<p>(3) All cases of slander and divorce.</p>
<p>(4) All cases of contested elections of every character other than for state officers, except where the validity of a statute is attacked by the decision.</p>
<p>The judgments of said courts of civil appeals shall be final in all appeals from interlocutory orders appointing receivers or trustees or such other interlocutory appeals as may be allowed by law, and the judgment of said court shall be final in all other cases as to law and facts except where appellate jurisdiction is given to the supreme court and not made final in said courts of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The said courts and the judges thereof shall have the power to issue writs of mandamus and all other writs necessary to enforce the jurisdiction of said court.</p>
<pb n="391" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. The said courts shall have power, upon affidavit or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, as by the courts may be thought proper, to ascertain such matters of fact as may be necessary to the proper exercise of their jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The said courts shall have power to punish any person for a contempt of said court, according to the principles and usages of law in like cases, not to exceed one thousand dollars fine or imprison<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment not exceeding twenty days.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The said courts, or any judge thereof, in vacation may issue the writ of mandamus to compel a judge of the district court to proceed to trial and judgment in a cause agreeably to the principles and usages of law, returnable on or before the first day of the next term, or during the session of the same, or before any judge of the said court, as the nature of the case may require.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. There shall be appointed for each of the courts of civil appeals one clerk who shall reside at the place of holding court, which appointment shall be made by the court or the judges thereof, and shall be entered of record in the proceedings of the court, and each person so appointed shall, before he enters upon the duties of his office, take and subscribe the oath prescribed by the constitution, before some officer authorized to administer oaths generally, and shall enter into a bond with two good and sufficient sureties, to be approved by the court or any judge thereof, payable to the governor and his successor in office, in the sum of five thousand dollars, conditioned for the faithful per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance of the duties of his office and that he will correctly record the judgments, decrees, decisions and orders of said courts, and deliver over to his successor in office all records, minutes, books and papers and whatever belongs to his said office of clerk, which bond and oath shall without delay, be deposited in the office of the secretary of state, and shall not be void on the first recovery but may be put in suit and prosecuted by any party injured until the amount thereof is recovered.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. If, in vacation, the office of clerk may become vacant, the appointment shall be made by the chief justice and the associates of said court, or by any one of said associates and chief justice; and the person so appointed shall give bond and take the oath as prescribed hi the preceding section, the bond to be approved by any judge of the court, which bond and oath shall be deposited in the same manner as though the appointment had been made in term time, and may be prosecuted and put in suit in like manner; copies of said bond, certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied under the hand of the secretary of state and the seal of the state, shall be received in evidence in any court in the state, in the same manner as the original would be were it presented in court; and the said appointment shall continue until regular term of the said court, and until a regular appointment shall be made.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. The clerk of each of said courts shall hold his office for a term of two years from his appointment, hut may be removed there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />from for neglect of duty or misconduct in office, by the court of civil appeals, on motion, of which the clerk against whom complaint is made shall have ten days previous notice, specifying the particular charges of negligence or misconduct in office, preferred; and in every such case the court shall determine both the law and the facts; and whenever the necessity occurs, the court may appoint a clerk pro tempore.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. It shall be duty of the clerk of each court of civil appeals to procure a seal for the use of the court, which shall have a star of<pb n="392" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>five points, with the words &#8220;Court of Civil Appeals of the State of Texas&#8221; engraved thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. The clerks of said court shall file and carefully preserve the transcripts of all records certified to said court, and all papers relative thereto, and shall docket all causes in the order in which they are filed.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. The said clerk shall faithfully record the proceedings and decisions of said court and certify their judgments to the court from which the causes were brought.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. The clerk of each court may appoint deputies, who, in the name of said clerk, may discharge all the duties required by law of said clerk, and said deputies may be required to give bonds with sureties to said clerk for the faithful discharge of their duties; which deputies shall be paid out of the fees collected by the clerk not to exceed twelve hundred dollars per annum to each deputy.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The clerk of each of said courts shall be librarian in charge of the libraries of said court, except the library at Austin, which shall be under the control of the clerk of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. It shall be the duty of such librarian to take charge of and keep together in good order, and make catalogues of the books of said library, which shall be open to the public use under such rules as may be prescribed by the court for the safe keeping thereof; provided, the books shall not be removed from the library room, except by the judges of the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. The clerks of each of the courts of civil appeals shall, within ten days after the first days in January and July, make a report under oath to said courts, showing the amount of costs collected by him during the preceding six months and al so the cases in which the same was col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected, and the disposition made of such costs. Such report shall be filed and recorded in the minutes of the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. In any appeal or writ of error as provided for in this act, the appellant or plaintiff in error shall file the transcript with the clerk of the court of civil appeals within ninety days from the perfecting of the appeal or service of the writ of error; provided, that for good cause the court may permit the transcript to be thereafter filed upon such terms as it may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. In case the appellant or plaintiff in error shall fail to file a transcript of the record, as directed in this act, then it shall be lawful for the appellee or defendant in error to file with the clerk of said court a certificate of the clerk of the district or county court in which any such appeal or writ of error may have been taken, attested by the seal of Iris court, stating the time when such appeal was perfected, or such citation was served; whereupon it shall be the duty of the court of civil appeals to affirm the judgment of the court below, unless good cause can be shown why such transcript was not filed by the appellant or plaintiff in error. If a copy of the bond accompanies such certificate of the clerk of the district or county court, the judgment shall in like manner be affirmed against the sureties on such bond.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. In all cases where the court of civil appeals shall have affirmed the judgment of the court below, under the provisions of the preceding section, said court may, at any time within fifteen days after such affirmance, permit the transcript to be filed by the appellant or plaintiff in error, and the case to be tried on its merits; provided, the appellant or plaintiff in error shall show to the court good cause<pb n="393" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>why the transcript was not filed by him in accordance with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of section 20, and shall also show to said court that he has given the appellee or defendant in error notice of his intention to apply for such permission to file said transcript; and in cases where the court shall adjourn, within fifteen days after any judgment shall have been affirmed under the provisions of the next preceding section, the court may per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit the appellant or plaintiff in error to file said transcript at such time as may be deemed proper, and have said cause tried on its merits; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, said appellant or plaintiff in error shall show good cause why said transcript was not filed as herein directed, and shall show to the court that he has given the appellee or defendant in error notice of his inten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to apply for permission to file said transcript.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. When a cause is carried to the courts of civil appeals by writ of error, it shall be docketed in the order of the date received, and the clerk shall transfer said cause to the trial docket thirty days after the same has been received and docketed; provided, that the court may upon motion of either party, of which notice shall be given to the adverse party, extend the time for placing said cause on the trial docket for good cause shown. Causes on the trial docket of said court shall be heard in the order of the date of tiling, except as hereinafter provided, unless con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued to some future time for good cause shown, and it shall be the duty of the clerk under the directions of the court to notify the parties or the attorneys of record, of the date when the cause is set for hearing.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. In all cases of appeal or writ of error to the court of civil appeals, the trial shall be on a statement of facts or agreed statement of the pleadings and proof, as agreed upon by the parties or their attorneys, or the conclusions of law and fact as the case may be, certified to by the judge of the court below; or should the parties fail to agree, then the judge of the court below shall certify the facts; or on a bill of excep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions to the opinion of the judge; or on a special verdict; or on an error in law, either assigned or apparent on the face of the record; and in the abscence of all these, the case shall be dismissed with costs alone, or with, costs and damages, at the discretion of the court. And the court shall, admit as part of the record to be examined by them in the trial of a cause every bill of exception not signed by the judge trying the cause below, upon its appearing to the satisfaction of the court that the facts are fairly stated therein; that said bill was prepared in accordance with the law governing the preparation of such bills, and that the judge trying the cause refused to sign the same; and the truth of any such bill of exceptions shall be determined by the court on the copies of the affi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />davits required by law to be made in such cases, such copies to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in and to form a part of the record transmitted to the court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. The appellant or plaintiff in error shall, in all cases, file with the clerk of the court below all assignments of error distinctly specifying the grounds on which he relies before he takes the transcript of the record from the clerk&#8217;s office; all errors not distinctly specified are waived.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. When any cause or suit may be taken up from any in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferior court to the court of civil appeals, whether by appeal, writ of error or otherwise, it shall be lawful for the attorney both for the plaintiff and defendant, to file in the papers of said suit or cause his<pb n="394" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>written brief or argument; and the said court shall be required to notice the same as if it were the personal appearance of said attorney, and shall not dismiss any suit or cause where such brief or argument of counsel is filed with the papers, for want of other or further prosecution.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. No judge of the court of civil appeals shall sit in any cause wherein he may be interested in the question to be determined, or where either of the parties may be connected with him by affinity or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sanguinity, within the third degree, or where he shall have been of coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel in the cause; and where the court, or any two of its members, shall be thus disqualified to hear and determine any cause or causes in said court, that fact shall be certified to the governor, who shall immediately com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission the requisite number of persons, learned in the law, for the trial and determination of said cause or causes.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. The cases filed in the court of civil appeals shall be decided in the order in which they are filed at each term of the court, but the following cases shall have precedence of all others in the order named:</p>
<p>(1) All cases in which the railway commission is a party.</p>
<p>(2) Cases in which the state is a party.</p>
<p>(3) Cases which shall be submitted on oral argument for all parties to the cause.</p>
<p>(4) Such other cases as the court by order or rule may direct.</p>
<p>On the call of cases the court shall set down the causes for argument for such time as the same can be heard, and notice of which shall be given to counsel as heretofore provided, and said cause shall be deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mined upon argument, or as soon thereafter as practicable, or it shall be set down for further argument hut may be postponed by order of the court to a later day in the term.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. There shall be no reversal or dismissal, on appeal or writ of error, for want of form; provided sufficient matter or substance be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in the record to enable the- court to decide the cause upon its merits; and where the court shall be of opinion that an appeal or writ of error has been taken for delay and that there was no sufficient cause for taking such appeal, then and in that case the appellant or plaintiff in error, if he be the defendant in the court below, shall pay ten per centum on the amount in dispute, as damages, together with the judgment, inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est and costs of suit thereon accruing. If in any judgment rendered in the district or county court there shall be an excess of damages rendered, and before the plaintiff has entered a release of the same in such court in the manner provided by law, such judgment shall be removed to the court of civil appeals, it shall be lawful for the party in whose favor such excess of damages has been rendered to make such release in the court of civil appeals in the same manner as such release is required to be made in the district or county court; and upon such release being filed in the said court, after revising said judgment said court of civil appeals shall proceed to give such judgment as the court below ought to have given if the release had been filed therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. If any party to the record in any cause hereafter taken to the court of civil appeals, by appeal or writ of error, or transferred from the supreme court or court of appeals, shall have died heretofore, or shall hereafter die after the appeal bond has been filed and approved, or after the writ of error has been served, and before such cause has been<pb n="395" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>decided, such cause shall not abate by such death, but the court shall proceed to adjudicate such cause and render judgment therein as if all parties thereto were still living, and such judgment shall have the same force and effect as if rendered in the life time of the parties thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. After a cause is decided in the court of civil appeals, a con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusion of the facts and law of the case shall be filed in said cause within thirty days after the decision of the same; provided, it shall not be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to file said conclusion in causes in which no writ of error will lie to the supreme court; but where a cause is reversed, then the court shall file the reasons for reversing the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. When any one of said civil courts of appeal shall in any cause or proceeding render a decision in which any one of the judges therein sitting shall dissent as to any conclusions of law material to the decision of the case, said judge shall enter the grounds of his dissent of record, and the said court of civil appeals shall upon motion of the party to the cause, or on its own motion, certify the point or points of dissent to the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. When a certificate of dissent is sent up by any court of civil appeals, it shall be the duty of the clerk to send up a certified copy of the judgment of the court below, with a certified copy of the conclusion of facts and law as found by the court, and the questions of law upon which there is a division, and the original transcript if so ordered by the supreme court; and thereupon, if the supreme court so direct, the clerk shall set down the same for argument and notify the attorneys of record.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. After the question is decided the supreme court shall imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately notify the court of civil appeals of their decision and the same shall be entered as the judgment of said court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. Whenever, in any case pending before the court of civil ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals, of which said court of civil appeals has final jurisdiction, there should arise an issue of law that is novel, or presenting a question of first impression to the court, and the court of civil appeals should deem it advisable to present the issue to the supreme court for adjudication, it shall be the duty of the presiding judge of said court to certify the very question to be decided to the supreme court, and during the pendency of the decision by the supreme court the cause in which the issue is raised shall be retained for final adjudication in accordance with the decision of the supreme court upon the issue submitted.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. When the judgment or decree of the court below shall be reversed, the court shall proceed to render such judgment or decree as the court below should have rendered, except when it is necessary that some matter of fact be ascertained or the damage to be assessed or the matter to be decreed is uncertain, in either of which cases the cause shall be remanded for a new trial in the court below.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. Whenever the court of civil appeals, on the trial of cases brought from an inferior court, shall affirm the judgment or decree of such inferior court, or when said court shall proceed to render such judgment or decree as should have been rendered by the court below and such judgment shall be for the same or a greater amount or of the same nature as rendered in the court below, said court shall render judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment against the appellant or plaintiff in error, and his sureties on the appeal bond, a copy of which shall always accompany the transcript of the record; and said court of civil appeals shall in their discretion<pb n="396" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>include in their said judgment or decree such damages, not exceeding ten per cent on the amount of the- original judgment, as the court may deem proper; and the judgment or decree of said court rendered as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated in this section shall be final.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. If no writ of error be sued out or motion for rehearing be filed within thirty days after the conclusions or decision of the court has been entered in any court of civil appeals, the clerk of the court shall, upon application of either party and the payment of all costs, issue a mandate upon said judgment; and in any cause reversed by said court the appellant shall be entitled to an execution against the appellee for costs occasioned by such appeal, including costs for the transcript, said costs to be taxed by the clerk of the said court.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. When there is a defect of substance or form in any appeal or writ of error bond, on motion to dismiss the same, for such defect, the court may allow the same to be amended by filing in said court of civil appeals a new bond on such terms as the court may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. A majority of the several courts of civil appeals shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The said courts may adjourn from day to day or for such time as may be deemed proper by the judges thereof; but if a sufficient number of the judges shall not be present at the first or any day of the term, any judge of the court, or the sheriff attending the same, may adjourn the court from time to time, until a quorum shall be in attendance, but the court shall not be finally adjourned for the term.</p>
<p>Sec. 41. Any party desiring a rehearing of any matter determined by said courts may, within fifteen days after the date of entry of the judgment or decision of the court, or the filing of the findings of fact and conclusions of law, file with the clerk of said court his motion in writing for rehearing thereof, in which motion the grounds relied upon for rehearing shall be distinctly specified and the name and residence of the counsel of the opposing party, if known, and if not known, then the name and residence of the opposing party as shown in the record; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that should the court adjourn within less than fifteen days after the rendition of the judgment, the motion may be made as [at] such time and in such manner as may be prescribed by rules to be made by the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 42. Upon the filing of such motion with the clerk of said court, he shall make a certified copy thereof and transmit the same by mail to the sheriff or any constable of the county in which the attorney or op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posing party, as the case may be, is alleged in said motion to reside, together with a precept commanding him to deliver the copy of the motion to the person named in such precept.</p>
<p>Sec. 43. Upon the receipt o-f such precept and copy of motion by the officer, it shall be his duty to deliver the copy of the motion to the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son named in said precept, if found in his county, and to return said pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept to the court from which it issued, by mail, stating thereon in what manner he executed the same, or that the party named in the precept is not to be found in his county, as the case may be.</p>
<p>Sec. 44. At any time after five days from the return of such precept served, it shall be lawful for said court to hear and determine such mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for rehearing, and not sooner.</p>
<p>Sec. 45. All writs and process issuing from the court of civil ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals shall bear the test of the chief justice or presiding judge of said<pb n="397" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>court, under the seal of said court, and signed by the clerk thereof, and shall be directed to the sheriff or any constable of any county in the state, and shall be by such officer executed according to the command thereof and returned to the court from which they emanated; and when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever such writ or process shall not be executed, the clerk of said court is hereby authorized and required to issue another like process or writ upon the application of the party suing out the former writ or process to the same or any other county.</p>
<p>Sec. 46. Upon the rendition by the court of civil appeals of any such judgment or decree as is contemplated by section 37, it shall not be necessary for the lower court from which the cause was removed to make any further order or decree therein, but the clerk of said lower court, on receipt of the mandate of the supreme court or court of civil appeals, shall proceed to issue execution thereon as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 47. On the rendition of any final judgment or decree by the court of civil appeals the clerk of said court shall not issue and deliver the mandate of the court, or certify the proceedings to the lower court, until all of the costs accruing in the cause in the court of civil appeals have been paid. If neither party shall pay the costs and take out the mandate within thirty days after the time when the same can be issued by law, then it shall be the duty of the clerk to issue execution for the costs accruing in his court against the party against whom such costs have been adjudged, and to send such execution by mail to the proper officer for collection, but he shall retain the mandate until the costs shall have been paid or collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 48. All executions for costs of the court of civil appeals, as authorized by law, shall be returned by the sheriff or constable to whom they are directed within four months from the date thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 49. In case any officer shall fail or refuse to make such return with the amount of such costs, if he has collected the same, within the time prescribed herein, or shall make a false or fraudulent return of any such execution, the clerk of said court may issue citation returnable forthwith to such officer to appear before said court and show cause, if any he can, why he has not collected and returned said costs and execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; and failing to show cause, said court may enter judgment against such officer and the sureties on his official bond for twice the amount of said costs, together with the costs of such proceeding.</p>
<p>Sec. 50. The clerk of each of the courts of civil appeals shall be entitled to a salary of twenty-five hundred dollars per annum to be paid out of the fees collected by him, and he shall collect and pay into the treasury of the state all fees and costs collected by him over and above the salary herein allowed, under such further rules and regulations not in conflict with this act as shall be prescribed by the comptroller and to be approved by the judges of each court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 51. Each court of civil appeals shall appoint one stenographer who shall discharge such duties as may be required by the court, shall be duly sworn to keep secret all matters which may come to his knowl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edge as said stenographer, shall receive a salary of twelve hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per annum, and shall each give bond with two or more sureties in the sum of five thousand dollars, payable to the State of Texas, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned for the faithful performance of the duties of said office.</p>
<p>Sec. 52. The reporter of the supreme court shall also be reporter of the court of civil appeals, and the decision [s] of said courts of civil appeals shall be published and sold by the state in the same manner as<pb n="398" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>is now provided by law for the publication and sale of the supreme court reports.</p>
<p>Sec. 53. All notices required herein to be given by the court of civil appeals to the parties or their attorneys of record in any case, shall be served by the clerk of said court transmitting said notice to said attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />neys by registered letter through the mail, properly directed. Registra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion receipts shall be filed and kept by the clerk with the record of the cause. And all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 54. The fact that the present session is rapidly drawing to a close and is limited by law, and the importance of this bill, creates an emergency, and an imperative public necessity exists that the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutional rule requiring bills to be read in each house on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted; and it is further enacted that this bill take effect and be in force on and after the 1st day of Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, A.D. 1892.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 13, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">COURT OF CRIMINAL APPEALS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Court to consist of three judges: their qualifications and salaries.</p>
<p>2. Election of judges; term of office.</p>
<p>3. Classification of judges after first election; for terms.</p>
<p>4. Vacancies, how filled.</p>
<p>5. Appellate jurisdiction prescribed. (See section 24.)</p>
<p>6. Power to issue writs.</p>
<p>7. Power to ascertain matters of fact.</p>
<p>8. Presiding judge, how chosen: process, how tested.</p>
<p>9. When judge is disqualified.</p>
<p>10. Terms of court, where held.</p>
<p>11. Appeals, to what terms returnable.</p>
<p>12. Clerks to be appointed.</p>
<p>13. Oath and bond of clerks.</p>
<p>14. Duties of clerks.</p>
<p>15. Deputy clerks.</p>
<p>16. Seal of the court.</p>
<p>17. Court reporter; salary; reports, how printed and distributed.</p>
<p>18. Reporter to return opinions to the clerk.</p>
<p>19. Transferring cases from court of appeals; duty of clerks.</p>
<p>20. Mandate of court, how directed.</p>
<p>21. Costs, when taxed against defendant.</p>
<p>22. Courts having criminal jurisdiction.</p>
<p>23. Writ of habeas corpus, when to issue.</p>
<p>24. Appellate jurisdiction prescribed.</p>
<p>25. Section 24 construed.</p>
<p>26. Appeals from district and county courts in criminal actions.</p>
<p>27. Defendant need not be personally present in this court.</p>
<p>28. Defendant in felony case to be committed to jail pending appeal.</p>
<p>29. Appeal in felony cases, to what term pros<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecuted; transcripts.</p>
<p>30. Transcript, may be filed when; sentence.</p>
<p>31. Escape of defendant is cause for dismis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sal of appeal.</p>
<p>32. Recognizance, form of.</p>
<p>33. Court will not entertain jurisdiction unless recognizance is filed.</p>
<p>34. Transcript, how forwarded.</p>
<p>35. After adjournment, clerk to make certified list of certain causes decided.</p>
<p>36. Certificate to be filed and attorney general notified.</p>
<p>37. Notice to clerk as to transcripts.</p>
<p>38. Same.</p>
<p>39. Clerk to file and docket appeals, when.</p>
<p>40. Appeals, when to be determined.</p>
<p>41. Judgment of the court, on appeal.</p>
<p>42. Reversal may be as well upon law as fact; remanding.</p>
<p>43. Duty of clerk after judgment rendered.</p>
<p>44. Mandate to be filed by clerk of lower court.</p>
<p>45. New trial.</p>
<p>46. Motion in arrest of judgment.</p>
<p>47. Defendant to be discharged where cause is dismissed.</p>
<p>48. When felony case is reversed and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manded, defendant entitled to bail.</p>
<p>49. Court of criminal appeals may make rules of procedure</p>
<p>50. Appeal in case of habeas corpus.</p>
<p>51. Defendant need not be present.</p>
<p>52. Habeas corpus, when to be heard.</p>
<p>53. Court of criminal appeals to make such order as case requires.</p>
<p>54. Judgment of court of criminal appeals conclusive.</p>
<p>55. Officer failing to obey mandate; penalty.</p>
<p>56. When appellant is detained by person other than officer</p>
<p>57. Judgment of court to be certified by officer holding defendant.</p>
<p>58. When bail bond, is required, and who shall take it.</p>
<p>59. Fees of attorney general in felony cases.</p>
<p>60. Fees of clerk in felony cases on appeal.</p>
<p>61. Fees allowed in two preceding sections, how paid.</p>
<p>62. Fees of district or county attorney.</p>
<p>63. Fees of attorney general in misdemeanor cases.</p>
<p>64. Clerk allowed fees not to exceed $2500 per annum.</p>
<p>65. What fees to be taxed against defendant.</p>
<p>66. Articles of Revised Statutes repealed.</p>
<p>67. Articles of Code of Criminal Procedure repealed.</p>
<p>68. Repealing clause as to conflicting laws.</p>
<p>69. Emergency clause; law takes effect Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember 1, 1892.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 16.&#8212;[H. B. No. 62.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to organize the court of criminal appeals of the State of Texas, to define the jurisdiction thereof, to prescribe the procedure therein, to fix the places and times of holding the terms of said court, to<pb n="399" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>repeal articles 1064, 1065, 1066, 1067, 1069, 1070, 1071, 1072, 1073, 1074, 1075, 1076, 1077, 1078, 1079, 1080, 1081, 1082, 1083, 1084, 1085, of the Revised Civil Statures of the State of Texas, to repeal articles 64, 65, 66, 67, 838, 840, 841, 843, 844, 845, 852, 853, 862, 863, 864, 665, 866, 867, 868, 869, 870, 871, 872, 876, 877, 878, 879, 880, 881, 882, 883, 885, 886, 887, 888, 889, 890, 1049, 1050, 1051, 1052, 1087, 1086, 1089, of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the court of criminal appeals shall consist of three judges, any two of whom shall constitute a quorum, and the concurrence of two judges shall be necessary to a decision of said court. Said judges shall have the same qualifications and receive the same salaries as judges of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The judges of said court shall be elected by the qualified voters of the state at a general election, and shall hold their offices for a term of six years.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. At the first session of said court after the first election of the judges thereof under this act, the terms of office of said judges shall be divided into three classes and the justices thereof shall draw for the different classes. The judge who shall draw class No. 1 shall hold his office two years from the date of his election and until the election and qualification of his successor; the judge drawing class No. 2 shall hold his office for four years from the date of his election and until the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and qualification of his successor, and the judge who may draw class No. 3 shall hold his office for six years from the date of his election and until the election and qualification of his successor; and thereafter each of the judges of said court shall hold his office for six years as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in the constitution of this state.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. In a case of a vacancy in the office of a judge of said court, the governor shall fill the vacancy by appointment for the unexpired term. The judges of the court of appeals who may be in office at the time when this act takes effect shall continue in office as judges of the said court of criminal appeals until the expiration of their term of office.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Said court shall have appellate jurisdiction co-extensive with the limits of the state in all criminal cases of whatever grade, with such exceptions and under such regulations as may be prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Said court and the judges thereof shall have the power to issue the writ of habeas corpus, and under such regulations as may be prescribed by law, issue such writs as may be necessary to enforce its own jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said court shall have power, upon affidavit or otherwise, to ascertain such matters of fact as may be necessary to the exercise of its jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The judges of said court shall choose a presiding judge for said court from their number at such times as they shall think proper, and all writs and process issuing from said court shall hear test in the name of said presiding judge and the seal of the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. When said court or any member thereof shall be disquali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, under the constitution and laws of this state, to hear and deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine any case or cases in said court, the same shall be certified to the governor of the state, who shall immediately commission the requisite number of persons learned in the law for the trial and determination of such cause or causes.</p>
<pb n="400" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 10. Said court shall hold its terms as follows:</p>
<p>A term of court shall be held in the city of Tyler, in Smith county, which shall begin on the first Monday in October in each year, and may continue until the last day of December thereafter, unless the business before it is sooner disposed of.</p>
<p>A term of said court shall be held in the city of Dallas, in Dallas county, which shall begin on the first Monday in January in each year, and may continue until the last day of March thereafter, unless the business before it is sooner disposed of.</p>
<p>A term of said court shall be held in the city of Austin, in Travis county, which shall begin on the first Monday in April in each year, and may continue until the last day of June thereafter, unless the business before it is sooner disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Appeals from the several counties shall be returnable to such terms of said court as shall be determined by said court, under the rules thereof; provided, that appeals from the several counties in the supreme judicial district in which Austin is situated shall be returnable to the term of the court of criminal appeals held in said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Said court shall appoint a clerk for each place at which it may sit, who shall hold his office for four years unless sooner removed by the court for good cause, entered of record in the minutes of said court.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Said clerk shall, before entering upon the duties of their offices, take and subscribe the oath of office prescribed by the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and shall give the same bond, to be approved by the court of crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal appeals, as is now or may be hereafter required by them, of clerks of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Said clerks shall perform as clerks of the court of criminal appeals the like duties as are now or may hereafter be required by law of the clerks of the supreme court, and shall be subject to the same liabilities as are now or may hereafter be prescribed for the clerks of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. Said clerks may appoint deputies who shall perform all the duties of said clerks and who shall be responsible to said clerks for the faithful discharge of the duties of their offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. It shall be the duty of the court of criminal appeals to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure a seal for said court at each place at which it may hold its ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions, said seals to be of the same size and design, and have a star with five points with the words &#8220;Court of Criminal Appeals of Texas&#8221; en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />graved on each of them.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. Said court is hereby authorized and required to appoint a reporter of its decisions as may be required by law to be published; said reporter may be removed by the court for inefficiency or neglect of duty; said reporter shall receive an annual salary of three thousand dollars, payable monthly, upon the certificate of the presiding judge of said court. The volumes of the dicisions of said courts shall be styled &#8220;Texas Crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal Reports,&#8221; and shall be numbered, in continuation of the present number of the Court of Appeals Reports. Said volume shall be printed and disposed of as is now or may hereafter be provided by law for the printing and distribution of the reports of the supreme court.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. As soon as the opinions are recorded, the originals, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with the records and papers in each case to be reported, shall be delivered to the reporter by the clerks of said court, who shall take<pb n="401" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>the reporter&#8217;s receipt for the same, but the reporter shall return to said clerks the said opinions, records, and papers when he shall have finished using them.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. All criminal cases pending in the court of appeals when this act takes effect, shall be transferred to the court of criminal appeals to be determined by said court as provided by law. All civil cases pend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in the court of appeals when this act takes effect, shall be transferred to the court of civil appeals having jurisdiction of the same, and it shall be the duty of the clerks of the courts of crimnal appeals to transmit the original papers and certified copies of orders of the court made in each of said cases, to the court of civil appeals to which the same is trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. When the court from which an appeal has been or may hereafter be taken, has been or shall be deprived of jurisdiction over any case pending such appeal, and when such case shall have been or may hereafter be determined by the court of criminal appeals, the mandate of said court of criminal appeals shall be directed to the court to which jurisdiction has been or may hereafter be given over such case.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. In every state case of a less grade than felony, in which an appeal is taken to the court of criminal appeals, and the judgment of the court below is affirmed against the defendant, all fees due the clerk of said court in such case shall be adjudged against the defendant and his sureties on his recognizance, for which execution shall issue as in other cases of appeal to the court of criminal appeals. Should such case be reversed by the court of criminal appeals and a new trial be had in the court below, and the defendant convicted, then the costs aforesaid in favor of the clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall be taxed by the court below against the defendant, and a certified copy of said bill of costs by the clerk of the court of criminal appeals, filed in the court be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />low, shall be sufficient to require said costs to be taxed and collected as other costs against the defendant in the court below.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. The following courts have jurisdiction in criminal actions:</p>
<p>1. The court of criminal appeals.</p>
<p>2. The district courts</p>
<p>3. The county courts.</p>
<p>4. The justices&#8217; courts and the mayors&#8217; and other courts of incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated cities and towns.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. The court of criminal appeals or either of the judges thereof, shall have original jurisdiction to inquire into the cause of the detention of persons imprisoned or detained in custody, and for this purpose- may issue the writ of habeas corpus, and upon the return thereof may re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand such person to custody, admit to bail or discharge the person im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisoned or detained, as the law and the nature of the case may require.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. The court of criminal appeals shall have appellate jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion co-extensive with the limits of the state in all criminal cases of whatever grade.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. The preceding section shall not be so construed as to em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />brace cases which have been appealed from justices', mayors&#8217; or other inferior courts, to the county court, and in which the judgment rendered or fine imposed by the county court shall not exceed one hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="402" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>lars, exclusive of cost. In such cases, the judgment of the county court shall be final.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. Appeals from judgments rendered by the district or county court, in criminal actions, shall be heard by the court of criminal ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. The defendant to a criminal action need not be personally present upon the hearing of his cause in the court of criminal appeals, but he may appear in person in cases where by law he is not committed to jail upon appeal.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. Where the defendant appeals in any case of felony, he shall be committed to jail until the decision of the court of criminal appeals can be made and received.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. An appeal in a felony case may be prosecuted immediately to the term of the court of criminal appeals pending at the time the appeal is taken, or to the first term of such court after such appeal, with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out regard to the law governing appeals in other cases; and it shall be the duty of the clerk, upon the application of either the state or the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fendant, to make out and forward without delay, to the court of crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal appeals, wherever it may be in session, or if not in session, to the clerk of said court where it will next be in session, a transcript of the case.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. The transcript may be filed in the court of criminal appeals, and the case tried and determined in said court, while the district court in which the conviction was had is yet in session; and upon an affirm<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of the judgment of conviction by the court of criminal appeals, sentence may be pronounced by the district court, at the same term at which the conviction was had, or any term thereafter.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. In case the defendant, pending an appeal in a felony case, shall make his escape from custody, the jurisdiction of the court of crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal appeals shall no longer attach in the case; and upon the fact of such escape being made to appear, the court shall, on motion of the attorney general, or attorney representing the state, dismiss the appeal; but the order dismissing the appeal shall be set aside, if it shall be made to appear that the accused had voluntarily returned to the custody of the officer from whom he escaped within ten days.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. In appeals of cases of misdemeanor the following form of recognizance shall be considered sufficient:</p>
<p>State of Texas <lb/>vs. <lb/>A...... B.......</p>
<p>No........</p>
<p>This day came into open court A...... B....... defendant in the above entitled cause, who, together with C....... D........ and E........ F........, his sureties, acknowledge themselves severally indebted to the State of Texas in the penal sum of....... dollars; conditioned that the said A....... B......., who stands charged in this court with the offense of........, and who has been convicted of said offense in this court, shall appear before this court from day to day and from term to term of the same, and not depart without leave of this court, in order to abide the judgment of the court of criminal appeals of the State of Texas in this case.</p>
<p>The amount of such recognizance shall be fixed by the court in which the judgment was rendered and the sufficiency of the security thereon shall be tested and the same proceedings had, in case of forfeiture as in other cases of recognizance.</p>
<pb n="403" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 33. The court of criminal appeals shall not entertain jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of any case in which a recognizance is required by law, unless such recognizance shall comply substantially with the form presented in the preceding section.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. As soon as a transcript is prepared the clerk shall forward the same by mail or other safe conveyance, charges paid, to the proper clerk of the court of criminal appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. The clerk shall immediately after the adjournment of the court at which appeals in criminal actions may have been taken, make out a certificate under his seal of office, exhibiting a list of all such causes which have been decided, and in which the defendant has ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed. This certificate shall show the style of the cause upon the docket, the offense of which the defendant stands accused, the day on which judgment was rendered, and the day on which the appeal was taken; which certified list he shall transmit, post paid, to the clerk of the court of criminal appeals at the proper place.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. The clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall file the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate provided for in the preceding section, and notify the attorney general that the same has been received.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. When it appears by the certificate provided for in the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding section that an appeal has been taken in any case in which the transcript has not been received by the clerk of the court criminal appeals, within the time required by law for filing transcripts in civil ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, the clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall immediately notify the clerk of the propel court by mail, that such transcript has not been received.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. The clerk receiving notification as provided in preceding section shall without delay prepare and forward another transcript of the case as in the first instance, and shall notify the clerk of the court of criminal appeals, by letter sent by mail, of the fact that such trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cript has been forwarded, and the day on which and the manner in which the same was forwarded.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. The clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall receive, file and docket appeals in criminal actions under such rules as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the court; except in cases of felony, a transcript may be filed, and the case heard and determined at any time during the term to which the appeal is taken.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. The court of criminal appeals shall hear and determine ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals in criminal actions at the earliest time it may be done with due regards to the rights of parties and a proper administration of justice.</p>
<p>Sec. 41. The court of criminal appeals may affirm the judgment of the court below, or may reverse and remand for a new trial, or may reverse and dismiss the case, or may reform and correct the judgment, as the law and the nature of the case may require. In all criminal cases by it decided, the court of criminal appeals shall deliver a written opin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ion setting forth the reason for the decision.</p>
<p>Sec. 42. The court of criminal appeals may reverse the judgment in a criminal action as well upon the law as upon the facts; but when a cause is reversed for the reason that the verdict is contrary to the weight of evidence, the same shall in all cases be remanded for a new trial.</p>
<p>Sec. 43. As soon as the judgment of the court of criminal appeals is rendered, the clerk shall make out the proper certificate of the pro<pb n="404" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>ceedings had and judgment rendered, and transmit the same by mail to the clerk of the proper court, or deliver the mandate to the defendant or his counsel when the decision is favorable to the defendant, if re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to do so, unless he is instructed by the court to withhold the mandate to any particular time.</p>
<p>Sec. 44. When the certificate of the judgment and proceedings in the court of criminal appeals shall be received by the proper clerk, he shall file the same with the original papers of the cause and note the same upon the docket of the cause [court].</p>
<p>Sec. 45. Where the court of criminal appeals awards a new trial to the defendant, the cause shall stand as it would have stood in case the new trial had been granted by the court below.</p>
<p>Sec. 46. Where the defendant&#8217;s motion in arrest of judgment was overruled, and it is decided on appeal that the same ought to have been sustained, the cause shall stand as if the motion had been sustained, unless the court of criminal appeals in its judgment direct the cause to be dismissed and the defendant wholly discharged.</p>
<p>Sec. 47. Where the court of criminal appeals reverse a judgment and direct the cause to be dismissed, the defendant, if in custody, must be discharged; and the clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall transmit to the officer having custody of defendant an order to that effect; said order shall be transmitted by telegraph or mail immediately upon the dismissal of the cause.</p>
<p>Sec. 48. When a felony case upon appeal is reversed and remanded for a new trial, the defendant shall be released from custody upon his giving bail as in other cases when he is entitled to bail, and the clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall transmit to the officer having cus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tody of the defendant an order to that effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 49. The court of criminal appeals, may make rules of procedure as to the hearing of criminal actions upon appeals; but in every case at least two counsel for the defendant shall be heard if they desire it, either by brief or by oral or written argument or by both, as such counsel shall deem proper.</p>
<p>Sec. 50. When the defendant appeals from the judgment rendered on the hearing of an application under habeas corpus, a transcript of the proceedings in the cause shall be made out and certified to, together with all the testimony offered, and shall be sent up to the court of crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal appeals for revision. This transcript, when the proceedings take place before the court in session, shall [be] prepared and certified by the clerk thereof; hut when had before a judge in vacation, the tran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />script may be prepared by any person under direction of the judge and certified by such judge.</p>
<p>Sec. 51. The defendant may not be personally present, upon the hear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of an appeal in case of habeas corpus.</p>
<p>Sec. 52. Cases of habeas corpus taken to the court of criminal ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals, by appeal, shall be heard at the earliest practicable time.</p>
<p>Sec. 53. The court of criminal appeals shall enter such judgment and make such orders as the law and the nature of the case may require, and may make such orders relative to the costs in the case as may seem right, allowing costs and fixing the amount, or allowing no costs at all.</p>
<p>Sec. 54. The judgment of the court of criminal appeals in appeals under habeas corpus shall be final and conclusive and no further appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="405" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>cation in the same case can be made for the writ, except in cases specially provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 55. If an officer holding a person, in custody fails to obey the mandate of the court of criminal appeals, he is guilty of an offense and punishable according to the provisions of the penal statutes of this state.</p>
<p>Sec. 56. If the appellant in a case of habeas corpus be detained by any person other than an officer, the sheriff shall, upon receiving the mandate of the court of criminal appeals, immediately cause the person so held to be discharged and the mandate shall be sufficient authority therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 57. The judgment of the court of criminal appeals shall be cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified by the clerk thereof to the officer holding the defendant in cus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tody, or when he is held by any person other than an officer, to the sheriff Of the proper county.</p>
<p>Sec. 58. When by the judgment of the court of criminal appeals upon cases of habeas corpus the applicant is ordered to give bail, such judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be certified to the officer holding him in custody, and if such officer be the sheriff, the bail bond may be executed before him, if any other officer he shall take the person detained before some magistrate who may receive a bail bond and shall file the same in the proper court of the proper county, and such bond shall have the same force and effect as a recognizance and may be forfeited and enforced in the same manner.</p>
<p>Sec. 59. The attorney general shall receive from the state the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing fees: 1. In each case of felony appealed to the court of criminal appeals, where the appeal is dismissed or where the judgment of the court below is affirmed, the sum of twenty dollars. 2. In the case of habeas corpus heard before the court of criminal appeals when the appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cant is charged with a felony, the sum of twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 60. The clerk of the court of criminal appeals, in every case of felony brought before such court by appeal, shall receive from the state the sum of ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 61. The fees allowed the attorney general and the clerk of the court of criminal appeals by the two preceding sections, shall be audited and paid out of the state treasury upon the certificate of the court of criminal appeals, or of any one of the judges thereof, that the same is correct.</p>
<p>Sec. 62. The district or county attorney shall be allowed the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing fees: 1. For all convictions in case of felonious homicide when the defendant does not appeal or dies, or escapes after appeal and before final judgment of the court of criminal appeals, or when upon appeal the judgment is affirmed, the sum of fifty dollars. 2. For all other con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />victions of felony, when the defendant does not appeal or dies, or es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />capes after appealing and before final judgment of the court of crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal appeals, or when upon appeal the judgment is affirmed, the sum of thirty dollars. 3. For representing the state in each case of habeas carpus where the defendant is charged with a felony, the sum of twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 63. The attorney general shall, in every conviction of offenses against the penal laws in cases of misdemeanors, when the judgment of the court below is affirmed by the court of criminal appeals, or the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peal is dismissed by said court, receive the sum of ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 64. The clerk of the court of criminal appeals shall in every<pb n="406" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>case where the judgment is affirmed, receive the sum of ten dollars; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, the entire sum such clerk shall receive as compensation for his services shall not exceed two thousand and five hundred dollars per annum; and any sum over and above that shall be paid by him to the treasury of the state, under such rules as may be prescribed by the comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to be approved by the judges of the criminal court of appeals.</p>
<p>Sec. 65. The fees named in the preceding sections shall be taxed against the defendant and collected as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 66. That articles 1064, 1065, 1066, 1067, 1069, 1070, 1071, 1073, 1073, 1074, 1075, 1076, 1077, 1078, 1079, 1080, 1081, 1082, 1083, 1084, 1085, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 67. That articles 64, 65, 66, 67, 838, 840, 841, 843, 844, 845, 852, 853, 862, 863, 864, 865, 866, 867, 868, 869, 870, 871, 872, 876, 877, 878, 879, 880, 881, 882, 883, 885, 886, 887, 888, 889, 890, 1049, 1050, 1051, 1052, 1087, 1088, 1089, of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 68. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 69. The near approach of the close of the present session, which is limited by law, and the great number of bills requiring consideration by the legislature, creates an imperative public necessity, and an emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read in each house on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted, and it is further enacted that this act take effect and be in force on and after the first day of September, A. D. 1892.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 13, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">COURTS&#8212;DISTRICT AND COUNTY. PRACTICE IN.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends articles 1377, 1380, 1386, 1389, 1391, 1394, 1396, 1400 and 1404 Revised Statutes.</p>
<p>Article 1377. Statement of facts agreed on by the parties.</p>
<p>Article 1380. Appeals and writs of error to the court of civil appeals.</p>
<p>Article 1386. Terms &#8220;appellate court&#8221; and &#8220;court below&#8221; defined.</p>
<p>Article 1387. Appeal, when and how taken.</p>
<p>Article 1389. Writ of error may be sued out, when.</p>
<p>Article 1391. Requisites of petition.</p>
<p>Article 1394. Citation in error.</p>
<p>Article 1396. Returns when citation is not served.</p>
<p>Article 1400. Cost bond on appeal or writ of error.</p>
<p>Article 1404. Supersedeas bond.</p>
<p>Article 1467a. Assignments of error to be filed, when.</p>
<p>Article 1416a. Filing of briefs.</p>
<p>2. Repeals articles 1381, 1382, 1383, Re vised Statutes.</p>
<p>3. Appeals taken and writs of error granted before this act takes ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect, when returnable.</p>
<p>4. Emergency clause; law takes effect September 1, 1892.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 17.&#8212;[J. C. S. for S. B. No. 32 and H. B. No. 13.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cle 1377 of title 29, chapter 18, and articles 1380, 1386, 1387, 1389, 1391, 1396, 1400, and 1404 of title 29, chapter 19, and to add after article 1407 another arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cle to be known as article 1407a, and to add after article 1416 another article to be known as article 1416a, of said title 29, chapter 19, of the Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes of the State of Texas, and to repeal articles 1381, 1382 and 1383, of said Revised Statutes, and providing for the disposition of certain causes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That article 1377 of title 29, chapter 18, and articles 1380, 1386, 1387, 1389, 1391, 1394, 1396, 1400 and 1404 of title 29, chapter 19, of the Revised Civil Statutes of Texas, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<pb n="407" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Article 1377. After the trial of any cause, either party may make out a written statement of the facts given in evidence on the trial, and submit the same to the opposite party, or his attorney, for inspection; if the parties or their attorneys agree upon such statement of facts, they shall sign the same, and it shall then be submitted to the judge, who shall, if he find it correct, approve and sign it, and the same shall be filed with the clerk. Where it is agreed by the parties to the suit or their attorneys of record that the evidence adduced upon the trial of the cause is sufficient to establish a fact or facts alleged by either party, the testimony of the witnesses and the deeds, wills, records or other written instruments, admitted as evidence relating thereto, shall not be stated or copied in detail into a statement of facts, but the facts thus estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished shall be stated as facts proved in the case; provided, an instru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment such as a note or other contract, mortgage or deed of trust, that constitutes the cause of action on which the petition, or answer, or cross bill, or intervention is founded, may be copied once in the statement of facts. When there is any reasonable doubt of the sufficiency of the evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence to constitute proof of any one fact under the preceding rule, there may then be inserted such of the testimony of the witnesses and written instruments, or parts thereof, as relate to such facts.</p>
<p>Article 130. An appeal or writ of error may be taken to the court of civil appeals from every final judgment of the district court in civil cases and from every final judgment in the county court in civil cases of which the county court has original jurisdiction, and from every final judgment of the county court in civil cases of which the: court has ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pellate jurisdiction, where the judgment or amount in controversy ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds one hundred dollars, exclusive of the interest and costs, and an appeal shall lie from an interlocutory order of the district court appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a receiver or trustee in any cause, provided said appeal be taken within twenty days from the entry of said order; an appeal under such cases shall take precedence in the appellate court, but the proceedings in other respects in the court below shall not be stayed during the pendency of the appeal unless otherwise ordered by the appellate court.</p>
<p>Article 1386. The term &#8220;appellate court&#8221; includes the supreme court, or court of civil appeals, having jurisdiction of a cause on appeal or writ of error. The term &#8220;court below&#8221; includes the district or county court from which such appeal or writ of error is taken.</p>
<p>Article 1387. An appeal may, in cases where an appeal is allowed, be taken during the term of the court at which the final judgment in the cause is rendered, by the appellant&#8217;s giving notice of appeal in open court within two days after final judgment or two days, after judgment overruling a motion for new trial, which shall be noted on the docket and entered of record, and by his filing with the clerk an appeal bond, where bond is required by law, or affidavit in lieu thereof, as hereinafter provided, within twenty days after the expiration of the term. If the term of the court may by law continue longer than eight weeks, the bond, or affidavit in lieu thereof, shall be filed within twenty days after notice of appeal is given, if the party taking the appeal resides in the county, and within thirty days if he resides out of the county.</p>
<p>Article 1389. The writ of error may, in cases where the same is<pb n="408" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>allowed, be sued out at any time within twelve months after the final judgment is rendered, and not thereafter.</p>
<p>Article 1391. The petition shall state the names and residences of the parties adversely interested, shall describe the judgment with suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient certainty to identify it, and shall state that he desires to remove the same to the court of civil appeals for revision and correction; where the plaintiff in error desires the issuance of a supersedeas, he shall state the facts which entitle him thereto, and pray for the issuance thereof.</p>
<p>Article 1394, The style of such citation shall be &#8220;The State of Texas/&#8217; and it shall be dated and tested by the clerk as other writs, and the date of its issuance shall be noted thereon. It shall be directed to the sheriff or any constable of the county where the defendant is alleged to reside or be, and shall command him forthwith to summon the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fendant to appear and defend such writ before the: court of civil appeals within sixty days from the date of service of said citation, stating the place of holding the same, according to the provisions of the law regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating the returns of appeals and writs of error from the county in which the judgment was rendered. It shall state the date of the filing of the petition in error, the names of the parties according to such peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and the description of the judgment as therein given. Such cita<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be made returnable within ten days from the issuance of the same if defendant resides in the county, and within twenty days if he resides out of the county.</p>
<p>Article 1396. The citation shall be returned as prescribed in article 1394, and where the same has not been served the return shall show the diligence used by the officer to execute the same, and a failure to execute it, and where the defendant is to be found, so far as he has been able to ascertain.</p>
<p>Article 1400. The appellant or plaintiff in error, as the case may be, shall execute a bond with two or more good and sufficient sureties, to be approved by the clerk, payable to the appellee or defendant in error, in a sum at least double the probable amount of the costs of the suit of the court of civil appeals, supreme court and the court below, to be fixed by the clerk, conditioned that such appellant or plaintiff in error shall prosecute his appeal or writ of error with effect, and shall pay all the costs which have accrued in the court below and which may accrue in the court of civil appeals and the supreme court.</p>
<p>Article 1404. Should the appellant or plaintiff in error, as the case may be, desire to suspend the execution of the judgment, he may do so by giving, instead of the bond or affidavit in lieu thereof, mentioned in the four preceding articles, or in addition to such bond, a bond with two or more good and sufficient sureties, to be approved by the clerk, payable to the appellee or defendant in error, in a sum at least double the amount of the judgment, interests and costs, conditioned that such appellant or plaintiff in error shall prosecute his appeal or writ of error with effect, and in case the judgment of the supreme court or the court of civil appeals shall be against him, he shall perform its judgment, sentence or decree, and pay all such damages as said court may award against him.</p>
<p>Article 1407a. The appellant or plaintiff in error shall in all cases file with the clerk of the court below his assignments of error, dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinctly specifying the ground on which he relies, before he takes the<pb n="409" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>transcript of the record from the clerk&#8217;s office, and all errors not dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinctly specified are waived.</p>
<p>Article 1416a. Not less than five days before the time of filing the transcript in the court of civil appeals, the appellant or plaintiff in error shall file with the clerk of the district court a copy of his brief, which shall be by the clerk deposited with the papers of the cause, with the date of the filing endorsed thereon, and the clerk shall forthwith give notice to the appellee or defendant in error, or his attorney of record, of the filing of such brief, and that in twenty days after such notice the appellee or defendant in error shall file a copy of his brief with the clerk of said court below, and with the clerk of the court of civil appeals four copies.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That articles 1381, 1382 and 1383, of the Revised Civil Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all appeals and writs of error taken and perfected from any district or county court to the supreme court or court of appeals be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the taking effect of this act, shall be returnable to the courts of civil appeals under the provisions of this act, and shall be decided under the same rules as if they had been so perfected after this law shall take ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The fact that the present session is rapidly drawing to a close, and is limited by law, and the importance of this bill creates an emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency, and an imperative public necessity exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read in each house on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted, and it is further enacted that this bill take effect and be in force on and after the 1st day of September, A. D. 1892.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 13, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SUPREME JUDICIAL DISTRICTS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. State divided into three districts.</p>
<p>2. Court of first district at Galveston.</p>
<p>3. Court of second district at Fort Worth.</p>
<p>4. Court of third district at Austin.</p>
<p>5. Counties composing first district.</p>
<p>6. Counties composing second district.</p>
<p>7. Counties composing third district.</p>
<p>8. Terms of court.</p>
<p>9. Emergency clause; law in effect Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust 15, 1892.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 18.&#8212;[S. S. B. No. 18.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to divide the State of Texas into three supreme judicial districts, and to provide for and establish a court of civil ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals in each of said districts, and to prescribe the times for holding court in each of said districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the State of Texas be and the same is hereby divided into three supreme judicial districts for the purpose of constituting and organizing the courts of civil appeals therein respectively.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That one of the civil courts of appeals shall be held in the first supreme judicial district, in the city of Galveston, in the county of Galveston.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That one of the civil courts of appeals shall be held in the second supreme judicial district, in the city of Fort Worth, in the county of Tarrant.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That one of the civil courts of appeals shall be held in the third supreme judicial district, in the city of Austin, in the county of Travis.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the following counties shall compose the first supreme judicial district: Panola, Shelby, Sabine, Newton, Orange, Jasper,<pb n="410" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>San Augustine, Nacogdoches, Rusk, Angelina, Tyler, Hardin, Jefferson, Chambers, Liberty, San Jacinto, Walker, Trinity, Polk, Houston, An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson, Leon, Madison, Grimes, Montgomery, Harris, Galveston, Vic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toria, Calhoun, Refugio, Goliad, Wharton, Brazos, Burleson, Washing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Austin, Port Bend, Brazoria, Fayette, Waller, Jackson, Cherokee, Colorado, Matagorda, DeWitt, Aransas, Lavaca, Harrison, Smith, Gregg, Bee, San Patricio, Nueces, Starr, Hidalgo, Cameron and Upshur.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the following counties shall compose the second dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict: Marion, Cass, Bowie, Morris, Camp, Titus, Franklin, Red River, Hopkins, Rains, Wood, Van Zandt, Henderson, Delta, Lamar, Fannin Grayson, Collin, Dallas, Rockwall, Hill, Johnson, Tarrant, Denton, Cooke, Wise, Montague, Parker, Hood, Somervell, Erath, Kaufman, Eastland, Borden, Crosby, Randall, Glascock, Howard, Palo Pinto, Jack, Clay, Wichita, Archer, Young, Stephens, Callahan, Shackleford, Throck<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />morton, Baylor, Wilbarger, Greer, Hardeman, Foard, Knox, Haskell, Jones, Taylor, Ward, Nolan, Fisher, Stonewall, King, Cottle, Child<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ress, Collingsworth, Wheeler, Hemphill, Lipscomb, Ochiltree, Roberts, Gray, Donley, Hale, Motley, Dickens, Kent, Garza, Scurry, Mitchell, Ftp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Midland, Martin, Dawson, Lynn, Lubbock, Hall, Lamb, Swisher, Armstrong, Potter, Carson, Hutchinson, Hansford, Sherman, Moore, Briscoe, Floyd, Hockley, Terry, Gaines, Andrews, Ector, Crane, Ward, Winkler, Loving, Reeves, Dallam, Hartley, Oldham, Deaf Smith, Par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer, Bailey, Cochran, Yoakum, Castro, Ellis and Hunt.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the following counties shall compose the third supreme judicial district: Robertson, Navarro, Freestone, Bosque, Hamilton, Comanche, Duval, Encinal, Webb, La Salle, Dimmit, McMullen, Live Oak, Maverick, Zavala, Frio, Atascosa, Uvalde, Medina, Bexar, Bandera, Val Verde, Edwards, Kerr, Foley, Mason, Kimble, Gillespie, Kendall, Sutton, Schleicher, Menard, Crockett, Pecos, Presidio, Jeff Davis, Buchel, San Saba, Llano, Burnet, Williamson, Travis, Gonzales, Hays, Comal, Guadalupe, Caldwell, Wilson, Karnes, Kinney, Zapata, Tom Green, Irion, Coke, Sterling, Brewster, El Paso, Falls, Limestone, Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Lennan, Milam, Bell, Coryell, Lampasas, Lee, Bastrop, Blanco, Mills, Brown, McCulloch, Coleman Concho and Runnels.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The terms of said courts shall commence on the first Monday in October of each year, and may continue in session until the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in July of each succeeding year.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The near approach of the close of the called session, and the imperative command of section 6, article 5, of the constitution of the State of Texas, to this legislature, as soon as practicable after the adop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the said section (at the recent elections held in this state), to divide the state into not less than two nor more than three supreme ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial districts and to establish a court of civil appeals in each of said districts, and the fact that the supreme court and the court of appeals are not able to dispose of the business now on their dockets, and a great public necessity exists that said courts of civil appeals should be organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and proceed to business as soon as possible, which creates a public necessity which requires the suspension of the constitutional rule requir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing bills to be read on three several days be and the same is suspended and this act take effect and be in force from and after the loth of Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust, 1892.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 13, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="411" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICTS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Divides state into the districts fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing:</p>
<p>2. First district.</p>
<p>3. Second district.</p>
<p>4. Third district.</p>
<p>5. Fourth district.</p>
<p>6. Fifth district.</p>
<p>7. Sixth district.</p>
<p>8. Seventh district.</p>
<p>9. Eighth district.</p>
<p>10. Ninth district.</p>
<p>11. Tenth district.</p>
<p>12. Eleventh district.</p>
<p>13. Twelfth district.</p>
<p>14. Thirteenth district.</p>
<p>15. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>16. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 19.&#8212;[H. S. B. No. 1, 26 and 29.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to apportion the State of Texas into congressional districts, and to repeal all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That until otherwise provided by law, the State of Texas shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portioned into the following congressional districts, each of which shall be entitled to elect one member to the congress of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The following counties shall compose the first district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Freestone, Leon, Madison, Trinity, Waller, Harris, Grimes, Walker, Chambers and Montgomery.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The following counties shall compose the second district, to-wit: Jefferson, Orange, Liberty, Hardin, Newton, Jasper, Polk, Ty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler, San Jacinto, Angelina, Nacogdoches, San Augustine, Sabine, Shelby, Panola, Harrison, Anderson, Cherokee, Houston.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The following counties shall compose the third district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Hunt, Rockwall, Rains, Yam Zandt, Wood, Smith, Upshur, Gregg, Rusk and Henderson.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The following counties shall compose the fourth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Hopkins, Franklin, Titus, Morris, Camp, Marion, Cass, Bowie, Red River, Lamar, Delta.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The following counties shall compose the fifth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Fannin, Collin, Grayson, Cooke, Denton and Montague.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The following counties shall compose the sixth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Dallas, Ellis, Navarro, Hill, Bosque, Johnson and Kaufman.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The following counties shall compose the seventh district, to-wit: Brazos, Robertson, Limestone, McLennan, Falls, Milam, Bell.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The following counties shall compose the eighth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Tarrant, Parker, Erath, Somervell, Mills, Hamilton, Coleman, Brown, Runnels, Hood, Comanche, Coryell and Lampasas.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The following counties shall compose the ninth district, to-wit: Burnet, Williamson, Lee, Travis, Burleson, Bastrop, Caldwell, Hays and Washington.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The following counties shall compose the tenth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Gonzales, Fayette, Austin, Colorado, Fort Bend, Galveston, Bra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zoria, Matagorda and Lavaca.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. The following counties shall compose the eleventh district, to wit: Wharton, Jackson, Calhoun, Victoria, DeWitt, Goliad, Refugio, Bee, Aransas, Karnes, Wilson, Guadalupe, Atascosa, Live Oak, San Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricio, Nueces, Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Zapata, Duval, Encinal, Webb, McMullen, La Salle, Dimmit, Zavalla, Frio and Uvalde.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The following counties shall compose the twelfth district, to-wit: Crockett, San Saha, Llano, Blanco, Kendall, Bexar, Medina, Kerr, Bandera, Gillespie, Mason, McCulloch, Menard, Kimble, Edwards, Val Verde, Sutton, Schleicher, Tom Green, Irion, Sterling, Coke, Glass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cock, Midland, Ector, Crane, Buchel, Pecos, Upton, Brewster, Foley, Presidio, Jeff Davis, Kinney, Maverick, Concho and Comal.</p>
<pb n="412" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 14. The following counties shall compose the thirteenth district, to-wit: Palo Pinto, Stephens, Shackelford, Eastland, Callahan, Taylor, Nolan, El Paso, Reeves, Ward, Loving, Winkler, Andrews, Martin, Gaines, Dawson, Borden, Scurry, Fisher, Jones, Wise, Jack, Young, Throckmorton, Haskell, Stonewall, Kent, Garza, Lynn, Terry, Yoakum, Cochran, Hockley, Lubbock, Crosby, Dickens, King, Knox, Baylor, Archer, Clay, Wichita, Wilbarger, Foard, Hardeman, Cottle, Motley, Floyd, Hale, Lamb, Bailey, Parmer, Castro, Swisher, Briscoe, Hall, Childress, Greer, Collingsworth, Donley, Armstrong, Randall, Deaf Smith, Oldham, Potter, Carson, Gray, Wheeler, Hemphill, Roberts Hutchinson, Moore, Hartley, Dallam, Sherman, Hansford, Ochiltree, Lipscomb, Howard and Mitchell.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with, the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. The nearness of the close of the present session of the leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature rendering it impracticable for this bill to be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days creates an emergency, and an imperative public necessity ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ists requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 19, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SENATORIAL DISTRICTS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Divides the state into thirty-one senatorial districts.</p>
<p>2. Election returns, where received; certificates.</p>
<p>3. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>4. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 20.&#8212;[S. H. B. No. 6, 7, 9, 25 and 29.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to apportion the State of Texas into senatorial districts, and to repeal all laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the senatorial districts of the State of Texas shall hereafter be composed respectively of the following named counties, each of which districts shall be entitled to elect one senator, to-wit:</p>
<div5 type="section">
<head type="main">Senatorial Districts.</head>
<p>No. 1. Bowie, Cass, Marion and Morris.</p>
<p>No. 2. Red River, Titus, Camp, Franklin, Hopkins and Delta.</p>
<p>No. 3. Lamar and Fannin.</p>
<p>No. 4. Grayson and Cooke.</p>
<p>No. 5. Collin and Hunt.</p>
<p>No. 6. Dallas and Rockwall.</p>
<p>No. 7. Rains, Van Zandt, Wood, Smith, Gregg and Upshur.</p>
<p>No. 8. Harrison, Rusk, Panola and Shelby.</p>
<p>No. 9. Navarro, Henderson and Kaufman.</p>
<p>No. 10. Ellis, Johnson and Hill.</p>
<p>No. 11. McLennan, Falls and Milam.</p>
<p>No. 12. Limestone, Freestone, Robertson, and Brazos.</p>
<p>No. 13. Anderson, Cherokee, Houston, Angelina and Trinity.</p>
<p>No. 14. Nacogdoches, San Augustine, Sabine, Newton, Jasper, Ty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler, Liberty, Hardin, Orange and Jefferson.</p>
<p>No. 15. Leon, Madison, Grimes, Montgomery, Walker, San Jacinto and Polk.</p>
<p>No. 16. Harris, Fort Bend, Waller and Austin.</p>
<pb n="413" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>No. 17. Chambers, Galveston, Brazoria, Matagorda and Wharton.</p>
<p>No. 18. Colorado, Lavaca and Fayette.</p>
<p>No. 19. Washington, Burleson, Lee and Bastrop.</p>
<p>No. 20. Williamson, Travis and Burnet.</p>
<p>No. 21. Gonzales, Caldwell, Guadalupe, Comal, Hays and Blanco.</p>
<p>No. 22. Jackson, Calhoun, Victoria, DeWitt, Goliad, Refugio, Bee, Live Oak, Karnes, Wilson, Atascosa, McMullen, La Salle, and Frio.</p>
<p>No. 23. Cameron, Hidalgo, Stair, Zapata, Webb, Encinal, Duval, Nueces, San Patricio and Aransas.</p>
<p>No. 24. Bexar, Medina, Bandera, Kendall, Kerr and Gillespie.</p>
<p>No. 25. Llano, Mason, Kimble, Menard, Schleicher, Sutton, Crock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ett, Tom Green, Coke, Sterling, Irion, Pecos, Buchel, Foley, Brewster, Presidio, Jeff Davis, El Paso, Val Verde, Edwards, Kinney, Uvalde, Za<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />valla, Dimmit, and Maverick.</p>
<p>No. 26. Erath, Comanche, Mills, San Saba, McCulloch, Concho, Runnels, Coleman and Brown.</p>
<p>No. 27. Bell, Lampasas, Coryell, Hamilton and Bosque.</p>
<p>No. 28. Palo Pinto, Stephens, Eastland, Callahan, Taylor, Nolan, Mitchell, Howard, Martin, Andrews, Glasscock, Midland, Ector, Wink<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler, Loving, Ward, Crane, Upton, Reeves, Gaines, Yoakum, Terry, Lynn, Dawson, Borden, Garza, Kent, Scurry, Fisher, Stonewall, Haskell, Jones and Shackelford.</p>
<p>No. 29. Jack, Young, Throckmorton, Clay, Archer, Wichita, Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />barger, Baylor, Knox, Foard, Hardeman, Greer, King, Dickens, Crosby, Lubbock, Hockley, Cochran, Bailey, Lamb, Hale, Floyd, Motley, Cottle, Childress, Hall, Briscoe, Swisher, Castro, Parmer, Deaf Smith, Randall, Armstrong, Donley, Collingsworth, Wheeler, Gray, Carson, Potter, Old<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ham, Hartley, Moore, Hutchinson, Roberts, Hemphill, Lipscomb, Ochil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tree, Hansford, Sherman and Dallam.</p>
<p>No. 30. Tarrant, Parker, Hood and Somervell.</p>
<p>No. 31. Denton, Wise and Montague.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The county judges of the following counties shall receive re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns and count the votes and issue certificates of election to persons re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceiving the highest number of votes for senator at any election in their respective districts, to-wit:</p>
<p>First District, Bowie county.</p>
<p>Second district, Red River county.</p>
<p>Third district, Lamar county.</p>
<p>Fourth district, Grayson county.</p>
<p>Fifth district, Collin county.</p>
<p>Sixth district, Dallas county.</p>
<p>Seventh district, Smith county.</p>
<p>Eighth district, Rusk county.</p>
<p>Ninth district, Navarro county.</p>
<p>Tenth district, Ellis County.</p>
<p>Eleventh district, McLennan county.</p>
<p>Twelfth district, Limestone county.</p>
<p>Thirteenth district, Cherokee county.</p>
<p>Fourteenth district, Tyler county.</p>
<p>Fifteenth district, Leon county.</p>
<p>Sixteenth district, Harris county.</p>
<p>Seventeenth district, Galveston county.</p>
<p>Eighteenth district, Colorado county.</p>
<p>Nineteenth district, Lee county.</p>
<pb n="414" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>Twentieth district, Williamson county.</p>
<p>Twenty-first district, Hays county.</p>
<p>Twenty-second district, Bee county.</p>
<p>Twenty-third district, Nueces county.</p>
<p>Twenty-fourth district, Bexar county.</p>
<p>Twenty-fifth district, Tom Green county.</p>
<p>Twenty-sixth district, Brown county.</p>
<p>Twenty-seventh district, Bell county.</p>
<p>Twenty-eighth district, Eastland county.</p>
<p>Twenty-ninth district, Clay county.</p>
<p>Thirtieth district, Tarrant county.</p>
<p>Thirty-first district, Wise county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the close of the session and the large amount of business undisposed of creates an emergency and an impera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive public necessity justifying the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 19, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div5>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">REPRESENTATIVE DISTRICTS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Apportions the state into representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive districts; number of represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives.</p>
<p>2. Election returns, by whom received in districts of more than one county.</p>
<p>3. Same, in districts of one county.</p>
<p>4. Article 13, chapter 13, act of May 3, 1882, and article 13 Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes repealed.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 21.&#8212;[S. H. B. Nos. 6, 7, 9, 25 and 39.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to apportion the State of Texas into representative districts and fix the number of representatives thereof, and to repeal article 13, chapter 13, of the general laws of the state, approved May 3, 1882, and article 13, title, 4, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the state, and all other laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the State of Texas is hereby apportioned into representative dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts and the number of representatives in each district shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:</p>
<p>No. 1. The first district, composed of the county of Bowie, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 2. The second district, composed of the county of Cass, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 3. The third district, composed of the counties of Bowie, Cass and Marion, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 4. The fourth district, composed of the county of Red River, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 5. The fifth district, composed of the counties of Morris, Titus and Red River, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 6. The sixth district, composed of the county of Lamar, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 7. The seventh district, composed of the county of Tannin, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 8. The eighth district, composed of the county of Grayson, and shall elect three representatives.</p>
<p>No. 9. The ninth district, composed of the county of Cooke, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<pb n="415" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>No. 10. The tenth district, composed of the county of Montague, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 11. The eleventh district, composed of the county of Wise, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 12. The twelfth, district, composed of the county of Denton, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 13. The thirteenth district, composed of the counties of Cooke, Denton and Wise, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 14. The fourteenth district, composed of the county of Collin, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 15. The fifteenth district, composed of the county of Hunt, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 16. The sixteenth district, composed of the county of Kaufman, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 17. The seventeenth district, composed of the counties of Hunt and Kaufman, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 18. The eighteenth district, composed of the county of Hopkins, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 19. The nineteenth district, composed of the counties of Hop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kins, Franklin and Delta, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 20. The twentieth district, composed of the counties of Wood and Rains, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 21. The twenty-first district, composed of the county of Harri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 22. The twenty-second district, composed of the counties of Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rison and Gregg, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 23. The twenty-third district, composed of the county of Smith, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 24. The twenty-fourth district, composed of the counties of Smith, Upshur and Camp, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 25. The twenty-fifth district, composed of the counties of Up<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shur and Camp, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 26. The twenty-sixth district, composed of the county of Rusk, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 27. The twenty-seventh district, composed of the counties of Rusk and Panola, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 28. The twenty-eighth district, composed of the county of Cher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />okee, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 29. The twenty-ninth district, composed of the county of An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 30. The thirtieth district, composed of the county of Houston, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 31. The thirty-first district, composed of the counties of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Anderson, Cherokee and Angelina, and shall elect one representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive.</p>
<p>No. 32. The thirty-second district, composed of the county of Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 33. The thirty-third district, composed of the counties of Shelby and Sabine, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 34. The thirty-fourth district, composed or the counties of San Augustine, Newton and Jasper, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 35. The thirty-fifth district, composed of the counties of San Jacinto and Polk, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 36. The thirty-sixth district, composed of the counties of Tyler.<pb n="416" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>Hardin, Liberty, Jefferson, Orange and Chambers, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 37. The thirty-seventh district, composed of the county of Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ris, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 38. The thirty-eighth district, composed of the counties of Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery, Walker and Trinity, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 39. The thirty-ninth district, composed of the county of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 40. The fortieth district composed of the counties of Brazoria and Matagorda, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 41. The forty-first district, composed of the counties of Fort Bend and Waller, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 42. The forty-second district, composed of the comity of Austin, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 43. The forty-third district, composed of the county of Colorado, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 44. The forty-fourth district, composed of the county of Lavaca, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 45. The forty-fifth district, composed of the county of Fayette, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 46. The forty-sixth district, composed of the counties of Whar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Colorado, Lavaca and Gonzales, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 47. The forty-seventh district, composed of the county of Wash<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ington, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 48. The forty-eighth district, composed of the counties of Wash<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ington, Burleson and Lee, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 49. The forty-ninth district, composed of the counties of Bur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leson and Lee, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 50. The fiftieth district, composed of the county of Travis, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 51. The fifty-first district, composed of the county of Caldwell, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 52. The fifty-second district, composed of the county of Bastrop, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 53. The fifty-third district, composed of the counties of Burnet and Lampasas, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 54. The fifty-fourth district, composed of the county of Grimes, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 55. The fifty-fifth district, composed of the counties of Brazos and Madison, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 56. The fifty-sixth district, composed of the counties of Leon and Madison, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 57. The fifty-seventh district, composed of the county of Free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stone, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 58. The fifty-eighth district, composed of the county of Navarro, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 59. The fifty-ninth district, composed of the counties of Na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />varro and Henderson, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 60. The sixtieth, district, composed of the county of Limestone, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 61. The sixty-first district, composed of the county of Falls, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<pb n="417" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>No. 62. The sixty-second district, composed of the county of Milam, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 63. The sixty-third, district, composed of the comity of Robert<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 64. The sixty-fourth district, composed of the counties of Lime<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stone, Robertson, Leon and Madison, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 65. The sixty-fifth district, composed, of the county of Bell, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 66. The sixty-sixth district, composed of the county of McLen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nan, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 67. The sixty-seventh district, composed of the county of Cory<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ell, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 68. The sixty-eighth district, composed of the county of Ellis, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 69. The sixty-ninth district, composed of the county of John<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 70. The seventieth district, composed of the counties of Ellis and Johnson, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 71. The seventy-first district, composed of the county of Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liamson, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 72. The seventy-second district, composed of the counties of Williamson, Milam and Palls, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 73. The seventy-third district, composed of the county of Dallas, and shall elect three representatives.</p>
<p>No. 74. The seventy-fourth district, composed of the counties of Dallas and Rockwall, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 75. The seventy-fifth district, composed of the county of Hill, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 76. The seventy-sixth district, composed of the counties of Bosque and Hamilton, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 77. The seventy-seventh district, composed of the counties of Hill, Bosque, Hamilton and Somervell, and shall elect one represents<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive.</p>
<p>No. 78. The seventy-eighth district, composed of the county of Tar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 79. The seventy-ninth district, composed of the county of Par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ker, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 80. The eightieth district, composed of the counties of Parker, Tarrant and Hood, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 81. The eighty-first district, composed of the counties of Palo Pinto and Eastland, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 82. The eighty-second district, composed of the counties of De Witt and Goliad, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 83. The eighty-third district, composed of the counties of Bee, Calhoun, Jackson, Refugio and Victoria, and shall elect one representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive.</p>
<p>No. 84. The eighty-fourth district, composed of the county of Gon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zales, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 85. The eighty-fifth district, composed of the counties of Cam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eron, Zanata, Hidalgo and Starr, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 86. The eighty-sixth district, composed of the counties of Webb and Encinal, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 87. The eighty-seventh district, composed of the counties of<pb n="418" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>Duval, Nueces, San Patricio and Aransas, and shall elect one repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative.</p>
<p>No. 88. The eighty-eighth district, composed of the counties of Atas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cosa, Karnes, Wilson and Live Oak, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 89. The eighty-ninth district, composed of the county of Bexar, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 90. The ninetieth district, composed of the counties of Bexar, Atascosa, Karnes, Wilson and Live Oak, and shall elect one representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive.</p>
<p>No. 91. The ninety-first district, composed of the counties of Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Mullen, La Salle, Dimmit, Zavalla, Uvalde, Medina and Trio, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 92. The ninety-second district, composed of the counties of Ban<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dera, Kerr and Kendall, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 93. The ninety-third district, composed of the counties of Llano and Mason, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 94. The ninety-fourth district, composed of the counties of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cho, McCulloch, Sara Saha and Mills, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 95. The ninety-fifth district, composed of the counties of Crock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ett, Sutton, Schleicher, Kimble, Menard, Runnels, Coke, Sterling, Tom Green, Irion and Edwards, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 96. The ninety-sixth district, composed of the counties of El Paso, Jeff Davis, Presidio, Brewster, Foley, Buchel, Pecos, Val Verde, Kinney and Maverick, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 97. The ninety-seventh district, composed of the county of Gua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dalupe, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 98. The ninety-eighth district, composed of the counties of Blanco, Gillespie, Hays and Comal, and shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>No. 99. The ninety ninth district, composed of the county of Erath, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 100. The one hundredth district, composed of the county of Van Zandt, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 101. The one hundred and first district, composed of the county of Comanche, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 102. The one hundred and second district, composed of the counties of Dallam, Sherman, Hansford, Ochiltree, Lipscomb, Hemphill, Roberts, Hutchinson, Moore, Hartley, Oldham, Potter, Carson, Gray, Wheeler, Collingsworth, Donley, Armstrong, Randall, Deaf Smith, Par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer, Castro, Swisher, Briscoe, Hall, Childress, Bailey, Lamb, Hale, Floyd, Motley, Cottle, Hardeman, Foard, Dickens and King, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 103. The one hundred and third district, composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Greer, Wilbarger and Wichita, and shall elect one representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive.</p>
<p>No. 104. The one hundred and fourth district, composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Knox, Baylor, Archer, Throckmorton, Young, and Stephens, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 105. The one hundred and fifth district, composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Clay and Jack, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 106. The one hundred and sixth district, composed of the counties of Reeves, Loving, Winkler, Ward, Crane, Upton, Ector, Midland, Glasscock, Andrews, Martin, Howard, Mitchell, Nolan,<pb n="419" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>Fisher, Scurry, Borden, Dawson, Gaines, Yoakum, Terry, Lynn, Garza, Kent, Stonewall, Haskell, Crosby, Lubbock, Hockley and Cochran, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 107. The one hundred and seventh district, composed of the counties of Jones, Shackelford, Callahan and Taylor, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>No. 108. The one hundred and eighth district, composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Brown and Coleman, and shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted: That in the several districts composed of more than one county, the county judges of the following named coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties shall receive the returns and issue the certificates of election to the representatives elected in their respective districts, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the third district, Cass county.</p>
<p>In the fifth district, Morris county.</p>
<p>In the thirteenth district, Denton county.</p>
<p>In the seventeenth district, Hunt county.</p>
<p>In the nineteenth district, Hopkins county.</p>
<p>In the twentieth district, Wood county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-second district, Harrison county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-fourth district, Smith county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-fifth district, Upshur county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-seventh district, Panola county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-first district, Cherokee county</p>
<p>In the thirty-third district, Shelby county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-fourth district, San Augustine county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-fifth district, Polk county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-sixth district, Jefferson county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-eighth district, Montgomery county.</p>
<p>In the fortieth district, Brazoria county.</p>
<p>In the forty-first district, Waller county.</p>
<p>In the forty-sixth district, Colorado county.</p>
<p>In the forty-eighth district, Washington county.</p>
<p>In the forty-ninth district, Burleson county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-third district, Burnet county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-fifth district, Brazos county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-sixth district, Leon county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-ninth district, Henderson county.</p>
<p>In the sixty-fourth district, Robertson county.</p>
<p>In the seventieth district, Ellis county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-second district, Milam county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-fourth district, Dallas county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-sixth district, Hamilton county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-seventh district, Bosque county.</p>
<p>In the eightieth district, Parker county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-first district, Eastland county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-second district, De Witt county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-third district, Victoria county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-fifth district, Cameron county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-sixth, district, Webb county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-seventh district, Nueces county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-eight district, Wilson county.</p>
<p>In the ninetieth district, Bexar county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-first district, Uvalde county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-second district, Kerr county.</p>
<pb n="420" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>In the ninety-third district, Llano county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-fourth district, McCulloch county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-fifth district, Tom Green county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-sixth district, Val Verde county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-eighth district, Hays county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and second district, Donley county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and third district, Wilbarger county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and fourth district, Baylor county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and fifth district, Jack county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and sixth district, Mitchell county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and seventh district, Taylor county.</p>
<p>In the one hundred and eighth district, Brown county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. In all districts composed of only one county, the county judge of such county shall receive the returns and issue the certificates of election to the representatives elected as shown by the highest number of votes cast for any one person.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That article 13, chapter 13, of the general laws of Texas, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved May 3d, 1882, and that article 13, title 4, of the Revised Civil Statutes, and all other laws and parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The near approach of the close of the session, and the large amount of business undisposed of, creates an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity, justifying the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">JUDICIAL DISTRICT&#8212;TWENTY-SECOND.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Terms of court in Caldwell county.</p>
<p>2. Repealing clause.</p>
<p>3. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 22.&#8212;[H. B. No. 58.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to extend the terms of the district court in Caldwell county in the 22d judicial district of Texas; to repeal all parts of laws in conflict herewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the term of the district court of Caldwell county, in the 22d judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial district of Texas, shall commence on the fourth Mondays in March and September of each year, and may continue in session five weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the close of this session creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity exists that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and said rule is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 19, 1892</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="421" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">JUDICIAL DISTRICTS&#8212;THIRTY-FIFTH AND FIFTY-FIRST.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends Section 2 of Act of March, 1891.</p>
<p>(2) Counties composing fifty-first district; terms of court.</p>
<p>3. [2]. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 23.&#8212;[H. B. No. 54.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section 2 of an act to reorganize the 35th judicial district, and to create the 51st judicial district of the state, presented to the governor 3d of March, 1891, but not being signed by him nor re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to the house where it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, became a law without his signature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section 2 of an act to reorganize the 35th judicial district and to create the 51st judicial district, which was presented to the governor, March 3, 1891, but not being signed by him nor returned to the house where it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the constitution, became a law without his signature, shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fifty-first judicial district of this state is hereby created, and shall be composed of the counties of Irion, Sutton, Coke, Crockett, Sterling, Tom Green and Schleicher, and a district court shall be held therein each Tear as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Irion on the first Mondays of September and Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Sutton on the third Mondays of September and Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Coke on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in September and February, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Crockett on the eighth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in September and February, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Sterling on the tenth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in September and February, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Tom Green on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in September and February, and may continue in session until the business of the court is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. [2]. The near approach of the close of the session, and the large amount of business undisposed of, creates an emergency and neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days to be suspended, it is so suspended.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the governor of Texas for his approval on the eleventh day of April, A. D. 1892, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto; nor were any objections thereto filed by him in this office after adjournment of the legislature, within the time prescribed by the constitution. This act thereupon became a law without his signa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture.&#8212;J. R. Curl, Chief Clerk and Acting Secretary of State.]</p>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="422" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">JUDICIAL DISTRICTS&#8212;FORTY-THIRD, FORTY-SIXTH AND FORTY-SEVENTH.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Counties comprising forty-sixth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict; terms of court.</p>
<p>2. Counties comprising forty-seventh district; terms of court.</p>
<p>6. Emergency clause; law takes effect, when.</p>
<p>3. Counties comprising forty-third dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict; terms of court.</p>
<p>4. Process, when returnable; juries.</p>
<p>5. Repealing clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 24.&#8212;[S. B. No. 31.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to reorganize the forty-third, forty-sixth, and forty-seventh judicial districts, and to fix the time for holding the terms of court therein, and to repeal all laws in conflict herewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the forty-sixth judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Wilbarger, Greer, Collingsworth, Hardeman, Childress, Hall and Foard, and the terms of the district court shall be held therein each year as follows:</p>
<p>In the county of Wilbarger on the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session eight weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Greer on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Collingsworth on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hardeman on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Childress on the sixteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Hall on the eighteenth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Foard on the twentieth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the forty-seventh judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Donley, Armstrong Randall, Deaf Smith, Potter, Old<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ham, Hartley, Dallam, Sherman, Briscoe, Swisher and Castro and the unorganized counties of Moore, Parmer, Bailey and Lamb, and the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court shall be held therein each year as follows:</p>
<p>In the county of Donley on the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Briscoe on the second Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Armstrong on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Potter on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session three weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Randall on the ninth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Deaf Smith on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<pb n="423" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>
<p>In the county of Oldham on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Hartley on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Dallam on the sixteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Sherman on the eighteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Castro on the nineteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Swisher on the twentieth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>The unorganized county of Parmer is hereby attached to Deaf Smith county for judicial purposes.</p>
<p>The unorganized counties of Bailey and Lamb are hereby attached to Castro county for judicial purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the forty-third judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Jack, Parker and Wise, and the terms of the district court shall be held therein each year as follows:</p>
<p>In the county of Jack on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Parker on the fourth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session eight weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Wise on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all process issued or served before this act goes into effect, returnable to the district courts in said judicial districts aforesaid, shall be considered returnable to said courts in accordance with the terms as prescribed by this act, and such process is hereby legalized; and all grand and petit juries drawn and selected under existing laws in any of the counties of said judicial districts, shall be considered lawfully drawn and selected for the next term of the district courts of their respective counties held after this act takes effect; and such process is hereby legal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and validated.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Whereas, the rapid settlement of the counties mentioned in this act, and the inability of the judges under former laws to trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />act all of the business in the courts of the said several counties, and the organization of unorganized counties, creates an imperative public necessity, and an emergency exists requiring the suspension of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house; therefore said constitutional rule is hereby suspended and so much of this act as affects the forty-sixth and forty-seventh judicial districts shall take effect from and after the first day of July, 1892,<pb n="424" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>and the remainder thereof shall take effect from and after, the first day of September, 1892, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the governor of Texas for his approval on the twelfth day of April, A. D. 1892, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto; nor were there any objections thereto filed by him in this office after the adjournment of the legislature, within the time prescribed by the constitution. This act thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. R. Curl, Chief Clerk and Acting Secretary of State.]</p>
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>