<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1049" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>FIRST CALLED SESSION OF THE TWENTY-FOURTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>OCTOBER 1, 1895, AND ADJOURNED OCTOBER 7, 1895.</byline>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/1049_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<byline>AUSTIN 1896</byline>
<pb n="1050" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>Appropriations&#8212;</p>
<p>Additional for support of State Government.................... 7</p>
<p>Mileage and per diem.................... 5</p>
<p>Australian Ballot System&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation to carry out transferred.................... 7</p>
<p>Booths and Guard Rails&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation to provide transferred.................... 7</p>
<p>Deaf and Dumb Asylum&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for expert at.................... 7</p>
<p>Delinquent Tax-Payers&#8212;</p>
<p>May not plead limitation in suits for taxes.................... 6</p>
<p>Expert Shoemaker, Binder, Etc.&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..................... 7</p>
<p>Fights Between Man and Animal&#8212;</p>
<p>Felony..................... 5</p>
<p>Limitation&#8212;</p>
<p>May not be pleaded in suits for taxes.................... 6</p>
<p>Prize-Fighting&#8212;</p>
<p>Felony.................... 5</p>
<p>Penalties..................... 5</p>
<p>See Pugilistic Encounter.</p>
<p>Public Printing and Binding&#8212;</p>
<p>Appropriation for..................... 7</p>
<p>Pugilism&#8212;</p>
<p>See Prize-Fighting.</p>
<p>Pugilistic Encounter&#8212;</p>
<p>Defined..................... 5</p>
<p>For prize, championship, etc., felony.................... 5</p>
<p>Statute of Limitation&#8212;</p>
<p>May not be pleaded in bar of payment of delinquent taxes.................... 6</p>
<p>Taxation&#8212;</p>
<p>Statute of limitation may not be pleaded in suits for delinquent taxes.................... 6</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1051" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS. FIRST CALLED SESSION TWENTY-FOURTH LEGISLATURE, 1895.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PEIZE FIGHTING, ETC.&#8212;PENALTIES THEREFOR.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 1.&#8212;[S. B. No. 3.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prohibit prize fighting and pugilism, and fights between men and animals, and to provide penalities therefor, and to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peal all laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That any person who shall voluntarily engage in a pugilistic encounter between man and man, or a fight between a man and a bull or any other animal, for money or other thing of value, or for any championship, or upon the result of which any money or any thing of value is bet or wa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gered, or to see which any admission fee is charged, either directly or indirectly, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and upon conviction shall be punished by imprisonment in the penitentiary not less than two nor more than five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. By the term &#8220;pugilistic encounter,&#8221; as used in this act, is meant any voluntary fight or personal encounter by blows by means of the fists or otherwise, whether with or without gloves, between two or more men, for money or for a prize of any character, or for any other thing of value, or for any championship, or upon the result of which any money or any thing of value is bet or wagered.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The fact that there is now no adequate penalty against prize fighting and pugilism, or fights between men and beasts, creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity and emergency requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and that this law should take effect and be in force from and after its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage, and it is hereby so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 3, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPROPRIATION&#8212;MILEAGE AND PER DIEM.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 2.&#8212;[S. B. No. 1.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation for mileage and per diem pay of members and per diem pay of officers and employes of the first called session of the Twenty-fourth Legislature of Texas, convened October 1st, 1895, by proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of twenty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in<pb n="1052" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>the treasury of this State, not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of mileage and per diem pay of the members and the payment of the per diem pay of the officers and employes of the first called session of the Twenty-fourth Legislature of Texas, convened October 1st, 1895, by proclamation of the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate, approved by the President thereof, or the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, approved by the Speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants upon the Treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The public importance of the objects herein contemplated creates an imperative public necessity and emergency fully authorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is hereby suspended, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 3d, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TAXATION&#8212;DELINQUENT TAX PAYERS&#8212;STATUTE OF LIMITATION.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 3.&#8212;[S. B. No. 8.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prevent delinquent tax payers from plead<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the statute of limitation by way of defense against the payment of any taxes due from him or her either to the State or any county, city, or town.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That no delinquent tax payer shall have the right to plead in any court or in any manner rely upon any statute of limitation by way of defense against the payment of any taxes due from him or her either to the State or any county, city, or town.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, there is now no law in this State to prevent delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent tax payers from setting up the statute of limitation as a defense against the payment of taxes due from him or her, and to avoid the fil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of a multiplicity of suits by the municipal authorities against delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent tax payers in order to prevent the bar of limitation being set up them, therefore an emergency exists and an imperative public necessity requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring all bills to be read on three several days, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 9, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FURTHER APPROPRIATION FOR SUPPORT OF THE STATE GOVERNMENT.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 4.&#8212;[S. B. No. 6.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making further appropriation for the sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port of the State government for the years beginning March 1, 1895, to Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 28, 1897.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in the enrollment of an act entitled &#8220;An Act making appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation for the support of the State government for the years beginning March 1, 1895, to February 28, 1897, and for other purposes,&#8221; approved May 3, 1895, the following clerical errors were committed, whereby the<pb n="1053" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">General Laws of Texas.</fw>items under the head of public printing of $2100.00 for each year should have been $21,000.00 for each year, and under the head of Deaf and Dumb Asylum the item of &#8220;expert shoemaker, expert binder and teacher&#8221; of $720.00 for each year should have been $1440.00 for each year; now therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following sums of money, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, are hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the following purposes, in addition to the sums of money already appropriated in the above entitled act: For first, second and third classes of public printing and binding, and for printing papers for first and second classes of public printing, eighteen thousand nine hundred dollars for the year ending February 28, 1896, and eigh<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen thousand nine hundred dollars for the year ending February 28, 1891. For salary of expert shoemaker, expert binder and teacher, the sum Of seven hundred and twenty dollars for the year ending February 28, 1896, and seven hundred and twenty dollars for the year ending February 28, 1897.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of $100.00 to pay expenses of building booths and guard rails to carry out the Australian ballot system be taken from the appropriation for the year 1897 and transferred to the year 1896.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that the amounts of money appropriated by this act are needed by the State at the present time, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and that this law should take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is hereby so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the fifth day of October, A. D. 1895, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;Allison Mayfield, Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary of State.]</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, Allison Mayfield, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the foregoing laws, passed at the first called session of the Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth Legislature, have been carefully examined and compared with the original enrolled bills, now on file in this department, and are true copies of said originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the first called session of the Twenty-fourth Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature convened in the city of Austin October 1, A. D. 1895, and ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed October 7, A. D. 1895.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have subscribed my name and have <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[Seal]</p></body></floatingText>hereto affixed the <i>seal of the State of Texas, in the city of</i> Austin, this November 7, A. D. 1895.</p>
<closer>
<signed>ALLISON MAYFIELD, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="1054" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" />
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>