<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="954" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="224" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">House Concurrent Resolution Ho. 11.</head>
<p>Whereas, the drouth which has prevailed for the last three or four years, the shortage in crops, the low prices for cotton and other farm products, and the general financial depression has rendered many of the purchasers and settlers of the public free school, the university and the several asylum lands unable to meet their obligations therefor; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, there are now about 3600 claims and accounts of such pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chasers which have been or are about to be forfeited for the non-pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of interest; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, such forfeitures will render homeless and penniless many of such purchasers, and will thereby work a hardship and produce great trouble and distress upon them and their families; therefore, be it</p>
<p>Resolved by the House of Representatatives, the Senate concurring: That the Commissioner of the General Land Office do, and he is hereby instructed to, withhold and suspend the forfeiture of all such lands sold under the acts of 1887 and subsequent acts thereto, until further legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation is had upon such land matters by the Legislature now in session, or until the close of said session, and the State Treasurer is hereby in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed to receive interest and principal payments upon such lands un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the rules of law regulating such payments for and during said time.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 6th day of February, A. D. 1895, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;Allison Mayfield, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">House Concurrent Resolution No. 25.</head>
<p>Whereas, Lieutenant Robert J. Lambert, of Company B, Fourth Texas Infantry, Hood&#8217;s Brigade, fell at Games&#8217; Mill, Va., June 27, 1862, in Hood&#8217;s memorable charge against McClellan, and sacrificed his young and noble life upon the altar of his country; as a tribute to his gallant and chivalrous conduct on the field of battle; therefore be it.</p>
<p>Resolved, that his friends be permitted to inter his remains in the State Cemetery.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 21, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="955" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="225" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. C. R. No. 21.] Authorizing and directing the Secretary of State to correct a mistake in enrollment of Substitute House Bill No. 120, passed at a former day of the present session of the Legislature, so as to show the action of the Senate thereon.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Senate, the House concurring: That the Secretary of State be and he is hereby authorized and directed to correct an error on the enrolled bill now on file in his office, passed at the present session of the Legislature, the error to be corrected being the following: &#8220;Substitute House bill No. 120 being under consideration in the Senate on March 6th, 1895, was on that day read the third time and duly passed by the following vote: twenty (20) yeas, and one (1) nay.&#8221; Such action of the Senate was thereupon correctly endorsed on the engrossed bill, and the same was on the 7th day of March re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ported to the House of Representatives; the bill was then enrolled by the enrolling clerk of the House of Representatives, but in enrolling the same the said clerk inadvertently and by mistake failed to copy the action of the Senate thereon as aforesaid. The bill as enrolled appear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing by such act of said clerk to have passed the Senate by the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing vote: &#8220;twenty (20) ayes, and no (0) nays;&#8221; and the Secretary of State is hereby directed to correct said mistake on the said act in his hands, and to file this resolution in his office along with said act, and in publishing the act he shall cause its publication as if said mistake had not occurred, and in accordance with the action of the Senate thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the fact of such mistake having occurred creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule that bills be read on three several days be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 30, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[S. C. R. No. 26.] Asking the Secretary of State to return to the Senate S. B. 170, entitled &#8220;An act to amend an act entitled an act to amend article 1054, chapter 2, title 15, of the Code of Criminal Procedure, as amended by an act of the Twenty-first Legislature, approved April 4, 1889,&#8221; constituting chapter 93, general laws of the State of Texas, 1891, in order that the same may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented to the Speaker of the House of Representatives for his signature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, at a previous day of the present session of the Legislature, S. B. 170, being entitled &#8220;An act to amend an act entitled an act to amend article 1054, chapter 2, title 15, of the Code of Criminal Proced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure, as amended by act of the Twenty-first Legislature, approved April 4, 1889, constituting chapter 93, general laws of the State of Texas, 1891,&#8221; was introduced and has passed both the Senate and House of Representatives, and has received the signature of the President of the Senate and has been presented to the Governor for his signature, and<pb n="956" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="226" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>said bill has been by him approved and delivered to the Secretary of State; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, by mistake the same was net presented to the Speaker of the House of Representatives for his signature and was not signed by him as is required by the Constitution of Texas: therefore, be it</p>
<p>Resolved by the Senate, the House of Representatives concurring: That the Secretary of State be and he is hereby requested to return to the Senate the said bill, in order that it may be presented to and receive the signature of the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 30, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[H. J. R. No. 32.] Amending article 6, section 2, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, requiring persons of foreign birth to declare their intention to be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come citizens of the United States six months before any election at which such persons may offer to vote.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That article 6, section 2, of the Constitution of the State of Texas be amended so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 2. Every male person subject to none of the foregoing dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />qualifications, who shall have attained the age of twenty-one years, and who shall be a citizen of the United States, and who shall have resided in this State one year next preceding an election, and the last six months within the district or county in which he offers to vote, shall be deemed a qualified elector. And every male person of foreign birth subject to none of the foregoing disqualifications, who, not less than six months before any election at which he offers to vote, shall have declared his in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tention to become a citizen of the United States in accordance with the Federal naturalization laws, and shall have resided in this State one year next preceding such election, and the last six months in the county in which he offers to vote, shall also be deemed a qualified elector; and all electors shall vote in the election precinct of their residence: Provided, that electors living in any unorganized county may vote at any election precinct in the county to which such county is attached for judicial pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Governor of this State is hereby directed to issue the necessary proclamation submitting this amendment to the qualified voters of Texas at the next general election.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 30th day of April, A. D. 1895, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon became a law without his signature.&#8212;Allison Mayfield, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<pb n="957" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="227" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[C. S. H. C. R. No. 22.] Authorizing and instructing the State Board of Public Printing to dispose of the property comprising what is known as the State printing office.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the State Board of Public Printing is hereby authorized and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed to advertise and sell all and singular the type, stands, stones, presses, boilers, engines, tools and implements, electrotyping machinery, tools, implements and material, and all other property of any character whatever and wherever found belonging to and comprising what was formerly known as the State printing office; not, however, including the outfit originally purchased for the Deaf and Dumb Institute for use in instructing the pupils in the art of printing and bookbinding in accordance with the provisions of an act of the Legislature March 13, 1875.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said Board of Public Printing shall dispose of said property as speedily as practicable, either at public or private sale, and in such manner as said board shall deem to the best interest of the State, the proceeds to be paid over to the Comptroller to the credit of the general revenue account of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that said property is rapidly deteriorating in value and the near approach of the close of the session and crowded condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the calendar creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity for a suspension of the constitutional rule requiring joint res<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />olutions to be read on three several days, and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>[H. J. R. No. 18.] To amend section 4 of article 7 of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section 4 of article 7 of the Constitution of the State of Texas be so amended as to read hereafter as follows:</p>
<p>Section 4. The lands herein set apart to the public free school fund shall be sold under such regulations, at such times and on such terms as may be prescribed by law; and the Legislature shall not have power to grant any relief to purchasers thereof. The Comptroller shall invest the proceeds of such sales, and of those heretofore made, as may be directed by the board of education herein provided for in the bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities as may be prescribed by law, or in agricultural lands, for the benefit of the penitentiary system of the State, under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law, and the State shall be responsible for all such investments.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The foregoing amendment shall be submitted to the qualified<pb n="958" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="228" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>voters of the State at the next general election. Those favoring its adoption shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;For the amendment to section 4, article 7, of the Constitution,&#8221; and those opposed to its adoption shall have written or printed on Their ballots the words &#8220;Against the amendment to section 4, article 7, of the Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution;&#8221; and the Governor of the State is hereby directed to issue the necessary proclamation for said election and have the same published, as required by the Constitution and existing laws of the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 27, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>Granting to John B. Hood Camp of Confederate Veterans the right to place in the Capitol grounds a monument to the Confederate dead.</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate, the House of Representatives concur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ring: That John B. Hood Camp of Confederate Veterans be and they are hereby granted permission to erect a monument to the Confederate dead on the Capitol grounds in the city of Austin, and that the Super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendent of Public Buildings and Grounds be authorized, in conjunc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion with the committee appointed by said camp, to select a site for said monument.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 16, 1895</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CERTIFICATE.</head>
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, Allison Mayfield, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the foregoing laws and resolutions, passed at the regular session of the Twenty-fourth Legislature, have been carefully examined and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared with the original enrolled bills, now on file in this department, and are true copies of said originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Twenty-fourth Legislature convened in the city of Austin January 8, A. D. 1895, and adjourned April 30, A. D. 1895.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have subscribed my name and <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[SEAL]</p></body></floatingText>have hereto affixed the seal of the State of Texas, in the city of Austin, this June 22, A. D. 1895.</p>
<closer>
<signed>ALLISON MAYFIELD, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<pb n="959" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="229" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<p>List of Bills with Emergency Clause, showing when they take effect.</p>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/0959_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<pb n="960" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="230" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<figure xml:id="fig2">
<graphic url="images/0960_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>