<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1311" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="257" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. No. 1.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Welcoming the Hon. William J. Bryan to Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Hon. William Jennings Bryan, of Nebraska, the brilliant orator, grand statesman and matchless tribune of the people, at the last election democratic candidate for president of the United States, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templates an early visit to this State; therefore, be it</p>
<p>Resolved by the Senate, the House of Representatives concurring, That in the name of all the people the Legislature of Texas welcomes the distinguished gentleman to our grand State, and voice the wish that his stay among us may be prolonged and agreeable.</p>
<p>Be it further resolved, That a cordial invitation is hereby extended Hon. W. J. Bryan to visit the capital of the State as the guest of the Legislature during his sojourn in Texas.</p>
<p>Be it farther resolved, That his Excellency, Hon C. A. Culberson, Governor of Texas, be and he is hereby requested to transmit to the Hon. W. J. Bryan a copy of this concurrent resolution, certified by the great seal of the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 18, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. R. No. 6.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>For printing Rules, Constitution, Standing Committees, and Lists of Officers and Members of each House.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, That there be printed and bound three hundred copies of a book contain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the rules of the Senate, the rules of the House of Representatives, the joint rules of the two houses, the Constitutions of the United States and of the State of Texas, properly indexed and annotated, also a list of the officers, standing committees and members of each house, one hundred copies of the same to be for the use of the Senate and two hundred copies for the use of the House; the printing to be done under the super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vision of the chairmen of the committees on printing and the commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees on rules of the two houses.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 30, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1312" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="258" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. J. R. No. 7.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To Amend Article S of the Constitution of Texas, so as to permit the formation of irrigation districts in West Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 8 of the Constitution of the State of Texas be amended by adding thereto Section 20, as follows:</p>
<p>Section 20. In addition to the powers of taxation granted in the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going sections, it shall be lawful for the land owners of certain portions of Texas, as hereinafter provided, to organize within that section of Texas which lies west, northwest and southwest of the following coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, viz: Montague, Wise, Parker, Hood, Somervell, Bosque, Coryell, Bell, Williamson, Travis, Blanco, Gillespie, Comal, Caldwell, Gonzales, De Witt, Goliad, Victoria and Calhoun, irrigation districts without re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gard to county lines. In making provision for the cost of construction of irrigation works within said territory it shall be lawful to create an indebtedness of not exceding fifteen dollars per acre to rest as a charge on and be secured by a lien on the irrigable land for the use and benefit of which said irrigation works have been or may be constructed. Within the term, cost of construction, shall be included the cost of ri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />parian rights, dam sites and reservoirs, rights of way for canal and laterals, and other appurtenant expenses of the construction of irriga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion plants. In case of destruction of the works, or any part thereof, the repair or rebuilding of the same shall be construed to be within the meaning of construction. To cover the cost of construction as above defined, bonds may be issued by such irrigation districts to run in time for forty years or less, and to bear interest at the rate of not more than six per cent per annum, interest payable annually, which bonds shall be sold at not less than par. The bonds shall be liquidated by the levy and collection of a tax upon the irrigable lands within such irrigation districts susceptible of irrigation from and by the system of irrigation works proposed. Such land shall be taxed in proportion to acreage and not in proportion to its value. An annual tax shall be levied and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected on such irrigable lands sufficient to pay the interest of said bonds and to create a sinking fund sufficient to liquidate the bonds above authorized. In addition to the tax above provided for, there shall be annually levied and collected a sufficient tax from the lands actually receiving the water for irrigation of a sufficient amount to cover the ordinary cost of the maintenance of the irrigation works, the distribu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the water and appurtenant charges and the collection of said tax. This charge shall be upon a basis of the amount of water contracted for; provided that this shall not interfere with the right of any land owner to demand his proportionate part of the water on the basis of acreage. The taxes above provided for shall when assessed, be secured by lien on the land as now provided by the general law for the security of State taxes, and when delinquent, shall be enforced as now provided by general law for the collection of delinquent State taxes, but the lien securing the same shall be subordinate to the lien securing the payment of State, county and municipal taxes.</p>
<p>None of the foregoing provisions of this amendment shall ever be construed to give authority to create a lien on or tax in any manner any<pb n="1313" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="259" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>lands so long as they shall belong to the State; nor after sale thereof shall any charge ever be created thereon which shall take precedence over the liens securing the balance of the purchase money due the State.</p>
<p>The indebtedness for the construction of irrigation works authorized under the provisions of this amendment shall be created only upon a vote of a majority of the land owners resident in the district proposed to be organized and whose lands are susceptible of irrigation from and by the system of irrigation works proposed; only qualified voters under the existing laws of Texas, being such owners of rural lands, within such dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts, shall have the right to vote as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Any natural or artificial person having an interest in any of the irri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gable lands in any such irrigation district shall have the right at any time within ninety days after the vote authorized has been declared, and not thereafter, to file a proceeding in any court having jurisdiction to test the validity of the formation of said, district, the classification of the land as irrigable lands, or other details thereof. Such procedings shall have precedence through all the courts as now provided by law in quo warranto suits.</p>
<p>Irrigation districts organized under the provisions of this amendment are hereby declared to be bodies corporate, and in the name of the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts they shall have the right to sue and be sued, and may acquire by purchase or condemnation proceedings as now authorized by law in the case of irrigation corporations all the property necessary for its organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation, operation and existence, and may buy in under foreclosure of its taxes any property, but the property bought in at tax sales shall be held and disposed of as hereafter provided by law.</p>
<p>All bonds issued under the provisions of this amendment shall be passed upon and certified to by the Attorney General of the State of Texas, as now required by law in the case of county and city bonds. When approved by the Attorney General said bonds shall be registered by the Comptroller of the State, as now required by law in the case of county and city bonds, and when so registered shall be entitled to all the faith and confidence now prescribed by law in the case of county and city bonds.</p>
<p>To the end that this amendment may be put into immediate operation upon its adoption by the people, it is provided that until otherwise pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by law the Governor of the State, the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office, and the Attorney General of the State, are hereby created a board and vested with complete power and authority to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to put into immediate practical operation this amendment to the Constitution and that may be necessary to enable irrigation districts to organize and operate under the provisions of this amendment. And to that end, until otherwise pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by law, said board shall have the power and authority in making said rules as complete as the Legislature of the State of Texas now have to enact laws. The rules, when adopted by said board, shall be filed with the Secretary of State, and when so filed shall remain in full force and effect until changed or modified by some other rule made by the said board on file in the office of the Secretary of State, or until the same are changed by general law. Said rules shall be printed under the direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Secretary of State, and a certified copy thereof shall be fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1314" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="260" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>nished to any one demanding the same upon the payment of such fees as said board may prescribe.</p>
<p>The Governor is hereby directed to issue the necessary proclamation for submitting this amendment to the qualified voters of Texas on the first Tuesday in August, 1897, at which election all voters favoring the amendment shall have written or printed on their tickets, &#8220;For amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Article 8, of the Constitution of Texas, so as to permit the formation of irrigation districts in West Texas,&#8221; and those opposed to said amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall have written or printed on their tickets, &#8220;Against amending Article 8, of the Constitution of Texas, so as to permit the formation of irrigation districts in West Texas.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 3, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the Senate by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 23, nays 1; and having passed the House by a two-thirds vote, yeas 90, nays 6, the Senate concurred in House amendments.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. No. 15.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Tendering thanks of the people of Texas to the Honorable Swante Palm for do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation of his library to the State University.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Honorable Swante Palm, a distinguished citizen of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin, and the consular representative of His Majesty, the King of Sweden, at the Texas capital, has manifested his patriotic and generous interest in the intellectual development of the youth of the State, by making to the Texas State University, a free donation of his magnificent library, consisting of rare volumes, valuable manuscripts, and costly works of art; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, it is appropriate that, as an inadequate, but sincere recogni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this splendid gift, the Legislature of this State, representing the whole people, should give formal expression of the people&#8217;s gratitude to the Honorable Swante Palm; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate of the State of Texas, the House concurr<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing: That the people of the State of Texas, without regard to political sentiment, and each constituency speaking through its Senator, and member or members of the House of Representatives, hereby tender to the Honorable Swante Palm, their profound thanks for his splendid gift.</p>
<p>Resolved, that an enrolled copy of this Concurrent Resolution, signed in autograph by the President and Secretary of the Senate, and the Speaker and Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives, and counter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed by the Governor and Secretary of State, and bearing the impress of the seal of the State, be presented to the Honorable Swante Palm, by a joint committee of two Senators, to be appointed by the President of the Senate, and three Representatives, to be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 4, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1315" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="261" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. R. No. 7.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Empowering the Governor of Texas to call a Cotton Growers&#8217; Convention, and inviting delegates from all Cotton growing States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the cotton industry of the South is a most important agri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cultural product of the United States, and in volume more than sixty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five per cent of the world&#8217;s product of cotton; and the condition of this great industry, being now depressed by speculators who control and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duce the price, in their own interest, by the following methods, among others:</p>
<p>By offering for sale fictitious cotton called, &#8220;futures,&#8221; at prices uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formly less than the current spot cotton market, which sales or fictitious cotton or contracts to deliver cotton at a future time at lower prices than the actual spot cotton prices, and in which speculators do not intend, and are not compelled to deliver actual cotton, but uniformly pay or receive the monetary difference in the price of futures and spot cotton at the expiration of the contract of delivery; these contracts being cheaper, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duce mill men and consumers of the raw material, who heretofore com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peted in the spot cotton sales, to withdraw from the market, thus foster<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a condition which takes from the cotton market the actual purchaser, destroys legitimate market demand and competition, and leaves the cot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton product at the mercy of dictated prices. By flooding the market re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports of actual sales of spot cotton with five to ten times the volume of fictitious sales at lower figures, thus producing a constant decrease in the price of real cotton. By operating a gambling enterprise known as the &#8220;New York Future Board,&#8221; in which fictitious cotton is offered for sale in the market at prices sufficiently reduced below spot cotton prices to invite investment, and wherein the said investments are virtually confis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated by arbitrary changes in said quotations, whereby the country is drained of enormous sums of money, and the cotton market fluctuated for gambling purposes, to the great detriment of legitimate trade; thus producing the decline in the price of cotton as observed in our markets since the organization of the New York Cotton Exchange and its &#8220;Fu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures Board;&#8221; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The price of labor necessary to raise and market a given quantity of cotton, in comparison with the price of labor necessary to manufacture and market the same quantity of cotton is of the ratio of two to three, and under legitimate conditions of trade, and estimates most favorable to manufactures, raw cotton should sell for not less than fifty per cent of the manufactured articles, yet the situation is such that the price of cotton has been so depressed by speculation and market gambling until manufactured goods sell for prices from four hundred to fourteen hundred per cent more than the material that composes such goods, and a vast wealth that should be distributed among its producers is annually confiscated by the unbridled greed of speculators; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The history of cotton production shows that the world&#8217;s demand has increased at a greater ratio than the world&#8217;s supply, and as measured by the surplus on hand at the end of each cotton season, the surplus has grown less for more than twenty years, proving the falsity of the cry of over-production, as proclaimed by speculators, and reveal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1316" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="262" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>ing facts that under proper conditions would have made prices steady, and improved during that time; and</p>
<p>Whereas, These and other conditions make it necessary that legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion be contrived and enacted to relieve cotton producers from these op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pressive, unjust and ruinous conditions:</p>
<p>Therefore, be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, That Governor C. A. Culberson be, and he is hereby empow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered to call a legislative convention of the cotton growing States, to meet at Galveston, on the 2nd day of August, 1897, for the purpose of devis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and recommending concurrent legislation in the cotton growing States, to the end that this important industry may be relieved from the speculative and gambling influence that oppresses it, and that unlawful interference with the cotton trade be suppressed.</p>
<p>Be it further resolved, That the Governor of Texas appoint from each congressional district in Texas, a representative to said convention, who is versed in the industrial conditions of our State, and two from the State at large, and that his excellency forward copies of this resolution to the respective governors of our cotton growing States, with the request that such governor appoint delegates from the congressional districts of their States to said convention.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. E. No. 16.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Favoring improvement by Congressional appropriation of harbor at the mouth of the Brazos River, and opening said river to navigation as far as practicable.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, a board of engineers, appointed under an act of Congress, have reported that the opening of a harbor at the mouth of the Brazos River is feasible, and that there are valid commercial reasons that justify the general government in undertaking the work, therefore:</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, First. That we favor an appropriation by Congress for the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, maintenance and control of said harbor by the government of the United States.</p>
<p>Second. An appropriation for the improvement and opening of the Brazos River to navigation as far as may be found practicable.</p>
<p>Third. That our senators and representatives in Congress are respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully requested to use their best endeavors to secure such, appropriations as may be necessary for these purposes.</p>
<p>Be it further resolved, That the Chief Clerk of the House of Represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives transmit to each of our senators and representatives in Congress a copy of these resolutions.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 20, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1317" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="263" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. B. No. 17.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Favoring national aid to the Afro-American Fair and Inter-State Exposition Co.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, there has been projected and permanently organized and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated the worthy institution known as the &#8220;Afro-American Fair and Inter-State Exposition Co.,&#8221; the object of which is the encourage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the education, the advancement in the arts, sciences and general husbandry of the Afro-Americans residing in the United States, and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the same being of national importance, looking toward the elevation and improvement of said race, now, therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the House of Representatives of the State of Texas, the Senate concurring, That the said Afro-American Fair and Inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />State Exposition is worthy of the aid and support of the citizens of the State of Texas and of the United States, and that the same should be encouraged to that extent as will guarantee the permanent and success<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful operation of the same. That the same being in its character of great national importance should be aided by national legislation and appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation to such a degree as will assure its success and permanency.</p>
<p>Be it further resolved, That while the organic law of our State for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bids appropriations to individuals or corporations for the purposes for which the Afro-American Fair and Inter-State Exposition is organized, yet we recognize its great usefulness, and commend to the people of the State and nation this worthy undertaking.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 26, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. No. 17.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Authorizing and empowering &#8220;The Daughters of the Republic of Texas&#8221; to place a Statue of one of the Fathers of Texas in the Hall of Statuary in the national Capitol at Washington, District of Columbia.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, two spaces in the Hall of Statuary in the national capitol at Washington have been allotted to each State in the Union by act of Congress, for the purpose of doing honor to the illustrious dead of each State; and</p>
<p>Whereas, both of the spaces so allotted to the State of Texas are yet unoccupied; and</p>
<p>Whereas, there is an organization within the State of Texas known as &#8220;The Daughters of the Republic of Texas,&#8221; a corporation composed of the female descendants of the first settlers in Texas, the founders and builders of the great State we have the honor to represent; and</p>
<p>Whereas, &#8220;The Daughters of the Republic of Texas&#8221; are desirous of placing within one of the allotted spaces, at their own cost and expense, a statue in memory and in honor of one of the Fathers of Texas:</p>
<p>Section 1. Therefore be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That &#8220;The Daughters of the Republic of Texas,&#8221; acting by and through its duly elected officers, be, and it is hereby authorized to erect and place within one of the allotted spaces assigned to the State of Texas in the Hall of Statuary, in the national capitol at Washington, a statue<pb n="1318" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="264" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>representing, and in memory of one of the Fathers of Texas; said statue, before being placed in said Hall of Statuary, to be approved by a State commission consisting of the Governor, the Comptroller, and the At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney General of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Legislature of the State of Texas hereby tenders its thanks to Mrs. Anson Jones, Mrs. Andrew Briscoe, Mrs. Rebecca Gil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leland Fisher, Mrs. Belle Sherman Kendall, Mrs. Minnie Phelps Yasmar, Mrs. Mary Fenn McKeever, Miss Bettie Ballinger, Miss Belle Fenn, Mrs. Adele Briscoe Looscan, Miss Hallie Bryan, Mrs. Cornelia Stone, Mrs. Emily Perry Moore, Mrs. Marie Bennett Urwitz, Mrs. Elizabeth Lock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hart Landers, Mrs. John Adriance, Mrs. Tennie Hensley Hamilton, Miss Adina de Zavalla, Mrs. Maggie Tod Milby, Mrs. Lucy Sherman Craig, and Mrs. Rosine Ryan, for the generous and patriotic purpose expressed in their desire to keep alive the names and deeds of men who honored Texas.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 3, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. No. 17. A.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Requesting the Governor of Texas to return to the Senate, House Joint Resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion No. 7, entitled &#8220;A Joint Resolution ratifying and confirming the action of the attorneys representing the State of Texas in compromising its claims to its University lands in McLennan County, Texas,&#8221; in order that the same may be presented to the President of the Senate for his signature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, at a previous day of the present session of the Legislature, House Joint Resolution Ho. 7, being entitled &#8220;A Joint Resolution rati<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fying and confirming the action of the attorneys representing the State of Texas is compromising its claim to its University lands in McLennan County, Texas,&#8221; was introduced and passed both the House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives and the Senate, and has received the signature of the Speaker of the House of Representatives and has been presented to the Governor for his signature, and whereas, by mistake the said resolution was not presented to the President of the Senate for his signature and was not signed by him as required by the Constitution of Texas:</p>
<p>Therefore, be it resolved by the Senate, the House of Representatives concurring, That the Governor of Texas be, and he is hereby requested to return to the Senate the said resolution in order that it may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented to and receive the signature of the President of the Senate.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 3, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1319" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="265" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. R. No. 19.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Requesting the Governor to return House Bills, No. 381, and No. 443, for signa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture of the Speaker to one, and of the Chief Clerk to the other.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, in signing of enrolled House Bills, No. 381, and No. 443, the name of the Speaker was accidentally omitted from one and the name of the Chief Clerk from the other, which omissions were not discovered until after said bills had been delivered to the Governor:</p>
<p>Therefore, be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, That the Governor be and [is] hereby respectively [respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully] requested to return said bills to the House that the omitted signa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures may be placed thereon as the law requires.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 3, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. J. R. No. 7] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Ratifying and confirming the action of the attorneys representing the State of Texas in compromising its claim to its University lands in McLennan County, Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the 16th Legislature of the State of Texas, at its regular session in 1879, passed a joint resolution authorizing and directing the Attorney General to institute and prosecute such legal proceedings as might be necessary to establish the title of the State to its University lands in McLennan and Hill counties, and to remove all clouds upon said title; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The Seventeenth Legislature, at its regular session in 1881, passed an act to provide for the protection of the State to the University lands in McLennan and Hill counties, and authorized the Governor and Attorney General to employ competent counsel to defend the title of the State to said lands; and</p>
<p>Whereas, In pursuance of said resolution and act, the Governor and Attorney General employed counsel who instituted suit in the Nine<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Judicial District Court of McLennan County, Texas, to recover of Jennie Lewis and a number of others, defendants therein named, fourteen thousand acres of land lying in McLennan County, Texas; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The State&#8217;s said attorneys compromised said suit with said defendants, whereby the State reclaimed 6533 acres of the said lands for its entire interest in the same, entered by decree of the court in said cause, and the said defendants were given 7022 acres by the terms of the same decree; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The Appellate Courts of our State have held that the State&#8217;s said attorneys exceeded their authority in making said compromise, and that the same did not affect the title of the State to its said lands; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the said compromise made by the said attorneys for the State in said cause, be, and the same is hereby in all things ratified and confirmed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the litigation now being instituted and threatened to be<pb n="1320" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="266" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>instituted by parties claiming an interest in said lands, causing the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple on said lands unnecessary costs and useless expense, creates a public necessity requiring the constitutional rule for bills to be read on three several days to be suspended, and said rule is hereby suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the House by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 88, nays 1; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 23, nays none.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, on Friday, the twenty-sixth day of March, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212; J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. No. 20.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to deep water, good harbors, and an open sea, etc.</salute>
</opener>
<p>The fact that deep water, good harbors, and an open sea, now exists at several places on the coast of Texas, and the great difference in distance as compared from our seacoast to that from the far off Atlantic coast to the States mentioned in the said concurrent resolution of the Kansas legislature, making it a forced and unnatural proceeding to carry the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mense surplus of agricultural, mineral and manufactured products fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen hundred miles further to find ships&#8217; bottoms, that they may be transmitted to the other countries of the world, thus denying an outlet to large quantities of such products, the cost of transporting being more than their market value; therefore, be it</p>
<p>Resolved, first, by the Senate of the State of Texas, the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives concurring therein: That we heartily endorse the resolutions of the Kansas legislature in so far as they may lead to the conference mentioned of delegates from the several States, and we would recommend that an invitation be extended to other States west of the Mississippi river to participate in the conference by sending representatives thereto.</p>
<p>Resolved, second: That his excellency, Gov. Culberson, when he is in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed of the appointment of delegates from the other States and Terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tories mentioned to such a conference, to appoint an equal number of our citizens to meet such delegates, who are hereby empowered to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent such a report to the next legislature as may enable that body to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />telligently deal with the subject of a low rate of freights from all the territory of this vast western region to our seaboard.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 15, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1321" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="267" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. J. R. No. 8.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend Section 3 (three), of Article XI (11), of the Constitution of the State of Texas, so as to authorize certain counties to give aid in the construction of railways.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Section 3, of Article XI, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be amended so that the same shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 3. No county, city or other municipal corporation shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after become a subscriber to the capital of any corporation or associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, or make any appropriation or donation to the same, or in any wise loan its credit, except as hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>It shall be lawful for any county in this State lying south of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Jeff Davis, Reeves, Ward, Ector, Midland, Glasscock, Sterling, Coke and Runnels, and south and west of the Colorado river; also, all those counties west of Hardeman, Knox and Haskell, and north of Fish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, Scurry, Borden, Dawson and Gaines; also, the counties of Matagorda and Brazoria, to give aid, by and through its commissioners&#8217; court, by the issue of bonds of such county, or other evidences of indebtedness, in the construction of a standard guage railway or railways into, through or across any such county, when, by a vote of the majority of the quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied voters of any such county, voting at an election held for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose, such aid authorized.</p>
<p>Provided, however, that no such aid as is hereinbefore authorized and provided for shall ever be given or paid to any railroad company, or in aid of any such railway construction, except in proportion to and for such railway or part thereof as shall have been completely constructed and equipped within any such county. And special authority and power is hereby given the commissioners&#8217; court of any county within the ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritory herein prescribed, wherein such aid may be authorized, to levy and collect an annual tax, in addition to any other tax authorized by this Constitution, upon all property in such county subject to taxation, to pay interest on and to create a sinking fund to meet said bonds or other indebtedness created for such purpose; provided, that the aggregate of such tax, in any county, shall never in any one year exceed two per centum upon the assessed valuation of the property in such county.</p>
<p>Full power is hereby given to said commissioners&#8217; court of any such county, and it is hereby made its duty, at once, upon the petition thereto of not less than one hundred (100) qualified voters of any such county to at any time order and in all things provide for and regulate such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and the holding, returns, and determination of the same, and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the form of the ballot to be used.</p>
<p>All bonds or other evidences of indebtedness, issued by any such county under the provisions of this section, shall, before being delivered, negotiated or floated, be approved by the Attorney General of this State, and thereupon the Comptroller of this State shall register the same and endorse the fact of such registry upon said bonds or evidences of indebt<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edness.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Governor is hereby directed to issue the necessary procla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation for submitting this amendment to the qualified voters of Texas on the first Tuesday in August, 1897; at which election all voters favor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1322" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="268" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>ing the amendment shall have written or printed on their tickets, &#8220;For the Amendment to Section 3, of Article XI, of the Constitution of Texas, authorizing all counties in this State lying south of the counties of Jeff Davis, Reeves, Ward, Ector, Midland, Glasscock, Sterling, Coke and Runnels, and south and west of the Colorado river; also, all those counties west of Hardeman, Knox and Haskell, and north of Fisher, Scurry, Borden, Dawson and Gaines; also the counties of Matagorda and Brazoria, to give aid in the construction of railroads by the issuance of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness, when authorized thereto by a majority vote of any such county;&#8221; and those opposed to said amendment shall have written or printed on their tickets, &#8220;Against the Amendment to Section 3, of Article XI, of the Constitution of Texas, authorizing all counties in this State lying south of the counties of Jeff Davis, Reeves, Ward, Ector, Midland, Glasscock, Sterling, Coke and Runnels, and south and west of the Colorado river; also, all those counties west of Harde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, Knox and Haskell, and north of Fisher, Scurry, Borden, Dawson and Gaines; also, the counties of Matagorda and Brazoria, to give aid in the construction of railroads, by the issuance of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness, when authorized thereto by a majority vote of any such county.&#8221;</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the Senate by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 25, nays 2; and having passed the House with amende<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, and being referred to a free conference committee, the report of said committee was adopted by both houses, the vote in the Senate being yeas 22, nays none. The certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House does not give the vote on passage of this joint resolution, or on adoption or the free conference report.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution was presented to the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of Texas for his approval, on Tuesday, the sixth day of April, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. J. R. No. 20.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend Article XI, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, by adding thereto Section 11.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the laws of the State of Texas authorize the several counties in this State, through their commissioners&#8217; court, to issue bonds for the erection of court houses and jails, and the construction and purchase of bridges; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the statutes of the State of Texas authorize the board of education of said State to invest the permanent school fund thereof in bonds issued for the purposes aforesaid by the said counties; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the board of education of this State, in pursuance of said statutory authority, has purchased as an investment for the permanent school fund of the State of Texas, bonds approximating three million dollars; and</p>
<pb n="1323" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="269" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<p>Whereas, the Constitution of the State of Texas provides that no debt for any purpose shall ever be incurred in any manner for any city or county unless provision is made at the time of its creation for the levy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and collecting of a sufficient tax to pay the interest thereon, and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide at least two per cent. as a sinking fund; and</p>
<p>Whereas, it is believed that some of the bonds so purchased by the State board of education as an investment for the permanent school fund were not issued in conformity with that provision of the Constitution, and it is doubtful whether proper provision was made at the time of the attempted creation of said debt, evidenced by said bonds, for the levy of a tax to secure the payment of interest and the creation of a sinking fund, and that some of said bonds may therefore be held invalid by the courts;</p>
<p>Therefore, Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article XI, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be amended by adding thereto the following, which shall be denominated &#8220;Section 11.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 11. That all bonds heretofore issued by the several counties of Texas for the purpose of the erection of court houses and jails, and for the purchase or construction of bridges, and that have been pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased by the proper authorities of the State of Texas as an investment for the permanent school fund of said State, and that at the time of the creation of said debt, evidenced by said bonds, the provision for the levy of a tax for the payment of the interest and the creation of a sinking fund was not made, shall not be for that reason held to be invalid; but said bonds are hereby validated, and are hereby made valid debts against the several counties by which they were issued.</p>
<p>Be it further resolved: That this amendment shall be submitted to a vote of the qualified electors of the State of Texas on the first Tuesday in August, 1897, at which election all voters favoring said proposed amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall write or have printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;For the amendment of Article XI, of the Constitution, validating bonds held by the State as an investment for the permanent school fund;&#8221; and all voters opposing said amendment shall write or have printed on their bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lots the words, &#8220;Against the amendment to Article XI, of the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, validating bonds held by the State as an investment for the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manent school fund.&#8221;</p>
<p>And that the governor of the State is hereby directed to issue the necessary proclamation for said election, and have same published as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by the Constitution and existing laws of the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 22, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the House by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 93, nays 2; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 21, nays none.]</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1324" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="270" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. No. 22.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting to the 8th Texas Cavalry Association, known as Terry&#8217;s Texas Rangers, the right to place in the Capitol grounds a monument to their heroic dead. Relating to Lease of Temporary Capitol.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate, the House of Representatives concur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ring: That the 8th Texas Cavalry Association, known during the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate War as Terry&#8217;s Texas Rangers, be, and they are hereby granted permission to erect, at the expense of said association, a monument in commemoration of their dead comrades, on the Capitol Grounds in the City of Austin, and that the Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds be authorized to select a site for said monument.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing concurrent resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, on Friday, the sixteenth day of April, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the House in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. R. No. 13.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to Lease of Temporary Capitol.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the lease on the Temporary Capitol owned by the State will expire on July 1st, 1897; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, that the Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds is hereby authorized and empowered to lease the same for a period not to exceed five years, together with any other lot, parts of lots or lands belonging to the State situated in the City of Austin.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 30, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect 90 days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. C. R. NO. 16.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to destruction of property at Brenham, Texas, in the year 1866, by United States Soldiers garrisoning the town.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, at Brenham, in Washington County, in this State, on the seventh day of September, 1866, more than a year after the war between the States had ended, soldiers of the United States, garrisoning the town, led by the commander of the post, burned and destroyed a block of houses embracing the largest and most valuable buildings and business estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishments in the town, together with the contents of the buildings&#8212;an act of spoliation for which the United States would have demanded prompt and ample indemnity if it had been committed upon citizens of the United States in any foreign country by the soldiers of that country,<pb n="1325" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="271" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>and for which the United States Government would have made prompt and ample indemnity to the persons injured, if it had been committed in this country by our soldiers, upon citizens of any foreign government; and</p>
<p>Whereas, immediately after the act was committed, while the facts could be readily and fully ascertained, the Legislature of this State, then in session, caused an investigation to be made by a committee of the two houses, which committee reported to the Legislature the persons in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jured, and value of property destroyed to be:</p>
<p>Francis D. Allen.......................................... $5,000 00</p>
<p>Allen &#38; Newman......................................... 3,500 00</p>
<p>C. R. Breedlove, Agt. for V. Little........................ 1,500 00</p>
<p>MeGary &#38; Roff (D. L. McGary and N. B. Roff)............ 5,000 00</p>
<p>Sam Levinson.............................................. 27,800 00</p>
<p>D. L. MeGary................................................. 500 00</p>
<p>J. B. Campbell............................................... 700 00</p>
<p>Compton Bros.............................................. 25,000 00</p>
<p>Norris &#38; McNeese...................................... 35,000 00</p>
<p>Pressler &#38; Roff........................................ 2,500 00</p>
<p>C. &#38; J. Stephenson..................................... 1,000 00</p>
<p>H. C. Surglmor............................................... 600 00</p>
<p>Wilkins &#38; Stephenson.................................. 15,141 00</p>
<p>John B. Wilkins............................................ 9,000 00</p>
<p>Wyatt &#38; McCrocklin..................................... 1,500 00</p>
<p>Therefore, by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Texas, be it resolved, That the Texas Senators and Representatives in Congress be and are hereby requested to use their best endeavors to se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure from the United States Government, by act of Congress, indemnity and payment to the citizens of Brenham, or their legal representatives, for the property destroyed.</p>
<p>Resolved, that the Secretary of State is hereby instructed to forward to each Texas Senator and Representative in Congress a certified copy of this resolution.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing concurrent resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, on Friday, the sixteenth day of April, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
<p>Takes effect 90 days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1326" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="272" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. J. R. No. 19.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Permitting the Hon. T. H. Conner, Judge of the 42nd Judicial District of Texas, to leave the limits of the State for a period of sixty days, on account of impor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tant business.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That whereas, the Hon. T. H. Connor, judge of the 42nd judicial district of Texas, has important business outside of the State of Texas demand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing his personal attention; therefore,</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said T. H. Connor, judge as aforesaid, be and is hereby permitted to go beyond the limits of the State of Texas for a period of sixty days from and after the passage of this joint resolution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The nature of the business of the said judge being of a press<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and urgent character, and the crowded condition of the calendar of both the Senate and the House, and the early adjournment of the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, create an emergency, and an imperative public necessity exists requiring that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this resolution take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 12, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the Senate by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 28, nays none; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. R. No. 30.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting Hon. J. M. Hall, Judge of the 18th Judicial District, sixty days leave of absence from the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Hon. J. M. Hall, District Judge of the 18th Judicial District, is at this time in very had health, and desires to leave the State on or about the first day of June, 1897, for the purpose of regaining his health;</p>
<p>Therefore, be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring,, that said Hon. J. M. Hall, District Judge of the 18th Judicial District, be and is hereby allowed to leave the State for a period of sixty days, from the first day of June, 1897, until the first day of August, 1897.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 19, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1327" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="273" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. J. R. No. 16.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting leave of absence from the State to Judge Eugene Archer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Judge Eugene Archer, judge of the 38th judicial district of Texas, be and is hereby granted leave of absence from the State for a period of sixty days, at any time between the 25th day of April and the 1st day of December, 1897, on account of serious illness.</p>
<p>Resolved, further, that the fact Judge Eugene Archer is in ill health and badly needs a change of climate, and the fact that the health of one of the State&#8217;s district judges is imperiled, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule that bills be read on three several days be suspended, and that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 21, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the Senate by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 21, nays none; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. J. R. No. 20.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting leave of absence for sixty days from the State of Texas, to Hon. W. M. Allison, Judge of the Thirty-Third District of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Hon. W. M. Allison, Judge of the Thirty-third Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict of Texas, on account of ill health, desires a leave of absence for sixty days from the State of Texas; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That said W. M. Allison be and he is hereby granted a leave of absence from the State of Texas for the period of sixty days.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session, and the crowded condition of the calendar, create an emergency, and an imperative public necessity exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills and resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions to be read on three several days be and the same is hereby sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and that this resolution be in effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 22, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the Senate by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 23, nays none; and passed the House, vote not given.]</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1328" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="274" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. C. R. No. 34.] CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Authorizing and directing the State Printing Board to contract for a reprint of such appellate court reports as are now out of print, and also such as may hereafter become out of print, or nearly so; and providing certain conditions and limitations in relation to such contract, and the manner of letting the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, many of the volumes of the Supreme Court reports of the State of Texas are now out of print, and the State&#8217;s supply therefor has been exhausted; and</p>
<p>Whereas, many other volumes of said reports are now nearly ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hausted, and doubtless will be entirely so at no very distant time; and</p>
<p>Whereas, other volumes of which a sufficient supply is now on hand are likely to become insufficient to supply the demand therefor; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the State owns and has on hand the stereotyped plates for many of said volumes; and will have others; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the State Printing Board is without authority to contract for a reprint of said reports; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ring, that the State Printing Board be and the same is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized, empowered and directed to make such contract or contracts as may be necessary to secure a reprint of such of said reports as are now ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hausted, or nearly so, and such as may hereafter become exhausted, or nearly so; provided, that the reprinting of said reports shall be done without cost to the State; and provided, further, that such contract or contracts shall stipulate that the State and the publisher or publishers of said reports shall sell the same at the same price, such price not to exceed the sum of two dollars ($2.00) per volume, and such volume to be printed and bound in style equally as good as the current numbers of said reports; and provided, further, that this resolution shall also apply to the Courts of Civil Appeals reports and the Court of Criminal Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals reports, should said Board find a reprint thereof advisable and necessary; and provided, further, that such contract shall be let to the best bidder after such publication for bids therefor as the said Board may think proper, and shall require that said reports be printed within this State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 22, 1897</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">S. J. R. No. 13.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend Section 24, of Article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Section 24, of Article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 24. The members of the Legislature shall receive from the public treasury such compensation for their services as may from time to time be provided by law, not exceeding five dollars per day for the first one hundred days of each session, and after that, not exceeding three dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per day for the remainder of the session. In addition to the per<pb n="1329" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="275" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>diem, the members of each house shall be entitled to mileage in going to and returning from the seat of government, which mileage shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed five dollars for every twenty-five miles, the distance to be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />puted by the nearest and most direct route of travel by land, regardless of railways or other routes; and the Comptroller of the State shall pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pare and preserve a table of distances to each county seat now or hereaf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter to be established, and by such table the mileage of each member shall be paid; but no member shall be entitled to mileage for any extra session they may be called within one day after the adjournment of a regular or called session.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The governor is hereby directed to issue the necessary procla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation for submitting this amendment to the qualified voters of Texas, at the next general election, at which election all voters favoring the amendment shall have written or printed on their tickets, &#8220;For amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to Section 24, of Article 3, of the Constitution of Texas, relating to compensation of members of the legislature,&#8221; and those opposed to said amendment shall have written or printed on their tickets, &#8220;Against amendment to Section 24, of Article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, relating to the compensation of members of the legislature.&#8221;</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the Senate by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 21, nays 1; and passed the House with amendments by a two-thirds vote, yeas 89, nays 7; and being referred to a free confer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence committee, the report of said committee was adopted by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote in both houses, the vote being, in the Senate, yeas 24, nays 4, in the House, yeas 90, nays 16.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution was presented to the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of Texas for his approval, on Thursday, the twentieth day of May, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212; J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">H. J. R. No. 34.] JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend Section 51, of Article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, so as to authorize the grant of aid to disabled and dependent Confederate sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers and sailors, and their widows, and to grant aid to the establishment and maintenance of a home for said soldiers and sailors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Section 51, of Article 3, of the Constitution of the Stare of Texas, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">ARTICLE 3.</head>
<p>Section 51. The legislature shall have no power to make any grant or authorize the making of any grant of public money to any individual, as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sociations or individuals, municipal or other corporations whatsoever; provided, however, the legislature may grant aid to indigent and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1330" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="276" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>abled Confederate soldiers and sailors who came to Texas prior to Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 1st, 1880, and who are either over sixty years of age, or whose dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ability is the proximate result of actual service in the Confederate army for a period of at least three months, their widows in indigent circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stances who have never re-married, and who have been bona fide resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dents of the State of Texas since March 1, 1880, and who were married to such soldiers or sailors anterior to March 1, 1866; provided, said aid shall not exceed eight dollars per month; and provided, further, that no appropriation shall ever be made for the purpose hereinbefore specified in excess of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars for any one year. And also grant aid to the establishment and maintenance of a home for said soldiers and sailors, under such regulations and limitations as may be provided by law; provided, the grant to aid said home shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed one hundred thousand dollars for any one year; and no inmate of said home shall be entitled to any other aid from the State; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, further, that the provisions of this section shall not be construed to prevent the grant of aid in case of public calamity.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This amendment shall be submitted to the qualified electors of the State on the first Tuesday in November, 1898; when those favor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the amendment shall have written or printed on their ballots, &#8220;For the amendment to Section 51, of Article 3, of the State Constitution.&#8221; Those opposing the amendment shall have written or printed upon their ballots, &#8220;Against the amendment to Section 51, of Article 3, of the State Constitution.&#8221;</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution passed the House by a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds vote, yeas 96, nays 9; and passed the Senate by a two-thirds vote, yeas 22, nays 6.]</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing joint resolution was presented to the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of Texas for his approval, on Friday, the twenty-first day of May, A. D. 1897, but was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his sig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nature.&#8212;J. W. Madden, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
